<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Hymenoptera on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/hymenoptera/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis chilensis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chilensis</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chilensis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; Howard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cosmopolitan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: An important parasitoid of the oleander scale, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aspidiotus_Nerii&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aspidiotus nerii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bouche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is yellow, its size being from 0.5 to 1.1 mm; smaller specimens are paler, bear less setae and were even described as a separate species (&lt;em&gt;Aphytis riadi&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale prepupae are attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; onto the host&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;figures/AphytisAspidiotus-Fig1.html&amp;quot;, 500, 300,&#34;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that at molting the shields of these insects adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;). The pupa is free, and its eyes change from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath. Although reared (in the field and in the laboratory) from several hosts, it seems to prefer the oleander scale. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; (but males have been described), requiring ca 18 days to complete a generation at 28°C and each female produces about 25 offspring. In the field the parasitoid has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn. It attacks mainly young host females and is a voracious &lt;a href=&#34;entry/HostFeeding&#34;&gt;host feeder&lt;/a&gt;, killing more scales by this practice than by parasitization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water extract of the shield of the oleander scale elicited a positive response
from &lt;em&gt;A. chilensis&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting that its host-searching is based on chemical
cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandrakis, V. and Neuenschwander, P. 1980. Le role d&amp;rsquo;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt;
(Hym.: Aphelinidae), parasite d&amp;rsquo;&lt;em&gt;Aspidiotus nerii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom.: Diaspididae) sur
olivier en Crete. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;:  61-71.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis riadi&lt;/em&gt; - a synonym of &lt;em&gt;A. chilensis&lt;/em&gt; (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Annals of the Entomological Society of America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;60:&lt;/strong&gt;
1116-1118.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lo Pinto, M., Lo Bue, P., Peri, E. Agrò, A., Liotta, G. and Colazza, S.
2002.  Responses of  2003.  &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; to the synthetic sex pheromone of
the oleander scale. &lt;em&gt;IOBC/WPRS Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;():&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck, R.F. and Uygun, N. 1986. Host recognition and selection by &lt;em&gt;Aphytis&lt;/em&gt;
species: response to California red, oleander and cactus scale cover extracts.
&lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt;: 129-136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae).&lt;/em&gt; Israel Universities Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis chrysomphali</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chrysomphali</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chrysomphali</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Mercet)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Probably a native of the Mediterranean basin; its distribution is now almost cosmopolitan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially California red scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aonidiella_Aurantii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Maskell).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A member of a guild of parasitoids that attack the California red scale. In Israel and Cyprus &lt;em&gt;A. chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; occurs only along the coastal plain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size is from 0.6 to 1.0 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;A. chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt;, young females and scale &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prepupa&#34;&gt;prepupae&lt;/a&gt; are attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the ectoparasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the host&amp;rsquo;s shield, or by crawling out from underneath. Although obtained from several armored scale hosts, it is best known as a parasitoid of the California red scale. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; species (with rare males) and a voracious &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Host_Feeding&#34;&gt;host feeder&lt;/a&gt;, killing more scales by this practice than by parasitization. It completes a cycle in a fortnight at 25°C, at which temperature each female produces about 25 offspring. It appears to be tolerant to low temperatures but susceptible to heat and aridity, attributes that could explain its prevalence along the coastal plain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanides, G.M. 1996. Establishment of &lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt; (Hym:
Encyrtidae) on &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom: Diaspididae) in Cyprus.
&lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;: 53-57.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of &lt;em&gt;Aphytis&lt;/em&gt; of the World
(Hymenoptera: Aphelinidae).&lt;/em&gt; Israel Universities Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis coheni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_coheni</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_coheni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt; DeBach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Probably a native of south-east Asia that had fortuitously arrived in Israel and Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;:  California red scale,  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aonidiella_Aurantii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Maskell), rarely other armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  An important natural enemy of the California red scale, especially in the inner, warmer and drier parts of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is yellow, about 0.8 to 1.1 mm in length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prepupa&#34;&gt;prepupae&lt;/a&gt; are attacked, but the young ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath. The California red scale is its major host, although the ectoparasitoid was also obtained from a few other armored scale hosts. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;, requiring 3-4 weeks at 20°C to complete a generation, 12 days at 28°C. Each female, whether mated or not, produces about 25 offspring; the parasitoid may place an average of 5 eggs in such hosts. At 24°C males live about three weeks, females slightly longer. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt; is a voracious &lt;a href=&#34;entry/HostFeeding&#34;&gt;host feeder&lt;/a&gt; that kills twice as many scales by this practice than by parasitization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the field the populations of &lt;em&gt;A. coheni&lt;/em&gt; have a mild spring peak. Its
juveniles, which are protected during their development by the host&amp;rsquo;s shield,
seem to be tolerant to high temperatures, but the adults, and especially the
males, are very susceptible. The parasitoid&amp;rsquo;s presence in the inner, hotter
and drier regions of Israel is probably due to lack of competition there from
other parasitoids of the California red scale (which are more susceptible to
arid conditions), not due to any intrinsic superior biological attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water extracts of the shield of the California red scale elicited positive
responses from &lt;em&gt;A. coheni&lt;/em&gt;, indicating that its host searching is based on
chemical cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, Z., M. Balshin and U. Gerson. 1970. Studies on &lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt;, a
parasite of the California red scale, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;, in Israel.
&lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;:  191-207.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck, R.F. and Uygun, N. 1986. Host recognition and selection by &lt;em&gt;Aphytis&lt;/em&gt;
species: response to California red, oleander and cactus scale cover extracts.
&lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; : 129-136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis hispanicus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt; Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mediterranean Basin, Central America, Texas, California, Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;:  Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_pergandii&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Comstock&lt;/code&gt; and tropical grey chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_cinerea&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria cinerea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hadden&lt;/code&gt;. In the laboratory the parasitoid can be reared on the latania scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Hemiberlesia_lataniae&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hemiberlesia lataniae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Signoret)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A parasitoid of chaff scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size being from 0.6 to 1.0 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale prepupae are sometimes attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath.  &lt;em&gt;A. hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; species, requiring about a fortnight to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 24 offspring. In the field this solitary parasitoid has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn, being rare during summer and winter. It attacks its chaff scale hosts mostly on the leaves, less on the fruit and very seldom on the wooden parts of the trees, and does not feed on its hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. The natural enemies of the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria
pergandii&lt;/em&gt; Comstock, in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 12: 97-109.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1968. The comparative biologies of two hymenopterous parasites of
the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 13: 163-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Israel Universities Press&lt;/em&gt;, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  
**Websites**: 

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

--&gt;

&lt;!--


**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis holoxanthus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_holoxanthus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_holoxanthus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; DeBach&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: , &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Of South-Eastern Asia origin, this species was successfully introduced into Israel in 1956/57 and later into Australia, Florida, South Africa and South America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;:  The Florida red scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Chrysomphalus_Aonidum&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrysomphalus aonidum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt; (L.) (&lt;a href=&#34;Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  An efficient natural enemy of the Florida red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size being from 0.7 to 0.9 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The eggs are deposited through the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the host and kill it; prior to pupation the larvae excrete their &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;. The pupa is free, and its eyes change from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of age. The adult emerges through an exit hole in the shield or by crawling out from underneath. It attacks 2nd-stage female scales, male pupae but mostly adult females, on which two or three juveniles may develop. It is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt; species, requiring a fortnight to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 35 offspring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; has not become established in the inner, arid valleys of
Israel. When co-occurring with another natural enemy of the Florida red scale,
the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Pteroptrix_Smithi&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pteroptrix smithi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; (Compere), the latter appears to be dominant. This
may reflect the latter&amp;rsquo;s ability to parasitize all scale stages (whereas &lt;em&gt;A.
holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; can attack the host only between its molts), to the reduced
activity of &lt;em&gt;A. holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; fruit, and to its
greater susceptibility to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt;
pesticides. On the other hand, the parasite has not been affected by the
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricide&lt;/a&gt; dicofol or by juvenile hormone analoge
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Insect_Growth_Regulator&#34;&gt;IGR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peleg, B.A. 1988. Effect of a new phenoxy juvenile hormone analog on
California red scale (Homoptera, Diaspididae), Florida wax scale (Homoptera,
Coccidae) and the ectoparasitic &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; DeBach (Hymenoptera,
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;81&lt;/strong&gt;: 88-92.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rehman, S.U., Browning, H.W., Nigg, H.N. and Harrison, J.M. 1999. Residual
effects of carbaryl and dicofol on &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; Debach (Hymenoptera :
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Biological Control&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt;: 252-257.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae)&lt;/em&gt;. Israel Universities Press , Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg, S., Podoler, H. and Rosen, D. 1986. Biological control of the
Florida red scale, &lt;em&gt;Chrysomphalus aonidum&lt;/em&gt;, in Israel by two parasite species:
current status in the coastal plain. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;:  199-204.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg, S., Podoler, H. and Rosen, D. 1987. Competition between two
parasites of the Florida red scale in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Ecological Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:
299-310.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encarsia inquirenda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/encarsia_inquirenda</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/encarsia_inquirenda</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Encarsia inquirenda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Silvestri)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mediterranean Basin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts:&lt;/strong&gt; Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_pergandii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Comstock&lt;/code&gt; and tropical grey chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_cinerea&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parlatoria cinerea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hadden&lt;/code&gt;. It also attacks the olive scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_oleae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parlatoria oleae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Colvee)&lt;/code&gt;. In the laboratory the parasitoid can be reared on the latania scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Hemiberlesia_lataniae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hemiberlesia lataniae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Signoret)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A parasitoid of chaff scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is dark yellow, its size being from 0.6 to 0.9 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;em&gt;Encarsia inquirenda&lt;/em&gt; is a solitary &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of chaff scales, attacking all stages, including the male prepupae and the females. The egg is inserted through the shield into the host&amp;rsquo;s body whereon the emerging &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larva&lt;/a&gt; feeds. Parasitized 2nd-stage male nymphs, whose bodies become bloated due the larva&amp;rsquo;s presence, continue to build their shields, which thus become rounded instead of elongated. Parasitized chaff scales gradually turn white, losing their purplish color, and then become mummified. Prior to pupation the larva excretes its fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The development of the parasitoid is undisturbed by the host&amp;rsquo;s molts. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath. &lt;em&gt;Encarsia inquirenda&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt;) species, requiring about four weeks to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 20 offspring. In the field the parasitoid, which is relatively tolerant to low humidities, has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn, being rare during summer and winter. It attacks its chaff scale hosts mostly on the fruit and leaves, rarely on the wooden parts of the trees, and does not feed on its hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. The natural enemies of the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria
pergandii&lt;/em&gt; Comstock, in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 12 97-109.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1968. The comparative biologies of two hymenopterous parasites of
the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 13 163-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://chalcidoids.tamu.edu/ENCARSIA/encarsia.htm&#34;&gt;http://chalcidoids.tamu.edu/ENCARSIA/encarsia.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encarsia lahorensis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/encarsia_lahorensis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/encarsia_lahorensis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Howard)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt;, of south Asian provenance, was initially introduced into California and has accompanied its host, the citrus whitefly, wherever it became established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus whitefly, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Dialeurodes_citri&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dialeurodes citri&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ashmead)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aleyrodidae&#34;&gt;Aleyrodidae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt; is the most important and most commonly employed natural enemy of the citrus whitefly, killing the pest by parasitization as well as by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Host_feeding&#34;&gt;host feeding&lt;/a&gt;. In Israel the pest was completely controlled by this natural enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the female is 0.55-0.85 mm long, and lemon-yellow in color; the smaller male (0.60 mm long) has a brown abdomen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt; is a solitary, primary &lt;a href=&#34;entry/endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt;; its fertilized (diploid) eggs are deposited in the fourth instar larvae of the host. Unfertilized (haploid) eggs are inserted into the body of the whitefly host and placed on the body of its own female larva, the males thus being &lt;a href=&#34;entry/hyperparasite&#34;&gt;hyperparasites&lt;/a&gt; on their own (or sometimes of other endoparasitoid) females. Eggs are deposited within the first 7-10 days of the adult life (20 to 50 eggs per female), and a generation is raised in 17 to 25 days. Under laboratory condition (26°C, 70% RH) females live about 9 days and the males 11 days. &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt; overwinters as both larvae and pupae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argov, Y., Rossler, Y., Voet, H. and Rosen, D. 2000. Introducing &lt;em&gt;Encarsia
lahorensis&lt;/em&gt; against &lt;em&gt;Dialeurodes citri&lt;/em&gt; in Israel: a case of successful
biological control. &lt;em&gt;BioControl&lt;/em&gt; 45: 1-10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argov, Y. and Rossler, Y. 1986. The introduction of &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Howard)&lt;/code&gt; (Hymenoptera: Aphelinidae) into Israel for the control of the citrus
whitefly, &lt;em&gt;Dialeurodes citri&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Ashmead)&lt;/code&gt; (Homoptera: Aleyrodidae). &lt;em&gt;Israel
Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 20: 1-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nguyen, R. 1986. &lt;em&gt;Encarsia lahorensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Howard)&lt;/code&gt; a parasite of &lt;em&gt;Dialeurodes
citri&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Ashmead)&lt;/code&gt; (Hymenoptera: Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Florida Department Agriculture
Consumer services, Entomology Circular&lt;/em&gt; 290, 2 pp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose, M. and DeBach P. 1981. Citrus whitefly parasites established in
California. &lt;em&gt;California Agriculture&lt;/em&gt; 35: 21-23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viggiani, G. and Mazzone, P. 1978. Morfologia, biologia e utilizzazione di
&lt;em&gt;Prospaltella lahorensis&lt;/em&gt; How. (Hym. Aphelinidae), parassita esotico
introdotto in Italia per la lotta biologica al &lt;em&gt;Dialeurodes citri&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ashm.)&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Bolletino di Laboratorio Entomologia Agraria &amp;ldquo;Filippo Silvestri&amp;rdquo; Portici&lt;/em&gt; 35: 99-161.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;:
Yael Argov
The Israel Cohen Institute for Biological Control, Citrus Marketing Board of
Israel, P.O. Box 80, 50250 Bet Dagan, Israel.
E-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:yael@jaffa.co.il&#34;&gt;yael@jaffa.co.il&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chalcidoids.tamu.edu/ENCARSIA/encarsia.htm&#34;&gt;http://chalcidoids.tamu.edu/ENCARSIA/encarsia.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)
 --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oncastichus goughi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/oncastichus_goughi</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/oncastichus_goughi</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oncastichus goughi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Headrick and Lasalle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, Apocryta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Geraldton wax wasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Australia, California and in Israel since the 1990’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: The cut-flower crop &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult wasps are black, about 1-2 mm in length&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A major pest of Geraldton wax, &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae) (wax flower). It induces &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Gall&#34;&gt;galls&lt;/a&gt; and plant deformations, rendering the cut-flower crop as well as the foliage unmarketable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The eggs are placed within the host plant and the larvae develop in young leaves and stems, inducing the formation of galls and other deformations. Pupation takes place within the gall, the adult bores a round hole through which it emerges. Catches in traps suggest that the pest raises two annual, overlapping generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Green and yellow sticky traps can be used to monitor the occurrence of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: The early cultivars of &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; that bear smaller leaves are less susceptible to the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectin&#34;&gt;Avermectins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Imidacloprid&#34;&gt;imidacloprids&lt;/a&gt;, applied as &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;systemics&lt;/a&gt; greatly reduce the pest’s damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben-David, Z., Ofer, Y., Kedar, J., Schachner, T and Zaidan, M. 1997. Control
of the gall wasp &lt;em&gt;Oncastichus goughi&lt;/em&gt;, a new pest of wax flowers. &lt;em&gt;Avivon&lt;/em&gt; 32: 14-16 (in Hebrew).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben-Yakir, D., Gokkes, M., Eitan, S., Klein, Z., Kuzlitzki, W., Ben-David, Z.,
Lavi, A. and Chen, M. 1997. Biology and control of a gall-forming wasp, a new
pest of Geraldton wax plant in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 25: 145-146.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headrick, D.H., LaSalle, J. and Redak, R.A. 1995. A new genus of Australian
Tetrastichinae (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) an introduced pest of &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium
uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae) in California. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Natural History&lt;/em&gt; 29:
1029-1036.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redak R.A. and Bethke, J.A. 1995. Detection and seasonal occurrence of gall-
forming wasps (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) on Geraldton wax plant. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 88: 387-392.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeuzera pyrina</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cossidae&#34;&gt;Cossidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Leopard moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Europe, North and South Africa, Japan, North America, Mediterranean region. Distribution Maps of Plant Pests, No. 314, Commonwealth Institute of Entomology. 1973.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Polyphagous, preferring soft-wood trees, in the Middle East occurring mostly on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apple&#34;&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Olive&#34;&gt;olive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pear&#34;&gt;pear&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Plum&#34;&gt;plum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pomegranate&#34;&gt;pomegranate&lt;/a&gt; and about 150 other tree species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A single young &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larva&lt;/a&gt; may cause the death of thin branches, by withering or breaking. Although olives are less susceptible, the tendency of the moth to remain on the same hosts results in several pest generations developing there, causing considerable damage to the trees, which become weakened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult moth is whitish and covered by numerous dark-bluish spots when developing within apple trees, whereas those from olives have pinkish wings with greenish dotes. The body is darkish with white hairs. At rest the wings are folded along the body, which is 25-30 mm long. The males are smaller (20 mm long). The larva is dark-yellow with black dorsal tubercles, About 50-55 mm long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The moths occur in the orchards from May to November, dependent upon temperatures, host plant and plant protection practices. A female lives about one week, depositing 100-300 eggs on the bark, mostly on the tree from which it had emerged, or nearby. The emerging larvae bore into young twigs, often at the leaf bases, bringing about the withering on a leaf growing underneath. The larvae then move into elder, thicker branches wherein it continues to borrow into the wood, pushing out its brownish &lt;a href=&#34;glossary/Frass&#34;&gt;frass&lt;/a&gt; and completing its development there. The pattern of the excavated tunnels differs between trees. In hosts like deciduous fruit trees, the tunnels are straight, whereas in other trees, like olives, the tunnels may be circular or sinuous. Prior to pupation the mature larva bores an emergence hole near the original point of ingress, and seals it by a thin membrane. The young adults break through and emerge. The pest completes a single annual generation in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Light_trap&#34;&gt;Light traps&lt;/a&gt; have been used in the past, but were supplemented by male &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mating_disruption&#34;&gt;mating disruption&lt;/a&gt; traps, placed during   spring on the trees, to serve as an early warning system. Another method is to   observe the occurrence of “flag leaves”, the withering leaves at the bases of      thin branches infested by the young larvae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural contro&lt;/strong&gt;: In the past thin wires   were inserted through the frass into the burrows, or pesticides were thus   introduced. These are time consuming methods and probably suitable only in   instances of low infestations. More recently  by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; threads (650 per hectare) is being used, as it controls the pest on olives during most of the season,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; are used when necessary, but may only be applied against the exposed adults, and cannot be used during harvest. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/insect_growth_regulators&#34;&gt;IGRs&lt;/a&gt; have also been successfully applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The parasitic &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Elachertus nigritulus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Zetterstedt&lt;/code&gt;, (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae)&lt;/a&gt; has been mass reared from leopard moth larvae, but its effect on the pest’s damage is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abed El-Hadi, Birger, R., Hanoch, E., Vardi, Y., Sarid, D. and Zemer, B. 2005.
Control of &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; in olives by using pheromone male confusing. &lt;em&gt;Alon
Ha’notea&lt;/em&gt; 59: 383-385 (in Hebrew)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, Z. and Harpaz, I. 1969. &lt;em&gt;Plant Pests of Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Israel Universities
Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismail, I.I., Abouzeid, N.A. and Abdallah, F.F. 1992. Population dynamics of
the leopard moth, &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt;, and its control on olive trees in
Egypt. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Pflanzenkrankheiten und Pfanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; 99:
519-524.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: **

** [ Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>