<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Enemies on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis hispanicus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt; Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mediterranean Basin, Central America, Texas, California, Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;:  Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_pergandii&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Comstock&lt;/code&gt; and tropical grey chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_cinerea&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria cinerea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hadden&lt;/code&gt;. In the laboratory the parasitoid can be reared on the latania scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Hemiberlesia_lataniae&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hemiberlesia lataniae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Signoret)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A parasitoid of chaff scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size being from 0.6 to 1.0 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale prepupae are sometimes attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath.  &lt;em&gt;A. hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; species, requiring about a fortnight to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 24 offspring. In the field this solitary parasitoid has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn, being rare during summer and winter. It attacks its chaff scale hosts mostly on the leaves, less on the fruit and very seldom on the wooden parts of the trees, and does not feed on its hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. The natural enemies of the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria
pergandii&lt;/em&gt; Comstock, in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 12: 97-109.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1968. The comparative biologies of two hymenopterous parasites of
the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 13: 163-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Israel Universities Press&lt;/em&gt;, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  
**Websites**: 

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

--&gt;

&lt;!--


**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis holoxanthus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_holoxanthus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_holoxanthus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; DeBach&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: , &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Of South-Eastern Asia origin, this species was successfully introduced into Israel in 1956/57 and later into Australia, Florida, South Africa and South America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host&lt;/strong&gt;:  The Florida red scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Chrysomphalus_Aonidum&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrysomphalus aonidum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt; (L.) (&lt;a href=&#34;Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  An efficient natural enemy of the Florida red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size being from 0.7 to 0.9 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The eggs are deposited through the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the host and kill it; prior to pupation the larvae excrete their &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;. The pupa is free, and its eyes change from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of age. The adult emerges through an exit hole in the shield or by crawling out from underneath. It attacks 2nd-stage female scales, male pupae but mostly adult females, on which two or three juveniles may develop. It is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt; species, requiring a fortnight to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 35 offspring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; has not become established in the inner, arid valleys of
Israel. When co-occurring with another natural enemy of the Florida red scale,
the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Pteroptrix_Smithi&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pteroptrix smithi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; (Compere), the latter appears to be dominant. This
may reflect the latter&amp;rsquo;s ability to parasitize all scale stages (whereas &lt;em&gt;A.
holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; can attack the host only between its molts), to the reduced
activity of &lt;em&gt;A. holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; fruit, and to its
greater susceptibility to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt;
pesticides. On the other hand, the parasite has not been affected by the
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricide&lt;/a&gt; dicofol or by juvenile hormone analoge
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Insect_Growth_Regulator&#34;&gt;IGR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peleg, B.A. 1988. Effect of a new phenoxy juvenile hormone analog on
California red scale (Homoptera, Diaspididae), Florida wax scale (Homoptera,
Coccidae) and the ectoparasitic &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; DeBach (Hymenoptera,
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;81&lt;/strong&gt;: 88-92.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rehman, S.U., Browning, H.W., Nigg, H.N. and Harrison, J.M. 1999. Residual
effects of carbaryl and dicofol on &lt;em&gt;Aphytis holoxanthus&lt;/em&gt; Debach (Hymenoptera :
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Biological Control&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt;: 252-257.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae)&lt;/em&gt;. Israel Universities Press , Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg, S., Podoler, H. and Rosen, D. 1986. Biological control of the
Florida red scale, &lt;em&gt;Chrysomphalus aonidum&lt;/em&gt;, in Israel by two parasite species:
current status in the coastal plain. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;:  199-204.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg, S., Podoler, H. and Rosen, D. 1987. Competition between two
parasites of the Florida red scale in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Ecological Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:
299-310.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>