<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Terebrantia on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/terebrantia/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frankliniella occidentalis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/frankliniella_occidentalis</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/frankliniella_occidentalis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Pergande)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Terebrantia&#34;&gt;Terebrantia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thripidae&#34;&gt;Thripidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Western flower thrips (WFT)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographic distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Worldwide in temperate regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;Polyphagous&lt;/a&gt;, infesting over 500 different plant species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Terebrantia&#34;&gt;Terebrantia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thripidae&#34;&gt;Thripidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Western flower thrips (WFT)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographic distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Worldwide in temperate regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;Polyphagous&lt;/a&gt;, infesting over 500 different plant species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest feeds on and breeds in the leaves and flowers. It punctures them, sucking up the exuding sap. Foliage becomes silvery, followed by browning and wilting and withering of the leaf tips, curling and death. The undersides of leaves are spotted with small black specks, which are feces. Flowers become flecked, spotted, and deformed, and buds do not open. WFT infestations result in reductions of the aesthetic quality and marketability of ornamental plants. The pest transmits two &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tospovirus&#34;&gt;tospoviruses&lt;/a&gt;, the impatiens necrotic spot virus (INSV) and the tomato spotted wilt virus (TSWV), both causing serious plant diseases. WFT also feeds on spider mites (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;) and may sometimes be a useful biocontrol agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent molecular studies indicated that WFT consists of two species that cannot be distinguished morphologically, thus the damage described above may be attributed to either, or to both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is about 1 mm long, larger than the male, with pale &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Forewings&#34;&gt;forewings&lt;/a&gt;. The color of the female varies from yellow to dark brown, being darker at low temperatures, yellowish at higher temperatures. The male is always pale yellow and has a narrower &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Abdomen&#34;&gt;abdomen&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; are yellow, becoming paler towards molting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: A life cycle, from oviposition to adult emergence, may require two weeks in warm weather, to about six weeks in cool weather. The adults live for several weeks; the females which are &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokus&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;, deposit 50-100 eggs during their lives. They develop through two quiescent, non-feeding pupal stages in the soil, in plant litter or in protected areas on the host plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Two methods are used to monitor thrips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1. White, yellow or blue sticky traps will attract and trap adults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2. Direct counts in blossoms of fruit crops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petunia plants (Petunia x hybrida) are excellent early indicators for WFT presence and for tospoviruses transmission, because petunias are not systemically infected with either virus disease. Presence of silvery leaf scars on other plants is another way of diagnosing WFT presence on plants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;Plant resistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Various efforts are underway to develop cucumber and pepper varieties resistant to WFT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: WFT are difficult to manage with pesticides because they tend to occupy narrow crevices in plant parts, and to feed deep within flowers and buds where they are sheltered from chemicals. Chemical management, mostly with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pyrethroid&#34;&gt;pyrethroids&lt;/a&gt; or spinosad (entry/Spinosad), is difficult due to the development of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance_to_pesticides&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;: Several predatory mites, especially the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;phytoseiid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius cucumeris&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ascidae&#34;&gt;ascid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hypoaspis&lt;/em&gt; have successfully been used to control WFT and are in commerce. Predatory bugs (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;em&gt;Orius&lt;/em&gt; spp., are also common. Other antagonists assayed against WFT include nematodes, such as the nematode (entry/Entomopathogenic&lt;em&gt;nematodes) _Steinernema feltiae&lt;/em&gt; Filipjev, and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Entomopathogenic_fungi&#34;&gt;entomopathogenic fungi&lt;/a&gt;, such as &lt;em&gt;Beauveria bassiana&lt;/em&gt; (Bals.-Criv.) Vuill. and &lt;em&gt;Metarhizium anisopliae&lt;/em&gt; (Met.) Sorokin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bautista, R. C., Mau, R. F. L., Cho, J. J. and Custer, D. M. 1995. Potential of tomato spotted wilt tospovirus plant hosts in Hawaii as virus reservoirs for transmission by &lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt; (Thysanoptera: Thripidae). &lt;em&gt;Phytopathology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;: 953-958.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chambers, R. J., Long, S. and Helyer, B. L. 1993. Effectiveness of &lt;em&gt;Orius laevigatus&lt;/em&gt; (Hem.: Anthocoridae) for the control of &lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt; on cucumber and pepper in the United Kingdom. &lt;em&gt;Biocontrol Science and Technology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;: 295-307.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chyzik, R., Glazer, I. and Klein, M. 1996. Virulence and efficacy of different entomopathogenic  nematode species against western flower thrips (Frankliniella occidentalis). &lt;em&gt;Phytoparastica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;: 103-110.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;de Kogel, W.J., van der Hoek, M. and Mollema, C. 1997. Variation in performance of western flower thrips populations on susceptible and partially resistant cucumber. &lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt;: 73-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fery, R. L. and J. M. Schalk. 1991. Resistance in pepper (&lt;em&gt;Capsicum annuum&lt;/em&gt; L.) to western flower thrips (&lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt; [Pergande]). &lt;em&gt;HortScience&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;: 1073-1074.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gao, Y., Lei, Z. and Reitz, S.R. 2012. Western flower thrips resistance to insecticides: detection, mechanisms and management strategies. &lt;em&gt;Pest Management Science&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;68&lt;/strong&gt;:1111-1121.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kontsedalov, I., Weintraub, P. G., Horowitz, A.R. and. Ishaaya, I. 1998. Effects of insecticides on immature and adult western flower thrips (Thysanoptera: Thripidae) in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;91&lt;/strong&gt;: 1067-1071,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montserrat, M., Castañé, C. and Santamaria, S. 1998. &lt;em&gt;Neozygites parvispora&lt;/em&gt; (Zygomycotina: Entomophthorales) causing an epizootic in &lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt; (Thysanoptera: Thripidae) on cucumber in Spain. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Invertebrate Pathology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;71&lt;/strong&gt;: 165-168.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rugman-Jones, P.F., Hoddle, M.S. and Stouthamer. R. 2010.Nuclear-mitochondrial barcoding (NuMB) exposes the global pest Western flower thrips, &lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt;(Thysanoptera: Thripidae) as two sympatric cryptic species in its native California. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;103&lt;/strong&gt;: 30-38.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vernon, R.S. and Gillespie, D.R. 1995. Influence of trap shape, size, and background color on captures of &lt;em&gt;Frankliniella occidentalis&lt;/em&gt; (Thysanoptera: Thripidae) in a cucumber greenhouse. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt;: 288-293.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_flower_thrips&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_flower_thrips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrips palmi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/thrips_palmi</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/thrips_palmi</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Karny&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Terebrantia&#34;&gt;Terebrantia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thripidae&#34;&gt;Thripidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: melon thrips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest occurs throughout the tropics, as well as in the subtropical region of Florida, and has recently been found in Western Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is about 1.0-1.3 mm long, yellowish to dark-yellow in color, bearing two pairs of large setae on the posterior edge of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prothorax&#34;&gt;prothorax&lt;/a&gt; and little or no banding on the abdomen. The dorsum of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Metathorax&#34;&gt;metathorax&lt;/a&gt; has convergent striations on its posterior margin. The antennae are seven-segmented, the terminal segments mostly dark-brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: About 120 plants are attacked by this pest, including vegetables such as cucurbits, legumes and solanaceous crops, field crops like &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Cotton&#34;&gt;cotton&lt;/a&gt; and sunflower, and even fruit trees, including &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Avocado&#34;&gt;avocado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Mango&#34;&gt;mango&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, the melon thrips infests many weed species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic Importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The melon thrips is a major &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Quarantine_pest&#34;&gt;quarantine pest&lt;/a&gt; that has not yet been reported from the Middle East. It has a rapid rate of development, which means that much damage may occur quickly. Its feeding causes silvery spots on the leaves, which brings about their stunting, wilting and drop. When present in the blossoms, pest feeding causes irregular fruit growth and scarring. Heavy infestations may kill entire plants. In addition, the pest can transmit plant viruses of the tospovirus group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: At 25ºC the pest raises a generation in about 18 days and each female may deposit ca 200 eggs, whose stalks are placed into the host-plant tissue. The emerging thrips often begin to feed inside the tightly rolled leaves, at the growing points of the plant. They undergo two &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphal&lt;/a&gt; and two “pupal” stages, and then live on the underside of expanding leaves and in the blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management:&lt;/strong&gt; The melon thrips is considered to be a dangerous pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: The small size of the melon thrips hinders its recognition, and various methods for its identification are in use, including whole plant examinations under strong light and color traps. Recognition of the pest&amp;rsquo;s presence is of much importance due to its rapid development, especially in regions with a long growing season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Pesticides like &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Imidacloprid&#34;&gt;imidacloprid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt; can provide good control, but &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pyrethroid&#34;&gt;pyrethroids&lt;/a&gt; should be avoided, as they may cause pest population outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Little is known about the natural enemies of the melon thrips, except some generalist predators like &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;phytoseiid&lt;/a&gt; mites, bugs of the genus &lt;em&gt;Orius&lt;/em&gt; spp. and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Entomopathogenic_fungi&#34;&gt;entomopathogenic fungi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Castineiras, A., Baranowski, R.M. and Glenn, H. 1997. Distribution of
&lt;em&gt;Neoseiulus cucumeris&lt;/em&gt; (Acarina: Phytoseiidae) and its prey, &lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt;
(Thysanoptera: Thripidae) within eggplants in south Florida. &lt;em&gt;Florida
Entomologist&lt;/em&gt; 80: 211-217.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Castineiras, A., Peña, J.E., Duncan, R. and Osborne, L. 1996b. Potential of
&lt;em&gt;Beauveria bassiana&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Paecilomyces fumosoroseus&lt;/em&gt; (Deuteromycotina:
Hyphomycetes) as biological control agents of &lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt; (Thysanoptera:
Thripidae). &lt;em&gt;Florida Entomologist&lt;/em&gt; 79: 458-461.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etienne, J., Guyot, J. and, van Waetermeulen, X. 1990. Effect of insecticides,
predation, and precipitation on populations of &lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt; on aubergine
(eggplant) in Guadeloupe. &lt;em&gt;Florida Entomologis&lt;/em&gt; 73: 339-342.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girling DJ. (ed.) 1992. &lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;A Literature Survey with an Annotated
Bibliography&lt;/em&gt;. International Institute of Biological Control, Silwood
Park, Ascot, U.K. 37 pp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tsai, J.H., Yue, B., Webb, S.E., Funderburk, J.E. and Hsu, H.T. 1995. Effects
of host plant and temperature on growth and reproduction of &lt;em&gt;Thrips palmi&lt;/em&gt;
(Thysanoptera: Thripidae). &lt;em&gt;Environmental Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 24: 1598-1603.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.defra.gov.uk/planth/pestnote/thrips.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.defra.gov.uk/planth/pestnote/thrips.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creatures.ifas.ufl.edu/veg/melon_thrips.htm&#34;&gt;http://creatures.ifas.ufl.edu/veg/melon_thrips.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>