<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Acari on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/acari/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria mangiferae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_mangiferae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_mangiferae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria mangiferae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Sayed&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Mango bud (or gall) mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Egypt and Israel, South Africa, southern Asia, Florida, Mexico and several Central and South American regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Mango&#34;&gt;Mango&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mangifera indica&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mango bud mite is considered to be the major pest of mango in Egypt. It lives (sometimes in large numbers, coming to over 20 per bud) in the buds and inflorescences of the host, causing &amp;ldquo;califlower&amp;rdquo;-like growths. Mite feeding stunts and malforms the buds, causes leaf drop and arrests plant growth, resulting in twiggy, stubby branches. Young trees are more heavily attacked. Yield can be greatly reduced. The mite usually occurs along with the pathogenic fungus &lt;em&gt;Fusarium mangiferae&lt;/em&gt;. The feeding wounds of the mite probably serve as portals for the fungus, which appears to cause most of the damage. In addition, &lt;em&gt;A. mangiferae&lt;/em&gt; transmits the fungus between trees and probably between tree parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult mango bud mite is whitish, about 0.20 mm in length, cylindrical. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; bears a pair of backwards-pointing setae set on tubercles with three strong ridges located between them. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feather_claw&#34;&gt;feather claw&lt;/a&gt; is six-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The mango bud mite lives throughout the year within closed adventive buds on the tree trunk and branches, moving into terminal buds duirng periods of population increase. It reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt; and its entire cycle (egg to egg) requires 2-3 weeks in summer, twice that much in winter. The pest raises 8 annual generations in Egypt, with distinct spring and autumn peaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Pruning of the affected twigs may reduce, but not eliminate, the extent of the damage. Certain varieties, such as Maya, Palmer, Keitt and Kent, seem to be resistant as they sustain only very small mite colonies, whereas Tommy Atkins is more affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: The application of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricides&lt;/a&gt; may reduce, but not eliminate, the extent of the damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;phytoseiid&lt;/a&gt; predator &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Amblyseius_swirskii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt; is commonly associated with the mango bud mite but its effect on the pest is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abou-Awad, B.A. 1981. Ecological and biological studies on the mango bud mite,
&lt;em&gt;Eriophyes mangiferae&lt;/em&gt; (Sayed), with descriptions of immature stages
(Eriophyoidea: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Acarologia&lt;/em&gt; 22: 145-150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peña, J. and Johnson, F. 1998. Insect Management in Mango. Department of
Entomology and Nematology Document ENY-413. Florida Cooperative Extension
Service, Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, University of Florida.
Available at:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://edis.ifas.ufl.edu/IG073&#34;&gt;http://edis.ifas.ufl.edu/IG073&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Goldenberg, S. 1976. Mango eriophyid mites in relation to
inflorescence. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 4: 45-50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Wysoki, M. and Izhar, Y. 2002. &lt;em&gt;Subtropical Fruits Pests in
Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Fruit Board of Israel (in Hebrew with English Summary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaher, M.A. and Osman, A.A. 1970. Population studies on mites associated with
mango trees in Egypt. _Bull. Societe d’entomologie Egypte_54: 141-148.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf]&#34;&gt;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria oleae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_oleae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_oleae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria oleae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Olive gall mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Of East Mediterranean origin, the pest has also invaded other Mediterranean countries and South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Olive&#34;&gt;Olive&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Olea europea&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: By feeding within the growing points of the olive, the mite causes the emerging leaves to be deformed and twisted. In severe cases this leads to withering and death, and even total lack of blossoming (and thus prevents fruit formation).  Overall tree development (especially of saplings) and yield may be seriously affected. Greenish spots develop on infested mature leaves which become distorted. Infested young fruit turns silvery and may be deformed by protuberances; more than half the fruit may drop or be damaged. Mature fruits are not attacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that on olives several eriophyid species may live side by side
and infest its organs together, the particular injury attributed to &lt;em&gt;A. oleae&lt;/em&gt;
may actually be due to one or more species damaging the host together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult mite is yellow, about 0.13 mm in length, cylindrical, with a similar number (50-60) of dorsal and ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ppisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosomal&lt;/a&gt; rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt; prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; has an obscure pattern with lines that are discernible only towards the rear and bears two long backwards-pointing setae; the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; The olive gall mite prefers young olives growing in warm and humid conditions, thus thriving in nurseries and well-irrigated young plantations, and infesting mainly the peripheral growth. It passes the winter hidden on the lower sides of the leaves, the populations moving to the flower clusters in spring. In Greece the pest raised 12-15 annual generations in the field, and its populations peaked during June-July, with a smaller rise in late September. The mite reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt; arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;, each female depositing up to 40 eggs. When reared in the laboratory on olive leaf disks at 21-24ºC, its life cycle (egg to egg) required about a forthnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Some olive varieties seem to be tolerant to the pest. In addition, horticultural practices, such as pruning or topping, induce new growth and thus the formation of more susceptible buds. The mite may spread to new areas by infested seedlings, which should be suitably treated prior to transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: In the past the mite was often controlled with wettable sulfur, usually applied early in the season. Nowadays either amitraz or &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt; will control the pest when applied before olive blooming, in order to prevent damage to fruit, or given several times during the season if leaf damage is to be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Several predatory mites of the family &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; are associated with the olive gall mite, the most abundant species in Italy being &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athenas&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Swirski and Ragusa&lt;/code&gt;. Although the quantitative effect of the various phytoseiids has not been resolved, it is commonly believed that eriophyid olive pests are held below their economic injury threshold by the predators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abd Elhadi, F. and Birger, R. 1999. A new approach to the control of the olive
mite &lt;em&gt;Aceria&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Eriophyes&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;em&gt;oleae&lt;/em&gt; in olive trees. &lt;em&gt;Acta Horticulturae&lt;/em&gt;
474: 555-557.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Castagnoli, M. and Oldfield, G.N. 1996. Other fruit trees and nut trees. In:
&lt;em&gt;Eriophyoid Mites, Their Biology, Natural Enemies and Control&lt;/em&gt; (edited by
Lindquist, E.E., Sabelis, M.W. and Bruin, J.), pp. 543–559. Elsevier,
Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harpaz, I. 1955. Notes on the eriophyid mites of Israel. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the
Research Council of Israel&lt;/em&gt; (Section B) 5: 61-69.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hatzinikolis, E.N. 1973. A contribution to the study of &lt;em&gt;Aceria oleae&lt;/em&gt;
(Nalepa, 1900) (Acarina: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International
Congress of Entomology&lt;/em&gt;, Junk, The Hague, pp. 221-224.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria sheldoni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_sheldoni</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_sheldoni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria sheldoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ewing)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Citrus bud mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; is grown. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #127, 1980 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Citrus&lt;/em&gt; spp., especially lemons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The bud mites lives in and feed on the buds, blossoms and flowers of the host. They sometimes occurs in very large numbers. Their feeding kills the cells and causes the blackening of the buds and irregular growth of leaves, branches and fruit. The damaged buds proliferate and produce irregular and twisted growth of leaf clusters. Twigs are foreshortened and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Brooming&#34;&gt;broomed&lt;/a&gt; and the fruit deforms into various distorted shapes, including finger-like forms. Further damage is caused by fruit drop. Although the pest attacks all citrus varieties, it causes the most serious damage to lemons, whose yield may be seriously affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult citrus bud mite is yellow to pink, about 0.17 mm in length, cylindrical, with a similar number (70-80) of dorsal and ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt; opisthosomal&lt;/a&gt; rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; bears a pair of backwards-pointing setae and two parallel ridges along its entire length. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt; featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is five-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus rust mite reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt; arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;, each female deposits about 50 eggs, and its entire cycle (egg to egg) requires about 15 days in summer, twice that much in winter. The pest thus raises about 20 annual generations. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sex_Ratio&#34;&gt; sex ratio&lt;/a&gt; is male-biased in spring and female-biased during fall. Although the mite lacks eyes, it is attracted to yellow and red, not to blue or green. The pest develops throughout the year, mostly in milder and more humid regions, with peaks in the spring and autumn. Dispersal takes place during the spring growth of most citrus trees and the several growth flushes of lemons. Young, elongating twigs are rapidly colonized by the mite, its infestations increasing as the twigs age. Temperatures below 8°C or above 35°C, and relative humidity below 40% are lethal to the mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managenment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: When necessary, the mite can be controlled by most acaricides as well as by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/White_Oils&#34;&gt; white oil&lt;/a&gt;, but the cost of such control may exceed the its economic benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Several predatory mites have
been found to be associated with the citrus bud mite, but due to being
protected inside the buds, none appear to effect the populations or the damage
caused by the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. 1969. A study of fluctuations in the citrus bud mite
population. &lt;em&gt;Annales de Zoologie-Écologie animale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;: 127-147.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. 1969. Effect of different wave lengths of light on the
behaviour of an eriophyid bud mite, &lt;em&gt;Aceria sheldoni&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Entomologia
Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;: 377-382.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Goldenberg, S. 1971. Fertilisation, sex ratio and
postembryonic stages of the citrus bud mite _ Aceria sheldoni_ (Ewing)
(Acarina, Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of Entomological Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;: 391-397.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker, G.P., Voulgaropoulos, A.L. and Phillips, P.A. 1992. Effect of citrus
bud mite (Acari: Eriophyidae) on lemon yields. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;: 1318-1329.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker, G.P., Voulgaropoulos, A.L. and Phillips, P.A. 1992. Distribution of
citrus bud mite (Acari: Eriophyidae) within lemon trees. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;: 2389-2398.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viarural.com.ar/viarural.com.ar/agricultura/frutales/plagas/aceria-sheldoni.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.viarural.com.ar/viarural.com.ar/agricultura/frutales/plagas/aceria-sheldoni.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aculops lycopersici</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculops_lycopersici</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculops_lycopersici</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Massee)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt;Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Tomato russet mite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;entry/images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Worldwide; in the Middle East known since the late 1940s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map # 164, 1987.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Many members of the family Solanaceae, especially in the genera &lt;em&gt;Lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Solanum&lt;/em&gt;. Bindweed, &lt;em&gt;Convolvulus arvensis&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt; (Convolvulaceae), also serves as host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Infestations on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Tomato&#34;&gt;tomato&lt;/a&gt; usually begin in the lower parts of host plants, on the stems and leaves, which lose their color, wilt and drop. Attacked tomatoes become bronzed and rough, and severe infestations cause plant withering and death. Yield is much reduced. Tomato is the most heavily affected host plant, but petunia, pepper and potato may also be damaged. Infested eggplants usually show less damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is spindle-shaped, yellowish, about 0.16-0.18 mm in length, with a pair of backwards-pointing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsal&lt;/a&gt; setae. The dorsal shield bears two ridges that are parallel along their posterior half but diverge anteriorly. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosoma&lt;/a&gt; has about 30 dorsal and 60 ventral rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feather_claw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is a warm-weather leaf vagrant that has no dormancy and dies if exposed to sub-freezing temperatures. Development is also retarded under high humidity conditions at high temperatures. In temperate regions the pest survives winters only within greenhouses, but under warmer conditions &lt;em&gt;A. lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; lives out of season on bindweed or on wild Solanaceae. These plants serve as sources for the infestation of crops, reaching them with winds, insects or by clinging to farming implements and personnel. An entire life cycle cn be completed in about one week, each female producing 30-50 progeny. Like other Eriophyidae, reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;; males deposite &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; on the leaves that are taken up by the females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: Tomato varieties whose leaves bear more &lt;a href=&#34;entry/trichome&#34;&gt;trichomes&lt;/a&gt; are less susceptible to the mite. Various mineral fertilization regimes or plant height have no effect on the pest&amp;rsquo;s level of attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Several acarine
predators in the families &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmaeidae&#34;&gt;Stigmaeidae&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tydeaidae&#34;&gt;Tydeidae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the pest in the
laboratory, but little is known about their effect in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;Acaricides&lt;/a&gt; effective against the pest include &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt;, dicofol, cyhexatin and compounds of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Bacillus_thuringiensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson, L.A. 1954. The tomato russet mite in the United States. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 47: 1001-1005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harpaz, I. 1955. Notes on the eriophyid mites of Israel. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the
Research Council of Israel&lt;/em&gt; 5B: 61-69.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hessein, N. A. and Perring, T.M. 1986. Feeding habits of the Tydeidae with
evidence of &lt;em&gt;Homeopronematus anconai&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Tydeidae) predation on &lt;em&gt;Aculops
lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Acarology&lt;/em&gt;
12: 215-221.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leite, G.L.D., PicanÇo, M., Guedes, R.N.C. and Zanuncio, J.C. 1999. Influence
of canopy height and fertilization levels on the resistance of &lt;em&gt;Lycopersicon
hirsutum&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Experimental and
Applied Acarology&lt;/em&gt; 23: 633-642.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osman, A.A. and Zaki, A.M. 1986. Studies on the predation efficiency of
&lt;em&gt;Agistemus exsertus&lt;/em&gt; Gonzalez (Acarina, Stigmaeidae) on the eriophyid mite
&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Massee). &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger Schadlingskunde Pflazenschutz,
Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt; 59: 135-136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice, R.E. and Strong, F.E. 1962. Bionomics of the tomato russet mite,
&lt;em&gt;Vasates lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Massee). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 55:
431-435.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Royalty, R.N. and Perring, T.M. 1987. Comparative toxicity of acaricides to
&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Homeopronematus anconai&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae:
Tydeidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 80: 348-351.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/a_lycope.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/a_lycope.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.
inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aculyc.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aculyc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)

 --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aculus cornutus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculus_cornutus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculus_cornutus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculus cornutus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Banks)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;[= &lt;em&gt;fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt;]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt;Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Silver peach mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: almost wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Peach&#34;&gt;peaches&lt;/a&gt; are grown. In the Middle East since the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Stone fruit trees (Rosaceae), including &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Almond&#34;&gt;almonds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apricot&#34;&gt;apricots&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Peach&#34;&gt;nectarines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Plum&#34;&gt;plums&lt;/a&gt; and prunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The feeding of the peach silver mite causes silvering of peach foliage late in the season as well as yellow chlorotic spots on young leaves. In heavy infestations the leaves curl and may drop, plant growth is retarded and yield is affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is spindle-shaped, yellowish, about 0.18 mm in length, with a pair of backwards-pointing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsal&lt;/a&gt; setae. The dorsal shield bears several parallel ridges that are more pronounced in the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Deutogyne&#34;&gt;deutogynes&lt;/a&gt;, which is also somewhat larger. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosoma&lt;/a&gt; has about 30 dorsal and 50 ventral rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is a leaf vagrant, overwintering around the host&amp;rsquo;s terminal buds as deutogynes, which appear in the autumn, and molt to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Protogyne&#34;&gt;protogynes&lt;/a&gt; next spring. A life cycle is completed in about a fortnight, and 15-20 annual generations may be raised. Like other Eriophyidae, reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;; the males deposit &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; that are taken up by the females. Fecundity is host-determined, as the mite produced 41 eggs/female on plum, only 31 on sour cherry. The protogynes of the peach silver mite differ in some morphological from the deutogynes, and were formerly described as a different species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;Acaricides&lt;/a&gt; in common usage against the pest include bromopropylate (Neoron), chlorobenzilate and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt;. The peach silver mite is not affected by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pyrethroid&#34;&gt;pyrethroids&lt;/a&gt; and applications of these compounds abroad have resulted in pest resurgences, probably due to killing its natural enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest appears to have several efficient natural enemies of the family &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; abroad, but nothing is known about them in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boczek, J., Zawadski, W. and Davis, R. 1984. Some morphological and biological
differences in &lt;em&gt;Aculus fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae)
on various host plants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Acarology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;:81-87.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kondo, A. and Hiramatsu, T. 1999. Resurgences of the peach silver mite,
&lt;em&gt;Aculus fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae), induced by a
synthetic pyrethroid fluvalinate. &lt;em&gt;Applied Entomology and Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt;:
531-535.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Rubin, A. 1990. The peach silver mite, a new pest in
Israel. &lt;em&gt;Ha&amp;rsquo;Sadeh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt;: 910-912 (in Hebrew with an English summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r602400211.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r602400211.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amblyseius swirskii</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/amblyseius_swirskii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/amblyseius_swirskii</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mesostigmata&#34;&gt;Mesostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Many indigenous and introduced plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: Dorsum about 0.3-0.4 mm in length, almost smooth, with a few &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Reticulations&#34;&gt;reticulations&lt;/a&gt;, and 17 pairs of nude setae plus two pairs of lateral setae. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternal_Plate&#34;&gt;sternal plate&lt;/a&gt; bears three pairs of setae, and there are three pairs of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Preanal_Setae&#34;&gt;preanal setae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; is the dominant summer phytoseiid predator in &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; groves along the coastal plain of Israel, where it is possibly one of the main natural enemies of the citrus rust mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phyllocoptruta_oleivora&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta oleivora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Ashmead). More recently _A. swirskii _has been developed by the Dutch company Koppert B.V. as a natural enemy of thrips (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;), and whiteflies (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aleyrodidae&#34;&gt;Aleyrodidae&lt;/a&gt;). By late 2006 more than one billion predators, mostly within slow-release bags, known as Swirski-Mite Plus, have been sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;:The female mite required less than one week to complete a generation at 27°C, produced 44 eggs when feeding on an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;eriophyid&lt;/a&gt; mite and lived about four weeks. The predator also feeds on other prey, including many pest mites, thrips, whiteflies, the eggs of moths (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;) and the crawlers of scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;), as well as on pollen. &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; has no winter &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El-Laithy, A.Y.M. 1998. Laboratory studies on growth parameters of three
predatory mites associated with eriophyid mites in olive nurseries. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Planzenkrankheiten und Pflanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt;: 78-83.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porath, A. and Swirski, E. 1965. A survey of phytoseiid mites (Acarina:
Phytoseiidae) on citrus, with a description of one new species. &lt;em&gt;Israel
Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;: 87-100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ragusa, S. and Swirski, E. 1977. Feeding habits, post-embryonic and adult
survival, mating, virility and fecundity of the predacious mite &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius
swirskii&lt;/em&gt; (Acarina: Phytoseiidae) on some coccids and mealybugs. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;: 383-92.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Amitai, S. and Dorzia, N. 1967. Laboratory studies on the
feeding, development and reproduction of the predaceous mites &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius
rubini&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Swirski &amp;amp; Amitai&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias&lt;/code&gt; (Acarina:
Phytoseiidae) on various kinds of food substances. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of
Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;: 101-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitefly.org/whiteflyforum/forum_posts.asp?TID=82&#34;&gt;http://www.whitefly.org/whiteflyforum/forum_posts.asp?TID=82&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eriophyidae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/eriophyidae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/eriophyidae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Gall mites; bud mites, rust mites, blister mites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The Eriophyidae include major plant pests such as the citrus rust mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phyllocoptruta_pleivora&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta oleivora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ashmead)&lt;/code&gt; and the tomato russet mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aculops_lycopersici&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Massee)&lt;/code&gt;. They cause various kinds of damage; their common names derive from the specific injury. They induce gall formation, russetting, plant stunting, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Brooming&#34;&gt;brooming&lt;/a&gt; and leaf rolling; some injuries are due to injected toxins, others to wounding the epidermal layer. In addition, some eriophyids transmit plant viruses. In severe cases these mites can totally destroy the yield, or seriously reduce its economic value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: Eriophyids are minute mites (0.15-0.35 mm long) with elongate, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Annulate.html&#34;&gt;annulate&lt;/a&gt;, worm-like bodies, two pairs of anteriorly placed legs and, close behind them, a transverse genital aperture. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsal&lt;/a&gt; shield bears 2 pairs of or none. The tarsi lack claws but bear a feather-shaped &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Empodium&#34;&gt;empodium&lt;/a&gt;, commonly called &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feather_claw&#34;&gt;feather claw&lt;/a&gt;. The chelicerae are stylettiform. About 3,400 species in more than 250 genera have so far been named.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: All Eriophyidae feed on plants and most are highly specific to their hosts (and at times even to particular organs or sites). They have a foreshortened life cycle, consisting of egg, larva, nymph and adults, a cycle often requiring less than one week. Reproduction is mostly by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;. Males deposit &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; that the females locate (probably due by an unidentified pheromone) and insert into their bodies. Some species, especially those living on evergreens, have a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Heteromorphic&#34;&gt;heteromorphic&lt;/a&gt; female form, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Deutogyne&#34;&gt;deutogyne&lt;/a&gt;, which conserves the species during harsh (usually cold) seasons. Deutogynes breed only in the year following their own genesis, when they give rise to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Protogyne&#34;&gt;protogynes&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Homeomorphic&#34;&gt;homeomorphic&lt;/a&gt; females, which reproduce in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eriophyids are often dispersed by winds, the females moving to exposed sites
and positioning themselves against the wind. Single wind-borne females can
then establish new colonies. Dispersal also takes place on infested plant
material and (more seldom) on animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eriophyid pests included in this compendium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aceria_mangiferae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria mangiferae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (mango bud mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aceria_oleae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria oleae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (olive gall mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aceria_sheldoni&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria sheldoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (citrus bud mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aculops_lycopersici&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (tomato russet mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aculus_cornutus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculus cornutus&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;Silver peach mite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Colomerus_vitis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Colomerus vitis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (grape erineum mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phyllocoptruta_oleivora&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta oleivora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (citrus rust mite)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amrine, J.W. Jr. (1996a) &lt;em&gt;Keys to the World Genera of the Eriophyoidea (Acari:
Prostigmata)&lt;/em&gt;. Indira Publishing House, West Bloomfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amrine J.W. Jr. &amp;amp; Stasny, T.A. (1994) &lt;em&gt;Catalog of the Eriophyoidea (Acarina:
Prostigmata) of the World&lt;/em&gt;. Indira Publishing House, West Bloomfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baker, E.W., Kono, T., Amrine, J.W. Jr., Delfinado-Baker, M. &amp;amp; Stasny, T.A.
(1996). &lt;em&gt;Eriophyoid Mites of the United States&lt;/em&gt;. Indira Publishing House, West
Bloomfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lindquist, E.E., Sabelis, M.W. &amp;amp; Bruin, J. (Eds.) (1996) &lt;em&gt;Eriophyoid Mites,
Their Biology, Natural Enemies and Control&lt;/em&gt;. Elsevier, Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/ZGLOSS/6g---129.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/ZGLOSS/6g&amp;mdash;
129.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cfl.scf.rncan.gc.ca
/collections-cfl/insectes/classgen/aca_eriophyidae&#34;&gt; http://www.cfl.scf.rncan.gc.ca/collections-
cfl/insectes/classgen/aca_eriophyidae.html &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

[ InsertText For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutetranychus orientalis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_orientalis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_orientalis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Klein)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychoidea&#34;&gt;Tetranychoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig30pr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/EutetranychusOrientalis-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Oriental spider mite, citrus brown mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite occurs in the eastern Mediterranean countries, in Asia from India to China and in most of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite may develop on over two hundred host plants, mostly &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Dicotyledones&#34;&gt;dicotyledons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult female is about 0.4-0.5 mm in length, brownish, with a oval body and its legs are about as long as the body (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/EutetranychusOrientalis-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: A colony of Eutetranychus orientalis on a citrus leaf&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male is reddish, smaller, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hysteronotum&#34;&gt;hysteronotum&lt;/a&gt; is pointed and the legs are longer than the body. The dorsal setae are short, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spatulate&#34;&gt;spatulate&lt;/a&gt; and placed on small tubercles. The rounded eggs are pale-brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite is an important pest of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, especially in drier areas. It is the most persistent citrus pest in Upper Egypt and an occasional serious pest in the south of Israel. The mites colonize the upper side of leaves where they feed, and their damage develops as yellow-grey stippled spots which cause leaf wilting and drop. Heavy infestations may cause fruit drop and the death of upper branches, and next-years&amp;rsquo; blossoming may be severely affected. Reduced irrigation increases the damage. Lemon trees are more damaged than other citrus species and varieties, whereas oranges are little affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: The mites colonize the upper side of leaves whereon their eggs are deposited along the midrib. The threshold of development is at 10° and development requires about two weeks at around 25°C. Each female produces 30-40 eggs during two-three weeks. The pest raises about 20 annual, largely overlapping generations. Like other Tetranychoidea, the Oriental spider mite is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sex_ratio&#34;&gt;sex ratio&lt;/a&gt; is usually 0.7, female-biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite has not yet developed &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to pesticides. Thus it may still be be controlled by such commonly-used &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricides&lt;/a&gt; as amitraz and dicofol, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organotin&#34;&gt;organotin&lt;/a&gt; fenbutatin oxide and even petroleum oils. However, the pest seems to be less susceptible to some of these chemicals, and continuous monitoring for resistance is thus necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The pest is attacked by many
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Indigenous&#34;&gt;indigenous&lt;/a&gt; predatory mites of the families
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmaeidae&#34;&gt;Stigmaeidae&lt;/a&gt;. The phytoseiid &lt;em&gt;Euseius scutalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Athias-Henriot)&lt;/code&gt; appears to regulate the
citrus brown mite in Jordan, but little is known about its specificity and the
ability of other predators to reduce pest outbreak populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, H.Z. 1936. Contributions to the knowledge of the red spiders in
Palestine. 1. The Oriental red spider, &lt;em&gt;Anychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt; Zacher. &lt;em&gt;Hadar&lt;/em&gt;
9: 107-111, 126-132.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drishpoun, Y. 2000. &lt;em&gt;A Guide to the Control of Citrus Pests&lt;/em&gt;. Ministry of
Agriculture and Rural Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Momen, F. and El-Borolossy, M. 1999. Suitability of the citrus brown mite,
&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt; as prey for nine species of phytoseiid mites
(Acari: Tetranychidae, Phytoseiidae). &lt;em&gt;Acarologia&lt;/em&gt; 40: 19-23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osman, M.S. 1997. Petroleum oils as a component of integrated pest management
of phytophagous mites. &lt;em&gt;Arab Journal of Scientific Research&lt;/em&gt; 15: 125-135.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanigoshi, L.K., Bahdousheh, M., Babcock, J.M. and Sawaqed, R. 1990. &lt;em&gt;Euseius
scutalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Athias-Henriot)&lt;/code&gt; a predator of &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Klein)&lt;/code&gt; in
Jordan: toxicity of some acaricides to &lt;em&gt;E. orientalis&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Arab Journal of Plant
Protection&lt;/em&gt; 8: 114-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaher, M.A., Wafa, A.K., Maher Ali, M. and Rasmy, A.H. 1970. Survey of mites
associated with citrus trees in Egypt and Gaza Strip. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin de la Societe
Entomologique d&amp;rsquo;Egypte&lt;/em&gt; 56: 73-79.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ento.csiro.au/aicn/system/c_204.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.ento.csiro.au/aicn/system/c_204.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutetranychus palmatus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_palmatus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_palmatus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychoidea&#34;&gt;Tetranychoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: This mite occurs in Egypt and in the south of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt; has been found on various Palmae, including the &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Date_palms&#34;&gt;date palm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Phoenix dactylifera&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Washingtonia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hyphaene&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult female is about 0.4-0.5 mm in length, red-brown, with an oval body and legs that are about as long as the body. The male is reddish, smaller, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hysteronotum&#34;&gt;hysteronotum&lt;/a&gt; is pointed and the legs are longer than the body. The dorsal setae are short and serate, not placed on small tubercles. The rounded eggs are pale-brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt; is a minor pest of date palm fruit (apparently more of the cultivar &amp;lsquo;Barhi&amp;rsquo;), whose feeding produces exudates that later become covered by dust as well as by the mites&amp;rsquo; shed skins. Its damage may be masked by that of &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Oligonychus_afrasiaticus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oligonychus afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt; (with which it often co-occurs), and could become more severe where &lt;em&gt;O. afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt; is not present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: Little is known about the biology of &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;. It develops thorough the year on the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Frond&#34;&gt;fronds&lt;/a&gt;, moving onto the fruit during mid-summer earlier then &lt;em&gt;O. afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt;, and back to the fronds when the dates turn yellow. Like other Tetranychoidea, this mite is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;: No measures to control this mite have so far been necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attiah, H.H. 1967. The genus &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus&lt;/em&gt; in U.A.R. with descriptions of
three new species (Acarina: Tetranychidae). &lt;em&gt;Bulletin de la Societe
Entomologique d&amp;rsquo;Egypte&lt;/em&gt; 51: 11-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., Venezian, A. and Blumberg, D. 1983. Phytophagous mites on date
palms in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Fruits&lt;/em&gt; 38: 133-135.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palevsky, E., Ucko, O., Peles, S. and Gerson, U. The phenology of
&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Tetranychidae) on date palms in
Israel. Submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllocoptruta oleivora</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/phyllocoptruta_oleivora</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/phyllocoptruta_oleivora</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta oleivora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ashmead)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt;Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;figpr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/thumbnails/phyllocoptruta-sm.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Citrus rust mite, silver mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; is grown. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #78, 1978 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Citrus&lt;/em&gt; spp.; &lt;em&gt;Swinglea glutinosa&lt;/em&gt; ; &lt;em&gt;Fortunella&lt;/em&gt; spp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus rust mite is wedge-shaped, yellowish in color, about 0.15 mm in length, with a pair of very short prodorsal setae. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; bears a six-sided cell and the
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosoma&lt;/a&gt;
is marked by a distinct dorsal furrow. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is five-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The vagrant mites feed on the fruit, leaves and green twigs, piercing the epidermal cells and killing them. Rust-like blemishes that consist of masses of dead cells, appear on the affected areas on orange, grapefruit and mandarin fruits; on lemons and citron they are silvery. As infestation proceeds the surface of the fruit becomes russetted and bronzed, rough and scaly; peels of young fruit lose their elasticity and may shrivel. Dark spots appear on affected leaves, which may also lose their gloss, and their lower surfaces become rust-like. Infested green twigs may show blackish areas.&lt;br /&gt;
The mite cannot feed on the russetted fruit rind and will not be found there;
it should be looked for at the margins of the affected area, and is also very
common around the sepals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The citrus rust mite is a major pest of citrus; unless controlled it can
affect 70-100% of the yield. Heavily infested fruit is smaller, its quality is
reduced and it may drop; such fruit is rejected as fresh product and by the
industry. Attack on leaves and twigs can affect next year&amp;rsquo;s growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus rust mite develops throughout the year, its entire cycle (egg to egg) requiring about a week in summer, several weeks in winter, and the pest may raise 30 annual generations. The mite has four stages: egg, two nymphs and adults. Reproduction is indirect; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; are deposited by males on the leaf substrate and taken up by the females. The species is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;, each female depositing about a dozen eggs at a range of temperatures between 20-31°C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecology&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus rust mite lives only on its host plants. Conditions optimal for its development are temperatures around 25°C and very high relative humidity. The mite is resistant to sub-freezing temperatures but susceptible to warm and dry winds. Consequently its populations (unless reduced by hot winds) increase during spring, remain high in the summer and decline in autumn. Mites (mostly females) disperse between patches when borne on winds and on infested plant material, such dispersal taking place throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;: Before fruit are about 1.5 cm in diameter, the citrus rust mite will be found mostly on the underside of young leaves. Later the mites prefer the fruit, initially feeding at protected sites, and later on its entire surface. Orchards, or parts thereof where the pest occurred in former years, should be sampled early in the season. An examination of four fruits, taken from around the tree (with hand lens of 10X or more magnification), of 1 cm² per fruit, will provide a reasonable estimate of infestation, provided 10 or more mites are present in each sample. A rapid estimate of the population can also be obtained by using standardized visual keys based on estimating infestation rates per 1 cm² of plant surface and comparing them to the keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crop resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: Citrus varieties differ in their attractiveness to the citrus rust mite. Lemons, oranges, tangerines and rough lemon are very susceptible, whereas pummelo and sour orange seem to be resistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to the rapid rate of increase of the citrus rust mite, it is usually recommended to treat it as soon as the pest is recognized, especially at sites that had experienced damage in the past. A repeat spray may be needed within 4-6 weeks. Fruit intended for processing can tolerate some cosmetic damage and may require fewer chemical treatments than fruit sold on the fresh market. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;Acaricides&lt;/a&gt; in current common usage include bromopropylate (Neoron), dicofol, maneb, quinomethionate, abamectin and zineb compounds (e.g. metiram). Field &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance_to_pesticides&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to zineb has been reported from Florida, Cyprus and Israel, and resistance to dicofol was found in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural enemies&lt;/strong&gt;: Several predatory mites of the families &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmaeidae&#34;&gt;Stigmaeidae&lt;/a&gt; prey on the citrus rust mite, and may be able to control the pest in combination, especially if active during early spring. None, however, appears to be either specific or capable of predictably controlling the pest. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaropathogenic_fungi&#34;&gt;acaropathogenic fungus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hirsutella thompsonii&lt;/em&gt; periodically controls the citrus rust mite in Florida and has been used for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allen, J.C., Yang, Y. and Knapp, J.L 1995. Temperature effects on development
and fecundity of citrus rust mite (Acari: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Environmental
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;: 996-1004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bergh, J.C. 2001. Ecology and aerobiology of dispersing citrus rust mites
(Acari: Eriophyidae) in central Florida. _ Environmental Entomology_ &lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt;:
318-326.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Childers, C.C. 1994. Biological control of phytophagous mites on Florida
citrus utilizing predatory arthropods. In D. Rosen, F.D. Bennett and J.L.
Capinera (Eds), &lt;em&gt;Pest Management in the Subtropics: Biological Control - A
Florida Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Intercept, Pp. 255-288. Andover, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hobza, R.F. and Jeppson, L.R. 1974. A temperature and humidity study of citrus
rust mite employing a constant humidity air-flow technique. &lt;em&gt;Environmental
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;: 813-823.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palevsky, E., Argov, Y., Ben-David, T. and Gerson, U. 2003. Identification and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;evaluation of potential predators of the citrus rust mite, &lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta
oleivora&lt;/em&gt;, in Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Systematic and Applied Acarology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;: 39-48.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rogers, J.S., McCoy, C.W. and Manners, M.M. 1994. Standardized visual
comparison keys for rapid estimations of citrus rust mite (Acari: Eriophyidae)
populations. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;87&lt;/strong&gt;: 1507-1512.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yue, B., Sun, M. and Qiu, A. 1998. A comparison of citrus resistance to citrus
rust mite (Acari: Eriophyidae) in the laboratory. &lt;em&gt;Systematic and Applied
Acarology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;: 59-62.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r107400511.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r107400511.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenuipalpidae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/tenuipalpidae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/tenuipalpidae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenuipalpidae&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acariformes&#34;&gt;Acariformes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt; Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychoidea&#34;&gt;Tetranychoidea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: False spider mites, flat mites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pest/images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: All Tenuipalpidae are phytophagous and several are pests of crops, including (in the Middle East) &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Grapes&#34;&gt;grapes&lt;/a&gt;. Their feeding causes leaf mottling and necrosis, fruit blistering and deformation, and may reduce yields. In rare cases false spider mites induce the formation of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Gall&#34;&gt;galls&lt;/a&gt;. In Florida and in South America several species of the genus &lt;em&gt;Brevipalpus&lt;/em&gt; transmit plant viruses (e.g. leprosis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: False spider mites are usually red to yellow, with flat bodies, about 0.3-0.4 mm in length. They have strongly-recurved whip-like &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chelicerae&#34;&gt;chelicerae&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Palpi&#34;&gt;palpi&lt;/a&gt; with 1-5 segments, whose tarsus lacks a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thumb_claw&#34;&gt;thumb-claw&lt;/a&gt; complex and short legs with sometimes modified &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Empodium&#34;&gt;empodia&lt;/a&gt;. The dorsum usually bears a reduced number of setae and two pairs of eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecology&lt;/strong&gt;: The Tenuipalpidae are sensitive to arid conditions, usually preferring to feed on the lower sides of leaves near the veins, at protected sites on fruits, also occurring on plant bark and even in galls. Most species have a narrow host plant range, but a few are very polyphagous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Most investigated tenuipalpids require 3-4 weeks at ca 25°C to complete a generation, and usually deposit about 30 to 50 eggs/female. Reproduction is usually by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;, although a few species are &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenetic&lt;/a&gt;. One cosmopolitan species, &lt;em&gt;Brevipalpus phoenicis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Geijskes)&lt;/code&gt;, appears to consist only of haploid females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;False spider mites included in this compendium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/brevipalpus_obovatus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brevipalpus obovatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Donnadieu)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/tenuipalpus_granati&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tenuipalpus granati&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sayed&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Childers, C.C. and Derrick, K.S. 2003. &lt;em&gt;Brevipalpus&lt;/em&gt; mites as vectors of
unassigned rhabdoviruses in various crops. &lt;em&gt;Experimental and Applied
Acarology&lt;/em&gt; 30: 1-3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeppson, L.R ., Keifer, H.H. and Baker, E.W. 1975. &lt;em&gt;Mites Injurious to
Economic Plants&lt;/em&gt;. University California Press, Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meyer Smith, M.K.P. 1979. The Tenuipalpidae (Acari) of Africa with keys to the
world genera. &lt;em&gt;Entomology Memoir, Department of Agricultural Technical
Services, Republic of South Africa&lt;/em&gt; 50: 1-135.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks, A.R., Marec, F. and Breeuwer, J.A.J. 2001. A mite that consists
entirely of haploid females. &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; 292: 2479-2482.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sel.barc.usda.gov/acari/content/brevipalpus/brevi1.html&#34;&gt;http://www.sel.barc.usda.gov/acari/content/brevipalpus/brevi1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact:  [ Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typhlodromus athiasae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/typhlodromus_athiasae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/typhlodromus_athiasae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athiasae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Porath &amp;amp; Swirski&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mesostigmata&#34;&gt;Mesostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle East, Greece and Libya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Many indigenous and introduced, annual and perennial plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: Length of the reticulated dorsum about 0.3 mm, with 17 pairs of nude setae plus two pairs of lateral setae. All dorsal setae on the anterior part of the body subequal in length, the posterior setae longer. A single &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Macrosetae&#34;&gt;macroseta&lt;/a&gt; present on leg IV. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternal_plate&#34;&gt;sternal plate&lt;/a&gt; with four pairs of setae, and there are four pairs of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Preanal_setae&#34;&gt;preanal setae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: In Israel &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athiasae&lt;/em&gt; is the dominant phytoseiid predator of the European red mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Panonychus_ulmi&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panonychus ulmi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Koch on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apple&#34;&gt;apples&lt;/a&gt; , and often reduces its populations. It is also the dominant phytoseiid on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;  trees in the inner parts of Israel and in the Nile Delta region of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athiasae&lt;/em&gt; raised a generation in 11-12 days at 25°C and produced about 30 eggs in 20 days at that temperature and 70% relative humidity. Fecundity was reduced at higher or lower relative humidities. The pollen of &lt;em&gt;Carpobrotus edulis&lt;/em&gt; (Aizoaceae) and the spider mite &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Tetranychus_urticae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tetranychus urticae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Koch provided the best nutrients for reproduction, but the mite can also survive and lay eggs on many other foods. A single mating sufficed for fertilizing all female eggs. The larvae did not feed but other stages were cannibalistic. The mite does not have a winter
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McMurtry, J.A. 1977. Some predaceous mites (Phytoseiidae) on citrus in the
Mediterranean region. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt;: 22: 19-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rasmy, A.H., Zaher, M.A. and Albagoury, M.E. 1972. Mites associated with
citrus in the Nile Delta (U.A.R.). &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift fur Angewandte Entomologie&lt;/em&gt;
70: 183-186.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reuveny, H., Palevsky, E. and Gerson, U. 1996. Laboratory life history of the
predaceous mite &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athiasae&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Systematic and Applied Acarology&lt;/em&gt;
!: 45-54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Amitai, S. and Dorzia, N. 1967. Laboratory studies on the
feeding, development and oviposition of the predaceous mite &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus
athiasae&lt;/em&gt; P. &amp;amp; R. (Acarina: Phytoseiidae) on various kinds of food substances.
&lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; 17: 213-218.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porath, A. &amp;amp; Swirski, E. 1965. A survey of phytoseiid mites (Acarina:
Phytoseiidae) on citrus, with a description of one new species. &lt;em&gt;Israel
Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; 15: 87-100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  
Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)

 --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>