<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Holometabola on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/holometabola/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agrotis ipsilon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/agrotis_ipsilon</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/agrotis_ipsilon</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agrotis ipsilon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Hufnagel)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Noctuidae&#34;&gt;Noctuidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Black cutworm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost cosmopolitan, Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #261, 1969.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Seedlings of most crops, including legumes, crucifers, Solanaceae and &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Cotton&#34;&gt;cotton&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Larvae commonly feed on seedlings, cutting off their stems at ground level, which topples them. Additionally, the larvae may feed on roots, thus occasionally causing great damage in newly planted fields (e.g. cotton) early in the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The specific name of the pest (&lt;em&gt;ipsilon&lt;/em&gt;) derives from the markings on the adult &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Forewing&#34;&gt;forewing&lt;/a&gt;, which resemble the Greek character &amp;ldquo;ipsilon&amp;rdquo;. Its common name (&amp;ldquo;cutworm&amp;rdquo;) is due to the nature of the damage, the cutting off of seedlings at ground level, and the dark background coloration of the larval integument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Female adults, which are reproductively immature on emergence, begin oviposition within a week and survive for about another week. During their gravid period eggs are deposited singly or in small clusters, on the underside of leaves, near ground level. A female may lay up to 1900 eggs during its lifetime. The larvae disperse after the first molt and remain solitary for the rest of their lives, residing in the soil during day, coming up to feed at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasonal history&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest is a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Migration&#34;&gt;migratory&lt;/a&gt; species, with no seasonal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;. The duration of each generation is one-two months, depending on environmental conditions. In Israel the pest has 4-5 generations, of which those with most potential to cause damage are during autumn (November-December) and spring (February-March). Early autumn rains (e.g. high humidity) and mild temperatures are conducive to population increase. The autumn population in Israel is presumably bolstered by migrant adults. Infestations in Syria are higher in years with high rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The occasional appearance of black cutworm populations poses a logistic
problem for preventive measures, especially as the larvae reside in the soil,
making detection difficult until damage had revealed their existence. Control
measures are difficult because of the inaccessible location of the larvae to
some forms of chemical applications. One preventive measure is sanitation, the
removal of weeds and volunteer plants from previously-damaged fields and their
surroundings, and deep ploughing if populations recur. Adults on the wing can
be monitored by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; trapping. First damage may usually
be expected about 2 weeks after peak flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Spray applications may be directed towards first instar &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; while they are still feeding on the underside of foliage, or else granular insecticides can be applied onto the soil. Moistened poison bait may be mixed with the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; trichlofon and parathion, or the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamate&lt;/a&gt; carbaryl, and broadcast in the field at 10 kg/ha, preferably in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural enemies&lt;/strong&gt;: Natural enemies are not reliable for black cutworm control, mostly due to the sporadic appearance of the pest and the inability of seedlings to compensate for any incurred damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hill, D.S. 1983. &lt;em&gt;Agrotis ipsilon&lt;/em&gt; (Hfn.). In: &lt;em&gt;Agricultural Insect Pests of
the Tropics and Their Control&lt;/em&gt;, 2nd Edition, pp. 357-358. Cambridge University
Press, Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rings, R.W., Arnold, F.J. and Johnson, B.A. 1975. Host range of the black
cutworm on vegetables: A bibliography. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Entomological Society
of America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;:229-234.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/agrotis.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/agrotis.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/AgrotIpsil.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/AgrotIpsil.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis chilensis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chilensis</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chilensis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; Howard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cosmopolitan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: An important parasitoid of the oleander scale, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aspidiotus_Nerii&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aspidiotus nerii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bouche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is yellow, its size being from 0.5 to 1.1 mm; smaller specimens are paler, bear less setae and were even described as a separate species (&lt;em&gt;Aphytis riadi&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale prepupae are attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; onto the host&amp;rsquo;s body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;figures/AphytisAspidiotus-Fig1.html&amp;quot;, 500, 300,&#34;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that at molting the shields of these insects adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;). The pupa is free, and its eyes change from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath. Although reared (in the field and in the laboratory) from several hosts, it seems to prefer the oleander scale. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; (but males have been described), requiring ca 18 days to complete a generation at 28°C and each female produces about 25 offspring. In the field the parasitoid has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn. It attacks mainly young host females and is a voracious &lt;a href=&#34;entry/HostFeeding&#34;&gt;host feeder&lt;/a&gt;, killing more scales by this practice than by parasitization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water extract of the shield of the oleander scale elicited a positive response
from &lt;em&gt;A. chilensis&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting that its host-searching is based on chemical
cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandrakis, V. and Neuenschwander, P. 1980. Le role d&amp;rsquo;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt;
(Hym.: Aphelinidae), parasite d&amp;rsquo;&lt;em&gt;Aspidiotus nerii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom.: Diaspididae) sur
olivier en Crete. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;:  61-71.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis riadi&lt;/em&gt; - a synonym of &lt;em&gt;A. chilensis&lt;/em&gt; (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae). &lt;em&gt;Annals of the Entomological Society of America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;60:&lt;/strong&gt;
1116-1118.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lo Pinto, M., Lo Bue, P., Peri, E. Agrò, A., Liotta, G. and Colazza, S.
2002.  Responses of  2003.  &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chilensis&lt;/em&gt; to the synthetic sex pheromone of
the oleander scale. &lt;em&gt;IOBC/WPRS Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;():&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck, R.F. and Uygun, N. 1986. Host recognition and selection by &lt;em&gt;Aphytis&lt;/em&gt;
species: response to California red, oleander and cactus scale cover extracts.
&lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt;: 129-136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae).&lt;/em&gt; Israel Universities Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis chrysomphali</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chrysomphali</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphytis_chrysomphali</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Mercet)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Probably a native of the Mediterranean basin; its distribution is now almost cosmopolitan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;: Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially California red scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Aonidiella_Aurantii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Maskell).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A member of a guild of parasitoids that attack the California red scale. In Israel and Cyprus &lt;em&gt;A. chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; occurs only along the coastal plain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size is from 0.6 to 1.0 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;A. chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt;, young females and scale &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prepupa&#34;&gt;prepupae&lt;/a&gt; are attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the ectoparasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the host&amp;rsquo;s shield, or by crawling out from underneath. Although obtained from several armored scale hosts, it is best known as a parasitoid of the California red scale. &lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; species (with rare males) and a voracious &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Host_Feeding&#34;&gt;host feeder&lt;/a&gt;, killing more scales by this practice than by parasitization. It completes a cycle in a fortnight at 25°C, at which temperature each female produces about 25 offspring. It appears to be tolerant to low temperatures but susceptible to heat and aridity, attributes that could explain its prevalence along the coastal plain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanides, G.M. 1996. Establishment of &lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt; (Hym:
Encyrtidae) on &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom: Diaspididae) in Cyprus.
&lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;: 53-57.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of &lt;em&gt;Aphytis&lt;/em&gt; of the World
(Hymenoptera: Aphelinidae).&lt;/em&gt; Israel Universities Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphytis hispanicus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enemy/aphytis_hispanicus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt; Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mediterranean Basin, Central America, Texas, California, Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt;:  Several armored scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;), especially chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_pergandii&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Comstock&lt;/code&gt; and tropical grey chaff scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Parlatoria_cinerea&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria cinerea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hadden&lt;/code&gt;. In the laboratory the parasitoid can be reared on the latania scale, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Hemiberlesia_lataniae&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hemiberlesia lataniae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Signoret)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A parasitoid of chaff scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The female is yellow, its size being from 0.6 to 1.0 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Like other members of its genus, &lt;em&gt;Aphytis hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; of armored scale insects. The 2nd-stage nymphs, young females and scale prepupae are sometimes attacked, but the ovipositing females are the preferred stage for parasitization. The eggs are deposited through the shield on the host&amp;rsquo;s body; due to the fact that when molting the shields of these scales adhere to their bodies, the parasitoid can deposit only between molts. Its emerging larvae feed on the scales and prior to pupation they excrete their fecal matter in the shape of black pellets (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Meconia&#34;&gt;meconia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). The pupa is free, its eyes changing from colorless to red to green, providing an indication of its age. The adult often emerges through an exit hole in the shield, or by crawling out from underneath.  &lt;em&gt;A. hispanicus&lt;/em&gt; is a uniparental &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt; species, requiring about a fortnight to complete a generation at 28°C, each female producing about 24 offspring. In the field this solitary parasitoid has two population peaks, in spring and in autumn, being rare during summer and winter. It attacks its chaff scale hosts mostly on the leaves, less on the fruit and very seldom on the wooden parts of the trees, and does not feed on its hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1967. The natural enemies of the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria
pergandii&lt;/em&gt; Comstock, in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 12: 97-109.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U. 1968. The comparative biologies of two hymenopterous parasites of
the chaff scale, &lt;em&gt;Parlatoria pergandii.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; 13: 163-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosen, D. and DeBach, P. 1978. &lt;em&gt;Species of Aphytis of the World (Hymenoptera:
Aphelinidae)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Israel Universities Press&lt;/em&gt;, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
  
**Websites**: 

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

--&gt;

&lt;!--


**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oncastichus goughi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/oncastichus_goughi</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/oncastichus_goughi</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oncastichus goughi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Headrick and Lasalle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Hymenoptera&lt;/a&gt;, Apocryta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Chalcidoidea&#34;&gt;Chalcidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Geraldton wax wasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Australia, California and in Israel since the 1990’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: The cut-flower crop &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult wasps are black, about 1-2 mm in length&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A major pest of Geraldton wax, &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae) (wax flower). It induces &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Gall&#34;&gt;galls&lt;/a&gt; and plant deformations, rendering the cut-flower crop as well as the foliage unmarketable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The eggs are placed within the host plant and the larvae develop in young leaves and stems, inducing the formation of galls and other deformations. Pupation takes place within the gall, the adult bores a round hole through which it emerges. Catches in traps suggest that the pest raises two annual, overlapping generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Green and yellow sticky traps can be used to monitor the occurrence of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: The early cultivars of &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; that bear smaller leaves are less susceptible to the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectin&#34;&gt;Avermectins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Imidacloprid&#34;&gt;imidacloprids&lt;/a&gt;, applied as &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;systemics&lt;/a&gt; greatly reduce the pest’s damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben-David, Z., Ofer, Y., Kedar, J., Schachner, T and Zaidan, M. 1997. Control
of the gall wasp &lt;em&gt;Oncastichus goughi&lt;/em&gt;, a new pest of wax flowers. &lt;em&gt;Avivon&lt;/em&gt; 32: 14-16 (in Hebrew).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben-Yakir, D., Gokkes, M., Eitan, S., Klein, Z., Kuzlitzki, W., Ben-David, Z.,
Lavi, A. and Chen, M. 1997. Biology and control of a gall-forming wasp, a new
pest of Geraldton wax plant in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 25: 145-146.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headrick, D.H., LaSalle, J. and Redak, R.A. 1995. A new genus of Australian
Tetrastichinae (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) an introduced pest of &lt;em&gt;Chamelaucium
uncinatum&lt;/em&gt; (Myrtaceae) in California. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Natural History&lt;/em&gt; 29:
1029-1036.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redak R.A. and Bethke, J.A. 1995. Detection and seasonal occurrence of gall-
forming wasps (Hymenoptera, Eulophidae) on Geraldton wax plant. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 88: 387-392.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllocnistis citrella</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/phyllocnistis_citrella</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/phyllocnistis_citrella</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis citrella&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Stainton&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Gracillaridae&#34;&gt;Gracillariidae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Citrus leafminer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The origin of this pest is in Southeast Asia. Now it occurs wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; is grown; in the Middle East since 1994.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Mainly plants of the family Rutaceae. Within that family, it is most often found on various species and varieties of citrus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms&lt;/strong&gt;: The mining of the larvae within young citrus leaves distorts them and destroys the epidermis (Figure 1),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/PhyllocnistisCitrella-leaves-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1:Citrus leaves mined by the citrus&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and thus the leaf&amp;rsquo;s photosynthetic capability. Mature leaves are not attacked. Mining within the fruit&amp;rsquo;s peel, although uncommon (except for pummeloes), causes direct damage (Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/PhyllocnistisCitrella-fruit-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 2: A grapefruit damaged by the citrus leaf miner&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A major pest of citrus throughout its distribution. The main damage is to seedlings in nurseries, young trees (1-3 years old) and to the young growth after grafting. Fruit-bearing trees are seldom damaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult is about 2-3 mm long, silvery-white with black spots, and four dark stripes on each &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Forewings&#34;&gt;forewing&lt;/a&gt;. The larvae are light-green in color, almost transparent, up to 3 mm in length (Figure3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/PhyllocnistisCitrella.Fig3-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;fig70p&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 3: The larva of _Phyllocnistis citrella_. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Each female deposits about 50-130 eggs, placing them on the very young leaves and the youngest twigs. The emerging &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; enter the leaves and burrow therein, forming uneven mines (Figure 1), where pupation takes place. The larvae have 4 instars: the 1st to 3rd &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Instar&#34;&gt;instar&lt;/a&gt; larvae feed, whereas the 4th instar is spinning larva that does not feed. The pest may raise a generation in a fortnight at 25°C and long day conditions, thus completing several generations in a year. It has no &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phenology&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to its specificity for citrus and preference for young leaves as oviposition sites, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phenology&#34;&gt;phenology&lt;/a&gt; of the pest is determined by the host&amp;rsquo;s growth or flashing cycles. The first and main flash, in the spring, is rarely affected in Israel. This is due to the low winter temperatures and/or because of natural enemy activity in the former year. The mid-summer and late summer flashes, which in any case are usually smaller, may be more damaged by the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crop resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: No species or varieties of citrus are clearly resistant to the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: As soon as the pest is first noted on young trees (1-3 years old) in the spring, they should be treated. This may include a spray with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt; and a concurrent soil treatment with the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemics&#34;&gt;systemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Imidacloprid&#34;&gt;imidacloprid&lt;/a&gt;). An alternative is to brush the systemic &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acetamiprid&#34;&gt;acetamiprid&lt;/a&gt; on the trunks; the precise method is dependent on tree age and trunk diameter. Confidor and Mospilan can also be applied to control infestations that occur during later growth flashes. Fruit-bearing trees do not need to be treated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: No indigenous natural
enemies seem to have any effect on the pest. Three imported
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parasite&#34;&gt;parasitoids&lt;/a&gt;
usually control the citrus leafminer in Israel: &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Citrostichus_phyllocnistoides&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Citrostichus
phyllocnistoides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Narayan), &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Semielacher_petiolatus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Semielacher
petiolatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Girault) and &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Cirrospilus_ingenuus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cirrospilus
ingenuus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gahan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argov, Y. &amp;amp; Rossler, Y. 1996. Introduction, release and recovery of several
exotic natural enemies for biological control of the citrus leafminer,
&lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis citrella&lt;/em&gt;, in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;: 33-38. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argov Y. &amp;amp; Rossler Y., 1998. Rearing methods for the citrus leafminer
&lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis citrella&lt;/em&gt; Stainton and its parasitoids in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Biological
Control&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;: 18-21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heppner, J. B. 1993. Citrus leafminer, &lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis citrella&lt;/em&gt;, in Florida
(Lepidoptera: Gracillariidae: Phyllocnistinae). &lt;em&gt;Tropical Lepidoptera&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;:
49-64. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knapp, J.L., Albrigo, L.G., Browning, H.W., Bullock, R.C., Heppner, J.B.,
Hall, D. G., Hoy, M.A., Nguyen, R., Peña J.E. &amp;amp; Stansly, P.A.. 1995. Citrus
leafminer, &lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis citrella&lt;/em&gt; Stainton: Current status in Florida -
1995. &lt;em&gt;Florida Cooperative Extension Service, Institute of Food and
Agricultural Sciences, University of Florida&lt;/em&gt;, Gainesville, 35 pp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ujiye, T. 2000. Biology and control of the citrus leafminer, &lt;em&gt;Phyllocnistis
citrella&lt;/em&gt; Stainton (Lepidoptera: Gracillariidae) in Japan. &lt;em&gt;Japan Agricultural
Research Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt;: 167-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;strong&gt;Yael Argov&lt;/strong&gt; E-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:yael@jaffa.co.il&#34;&gt;yael@jaffa.co.il&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Israel Cohen Institute for Biological Control; Citrus Marketing Board of
Israel, P.O. Box 80, 50250 Bet Dagan, Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creatures.ifas.ufl.edu/citrus/citrus_leafminer.htm&#34;&gt;http://creatures.ifas.ufl.edu/citrus/citrus_leafminer.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doacs.state.fl.us/pi/enpp/ento/clm-page.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.doacs.state.fl.us/pi/enpp/ento/clm-page.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thaumetopoea pityocampa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_pityocampa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_pityocampa</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;(Denis &amp;amp; Schiffermüller)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thaumetopoeidae&#34;&gt;Thaumetopoeidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Winter pine processionary moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The western Mediterranean region, reaching south-western Turkey in the Middle East, colonizing over 1,500,000 ha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past the vicariants  &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; and   &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt; were often confused. A
molecular study recently revealed  differences between the two species, which
became separated before the Quaternary ice ages.  Commonwealth Institute of
Entomology Map #366, 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Feeding of the pest is restricted to pines, such as &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;inus&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;nigra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;P. brutia&lt;/em&gt;,  &lt;em&gt;P. sylvestris&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;em&gt;P. pinea&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;P. halepensis&lt;/em&gt; and to &lt;em&gt;Cedrus&lt;/em&gt; spp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the needles which then drop; saplings may be entirely defoliated, causing tree dieback and even death.  Fourth- and fifth-instar larvae consume all the needles of pine trees, so that they to have been burned. The average decrease in annual diameter increment for Calabrian trees in damaged areas, compared with healthy trees, can reach about 22%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The larvae are armed with stinging setae that break off easily and release a
protein, thaumetopoein, which causes inflammations of eyes and of the
respiratory system in humans and domestic animals, as well as allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moth is a relatively new pest in Turkey, whose emergence has been
attributed to the intense cultivation of conifers for afforestation of
degraded soils and as ornamentals, and the recent expansion of the pest to
upper elevations and latitudes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The greyish adults bear transverse dark stripes and their heads are decorated with dense hairs. The young larvae are brown-yellow, becoming darker with each molt. All larvae bear red-brown tubercles with yellow-white detachable setae with hooked tips. The average weight of mature larvae is almost 0.80 g, and their average length 30 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Univoltine&#34;&gt;univoltine&lt;/a&gt;. Adults emerge and fly in August, laying eggs in September; the larvae hatch by the end of that month and the next (October). They form processions as they crawl along pine branches to find feeding sites and then rest in nests; an average nest holding about 210 larvae. They pass through five &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Instar&#34;&gt;instars&lt;/a&gt;, pupating in the soil during May, June and July. Pine &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Secondary_plant_constituents&#34;&gt;secondary plant constituents&lt;/a&gt; seem to determine the pest&amp;rsquo;s host selection processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphates&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; were formerly applied
against the pest. Steam-distilled wood sulfate turpentine was the best of
several essential plant oils tried in Turkey to control the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparations of  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Bacillus_thuringiensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Bt) may control the pest but two applications are required for
satisfactory control. This is the result of the prolonged, month-long
emergence of the vulnerable young larval instars, whose late members avoid the
treatment, which does not persist that long on the needles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: In Turkey the pest is attacked by several natural enemies, the more common being the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; egg parasitoids &lt;em&gt;Ooencyrtus pityocampae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Eutetrastichus&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Baryscapus&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;em&gt;servadeii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Dom.)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;). The former parasitized eggs placed near the top of the batches, whereas the latter was found mainly in eggs near the base of the batches. All egg parasitoids together reduced hatching rate to 50.7-65.6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battisti, A., Longo, S., Tiberi, R. and Triggiani, O. 1998. Results and
perspectives in the use of &lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt; Berl. var. &lt;em&gt;kurstaki&lt;/em&gt; and
other pathogens against &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. et Schiff.)&lt;/code&gt; in Italy
(Lep., Thaumetopoeidae). &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger für Schädlingskunde, Pflanzenschutz,
Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt;, 71, 72-76.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devkota, B. and Schmidt, G. H., 1990: Larval development of &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. &amp;amp; Schiff)&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) from Greece as influenced
by different host plants under laboratory conditions. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 109: 321-330.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanat, M., Sivrikaya, F. and Serez, M. 2002. A research on the effects of pine
processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Schiff&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;em&gt;Pinus brutia&lt;/em&gt; Ten
trees and tending activities on the diameter increment of calabrian pine in
Kahramanmaras. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on the Pine Processionary Moth&lt;/em&gt;, Kahramanmaras,
Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanat, M. and Alma, M.H. 2004. [ Insecticidal effects of essential oils from
various plants. against larvae of pine processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Schiff&lt;/code&gt;) (Lepidoptera : Thaumetopoeidae)]
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14971685&#34;&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14971685&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;em&gt;Pest Management Science&lt;/em&gt; 60: 173-177.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirchev, P., Schmidt, G. H., Tsankov, G. and Avci M. 2004. Egg parasitoids of
&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. &amp;amp; Schiff.)&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) and their
impact in SW Turkey. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 128: 533-542.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvato, P.; Battisti, A.; Concato, S.; Masutti, L.; Partanello, T. and Zane,
L., 2002. Genetic differentiation in the winter pine processionary moth
(&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa-wilkinsoni _complex), inferred by AFLP and
mitochondrial DNA markers&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Molecular Ecology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 2435-2444.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Türkmen, H. and Y. Ali Öner[ Y. ]
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.1398-9995.2003.00369.x&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.1398-9995.2003.00369.x&lt;/a&gt;
2004. A human dermatitis
caused by _ Thaumetopoea pityocampa_ (Denis and Schiffermüller, 1775) (order:
Lepidoptera) caterpillars in Istanbul, Turkey. &lt;em&gt;Allergy&lt;/em&gt; 59: 232-233.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--- 
aj13989995200300369x ---&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Zhang, Q.-H., Schlyter, F., Battisti, A., Birgersson, G. and Anderson, P.
2003. Electrophysiological responses of &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; females to
host volatiles: implications for host selection of active and inactive
terpenes. &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger für Schädlingskunde Pflanzenschutz, Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt;, 76:
103-107.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ThaumPityoc.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ThaumPityoc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thaumetopoeidae&#34;&gt; Thaumetopoeidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Cyprus processionary caterpillar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cyprus, Israel, Jordan and Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vicariants &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Denis and Schiffermüller)&lt;/code&gt; were often confused in the past.
However, a recent molecular study showed clear differences between the two
species, which became separated before the Quaternary ice ages. &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; is restricted to the Middle East, whereas &lt;em&gt;T.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;pityocampa&lt;/em&gt;
is a more western species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Feeding of the pest is restricted to pines (&lt;em&gt;Pinus&lt;/em&gt; spp.). In the Middle East young &lt;em&gt;P. eldarica&lt;/em&gt; trees are preferred to &lt;em&gt;P. brutia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;P. halepensis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the needles, which causes their shedding; saplings may entirely be defoliated, causing die back and even (in dry years) tree death. Larger trees may recover, although totally defoliated branches can still be seen. The external parts of the trees, especially young ones, are usually preferred. The larvae are armed with stinging setae that easily break off and release a protein, thaumetopoein, which causes inflammations of eyes and of the respiratory system in humans and domestic animals, as well as allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large-scale reforestation programs with pines undertaken in Cyprus and Israel
have increased the importance of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The brownish adults, whose length is 17-22 mm, bear transverse dark stripes and their bodies are decorated with dense hairs. The young larvae are brown-yellow, becoming darker with each molt. At maturity they are almost black and attain a size of 40 mm. All larvae bear tubercles with yellow-white detachable setae with hooked tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Univoltine&#34;&gt;univoltine&lt;/a&gt;. Adults emerge in the autumn and lay their eggs in early winter. Each female lays many eggs, arranging them in rows around pine needles and covering them with reddish scales. The larvae emerge after 6-7 weeks and immediately form processions that march off to seek food. The young larvae feed only on the needles&amp;rsquo; epidermis, but later stages consume entire needles. After a few days of feeding the larvae form a temporary communal nest, moving to another site as they crawl on to look for fresh needles. Larval development lasts 4-6 months, pupation taking place in the soil and takes about 5 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Mass &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mass_trapping&#34;&gt;male trapping&lt;/a&gt; is feasible with the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; pityolure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Stem injections with an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt; bring about 100% mortality, as do implants of similar pesticides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Various stages of the pest are attacked by several natural enemies, the more common being the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; egg parasitoids &lt;em&gt;Ooencyrtus pityocampae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Eutetrastichus servadeii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Dom.)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;). Their overall effect on the pest appears to be  negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halperin, J. 1985. Detection and control of the pine processionary
caterpillar, &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; , with pityolure.  &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt;
13: 148-149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halperin, J. 1986. Acephate implants for control of the pine processionary
caterpillar. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 14: 97-100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitt, J. and Schmidt, G. H., 1993: Parasitism of egg-batches of the pine
processionary moth &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) in the
mountains of Lahav (Israel). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 115, 484-498.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mendel, Z. 1988. Host selection by the pine processionary caterpillar,
 &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 16: 101-108.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mendel, Z. 1990. On the origin of the pine processionary caterpillar,
&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 109: 311-314.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvato, P., Battisti, A., Concato, S., Masutti, L., Partanello, T. and Zane, L., 2002: Genetic differentiation in the winter pine processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa-wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; complex), inferred by AFLP and mitochondrial DNA markers. &lt;em&gt;Molecular Ecology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 2435-2444.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeuzera pyrina</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cossidae&#34;&gt;Cossidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Leopard moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Europe, North and South Africa, Japan, North America, Mediterranean region. Distribution Maps of Plant Pests, No. 314, Commonwealth Institute of Entomology. 1973.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Polyphagous, preferring soft-wood trees, in the Middle East occurring mostly on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apple&#34;&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Olive&#34;&gt;olive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pear&#34;&gt;pear&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Plum&#34;&gt;plum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pomegranate&#34;&gt;pomegranate&lt;/a&gt; and about 150 other tree species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A single young &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larva&lt;/a&gt; may cause the death of thin branches, by withering or breaking. Although olives are less susceptible, the tendency of the moth to remain on the same hosts results in several pest generations developing there, causing considerable damage to the trees, which become weakened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult moth is whitish and covered by numerous dark-bluish spots when developing within apple trees, whereas those from olives have pinkish wings with greenish dotes. The body is darkish with white hairs. At rest the wings are folded along the body, which is 25-30 mm long. The males are smaller (20 mm long). The larva is dark-yellow with black dorsal tubercles, About 50-55 mm long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The moths occur in the orchards from May to November, dependent upon temperatures, host plant and plant protection practices. A female lives about one week, depositing 100-300 eggs on the bark, mostly on the tree from which it had emerged, or nearby. The emerging larvae bore into young twigs, often at the leaf bases, bringing about the withering on a leaf growing underneath. The larvae then move into elder, thicker branches wherein it continues to borrow into the wood, pushing out its brownish &lt;a href=&#34;glossary/Frass&#34;&gt;frass&lt;/a&gt; and completing its development there. The pattern of the excavated tunnels differs between trees. In hosts like deciduous fruit trees, the tunnels are straight, whereas in other trees, like olives, the tunnels may be circular or sinuous. Prior to pupation the mature larva bores an emergence hole near the original point of ingress, and seals it by a thin membrane. The young adults break through and emerge. The pest completes a single annual generation in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Light_trap&#34;&gt;Light traps&lt;/a&gt; have been used in the past, but were supplemented by male &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mating_disruption&#34;&gt;mating disruption&lt;/a&gt; traps, placed during   spring on the trees, to serve as an early warning system. Another method is to   observe the occurrence of “flag leaves”, the withering leaves at the bases of      thin branches infested by the young larvae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural contro&lt;/strong&gt;: In the past thin wires   were inserted through the frass into the burrows, or pesticides were thus   introduced. These are time consuming methods and probably suitable only in   instances of low infestations. More recently  by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; threads (650 per hectare) is being used, as it controls the pest on olives during most of the season,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; are used when necessary, but may only be applied against the exposed adults, and cannot be used during harvest. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/insect_growth_regulators&#34;&gt;IGRs&lt;/a&gt; have also been successfully applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The parasitic &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Elachertus nigritulus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Zetterstedt&lt;/code&gt;, (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae)&lt;/a&gt; has been mass reared from leopard moth larvae, but its effect on the pest’s damage is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abed El-Hadi, Birger, R., Hanoch, E., Vardi, Y., Sarid, D. and Zemer, B. 2005.
Control of &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; in olives by using pheromone male confusing. &lt;em&gt;Alon
Ha’notea&lt;/em&gt; 59: 383-385 (in Hebrew)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, Z. and Harpaz, I. 1969. &lt;em&gt;Plant Pests of Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Israel Universities
Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismail, I.I., Abouzeid, N.A. and Abdallah, F.F. 1992. Population dynamics of
the leopard moth, &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt;, and its control on olive trees in
Egypt. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Pflanzenkrankheiten und Pfanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; 99:
519-524.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: **

** [ Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>