<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Oedipodinae on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/oedipodinae/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locusta migratoria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/locusta_migratoria</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/locusta_migratoria</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy: Insecta, Hemimetabola, Orthoptera, Acridoidea, Acrididae, Oedipodinae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Migratory locust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Click on image to enlarge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt;  The distribution of &lt;em&gt;L. migratoria&lt;/em&gt; encompasses practically the whole of the temperate and tropical parts of the Eastern Hemisphere, from the Canaries and the Azores in the West to Japan and New Zealand in the East. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants:&lt;/strong&gt; The migratory locust prefers gramineous plants, but may feed on a large variety of rangeland flora in its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Primary_breeding_sites&#34;&gt;primary breeding sites&lt;/a&gt;, or on economic crops, when present in the environment. Leguminous plants are less compatible nutritionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance:&lt;/strong&gt; At low population densities, the migratory locust is a minor pest. Although permanently solitariform in the eastern Mediterranean, the behavior of occasional crowded populations is reminiscent of its gregariform subspecies, the African migratory locust, &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria migratorioides&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Reiche &amp;amp; Fairmaire)&lt;/code&gt;, with which it can readily hybridize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology:&lt;/strong&gt; The Egyptian tree locust is a large grasshopper. At rest, the adult female body, including the folded, is up to 90 mm in length, while the male measures up to 65 mm. The mottled tegmina project beyond the end of the abdomen. Adults are grey-brown in color. The hind wings are transparent and have a purplish cast, and a curved band of darker aspect runs diagonally across them. A dull yellow line runs dorsally along the crest of the pronotum. The hind tibial spines are basally pale and apically dark-tipped. The juveniles are greenish.
 Within this species in its broad distribution, solitariform adults are characterized by a concave pronotum. Their background coloration is cryptic, being green or brown, dependent on levels of ambient humidity. Gregariform adults are much darker. Isolated males are substantially larger than females whereas crowded males are about the same size as the females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; Within their vast geographic range the populations of the migratory locust exhibit morphological and biological diversity, and the existence of nine subspecies is nowadays accepted; some are economic pests. Populations of L. migratoria that are endemic to temperate climates (some classified as subspecies), undergo embryonic diapause, thus establishing 1-2 annual generations. However, this does not occur in the subtropical Middle East. A non-swarming subspecies, &lt;em&gt;L. m. cinerascens&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Fabricius)&lt;/code&gt;, exists in some of the other countries surrounding the Mediterranean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule, the migration of L. migratoria is more limited than that of the desert locust, Schistocerca gregaria (Forskal). Isolated migratory locusts fly at night, whereas crowded adults fly mainly by day. Isolated locusts have 1-2 more larval instars than individuals in crowded populations, but this does not prolong their development, which is more rapid than when crowded. In consequence locusts in crowded populations establish fewer generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selection favoring non-migratory behavior may occur in localities where emigration is detrimental to survival. Evolution of distinct populations and subspecies with pronounced solitarious phase characteristics would have been favored in such cases. The more isolated and smaller the population and its geographical distribution, the more likely it is to possess unique morphometrics. In Israel, when first recorded in the Jezreel Valley (which is contiguous with the Jordan Valley), L. migratoria was originally described as L. danica, but later determined to be the solitariform of L. migratoria. Its primary breeding sites on the shores of the Sea of Gallilee have since become degraded due to development projects. Some breeding sites may still exist in the Sudano-Deccanian enclave surrounding the Dead Sea. The Jordan Valley, contiguous with the Arava Valley, was originally part of the African Rift Valley and the Israeli population is possibly a relict form of the African migratory locust. The Israeli population of L. migratory does not undergo an overt gregarization, and is permanently solitariform in appearance. This does not mean that crowded populations do not behave like typical gregarious locusts, but only that morphometrically, differences between the two phases is slight. Finally, the Israeli migratory locust population is superficially similar to another population that is established in irrigated localities in central Arabia. Migration along the Arava Valley could connect these two populations but this has not been examined. Solitariform L. migratoria may occur in low numbers on field crops and grasses during summer and autumn in Israel, and disappear in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Other than on the rare occasions when population of the migratory locust increases substantially, the solitariform grasshopper does not require special control measures. In its areas of abundance, environmentally compatible control agents, such as the entomopathogenic fungus Metarhizium anisopliae applied in an oil-based formulation, have been tested. IGRs, inhibitors of chitin synthesis, such as Dimilin, prevent normal molting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heifetz, Y., Applebaum, S.W., and Popov, G.B. 1994. Phase characteristics of the Israeli population of the migratory locust, &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt; (Orthoptera: Acrididae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Orthoptera Research&lt;/em&gt; 2: 15-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El-Minshawy, A.M., El-Hinnawy, N.H. et al. 1975. Population fluctuations of grasshoppers and locusts in Alexandria area (Egypt) &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Entomological Society of Egypt&lt;/em&gt; 59: 83-98.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanyang, S. and van Emden, H.F. 1996. The combined effects of the fungus Metarhizium flavoviride Gams &amp;amp; Rozsypal and the insecticide cypermethrin on &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria migratorioides&lt;/em&gt; (Reiche &amp;amp; Fairmaire) in the laboratory. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Pest Management&lt;/em&gt; 42: 183-187.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&#34;&gt;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>