<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>P on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/topics/p/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pheromone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/pheromone</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/pheromone</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pheromone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt; None&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chemical signals produced and emitted by living organisms and involved in
intraspecific communication. They are usually composed of blends of
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Allelochemical&#34;&gt;allelochemicals&lt;/a&gt;; some may be sequestered from
host plants, others are derivatives of plant components and yet others are
produced &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt; in the pheromone gland of the organism. The repertoire of
responses elicited by pheromones is very extensive. For example, sex
pheromones are produced by individuals of one sex (in most cases the females)
and influence the seeking and mating behavior of the opposite sex. They are
exploited in plant protection in the context of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/IPM&#34;&gt;IPM&lt;/a&gt;.
Aggregation pheromones attract both sexes. Pheromones may mark trails or
oviposition sites, serve for kin recognition and elicit defensive maneuvers or
aggressive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed treatment of pheromones, see the website listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nysaes.cornell.edu/fst/faculty/acree/pheronet/pherom.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nysaes.cornell.edu/fst/faculty/acree/pheronet/pherom.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-pherolist.slu.se/pherolist.php?command=pherolist&amp;amp;file=family&#34;&gt;http://www-pherolist.slu.se/pherolist.php?command=pherolist&amp;amp;file=family&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytoplasma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/phytoplasma</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/phytoplasma</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phytoplasma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the previous century pathogens causing “yellows” diseases
were variously known as viruses, mycoplasma-like organisms (MLOs) and finally
phytoplasmas. They have not yet been cultured in artificial media, which has
greatly hindered research. However, they have been identified by several
means, including antibodies, DNA probes and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polymerase_chain_reaction&#34;&gt;polymerase chain
reaction&lt;/a&gt; (PCR) primers. A proposed
classification scheme distinguishes phytoplasma clades at the level of genera,
and subclades as species. Of the 14  phytoplasma groups, a number have been
named in the genus &lt;em&gt;Candidatus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The symptoms of “yellows” diseases vary, depending on the host plant. Plant
growth may be stunted or dwarfed, due to reduced shoot growth and lack of
apical dominance. Leaves tend to be yellow, although they may also turn
reddish, are smaller than normal, and often curl inwards.
There may also be a proliferation of leaves known as
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Witches_broom&#34;&gt;witches’ broom&lt;/a&gt;,
or production of “asparagus fern” branching. Symptoms often appear to be
hormonally induced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While phytoplasmas can be transmitted by cuttings, grafting, and parasitic
plants such as dodder (&lt;em&gt;Cuscuta pentagona&lt;/em&gt;), they are primarily spread by
insects, mainly &lt;a href=&#34;Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;. Leafhoppers
(&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cicadelloidea&#34;&gt;Cicadelloidea&lt;/a&gt;) and planthoppers
(&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Fulgoroidea&#34;&gt;Fulgoroidea&lt;/a&gt;) are the predominant transmitters
of phytoplasmas, although &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Psyllidae&#34;&gt;Psyllidae&lt;/a&gt; and a member
of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Flatidae&#34;&gt;Flatidae&lt;/a&gt; are also known vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several traits combine to make these &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;hemimetabolous&lt;/a&gt;
insects efficient vectors of phytoplasmas. Their nymphs and adults feed on the
same hosts and inhabit the same physical location, thus facilitate
transmission by juveniles as well adults. They feed selectively on the tissues
wherein phytoplasmas reside, namely &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phloem&#34;&gt;phloem&lt;/a&gt; sieve
elements. The insects’ feeding is non-destructive, promoting successful
inoculation of the vascular system, without damaging the plant. Finally, the
phytoplasmas replicate in the insect hosts and persist therein, and can
therefore be transmitted for days, weeks or months after the initial
acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transmission cycle of phytoplasmas can be divided into two phases. 1. The
acquisition time or the acquisition access period (AAP), the length of time an
insect must feed on the plant in order to acquire the phytoplasma. Most
insects require more than 24 hours for maximum acquisition and subsequent
transmission of the pathogen. This period is age dependent
(&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt; versus adults) and has to be established for
each individual species. 2. The latent period (LP), the time required by the
phytoplasma to penetrate the gut wall, migrate to the salivary glands,
replicate and become transmissible. This period is temperature dependent. At
optimal temperatures it can be as short as 10-20 days, whereas at low
temperatures 50-60 days may be required. At high temperatures (relative to the
particular phytoplasma, usually above 30°C), phytoplasmas are inactivated
within the insect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships between vector and phytoplasmas are highly complex. Vectors can
have dual infections; they may harbor a phytoplasma but be unable to vector it
to healthy plants; or they may be unable to acquire a given phytoplasma from
one plant species, but obtain it from another plant.
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;Polyphagous&lt;/a&gt; vectors, such as &lt;em&gt;Macrosteles
fascifrons&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Stål)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cicadellidae&#34;&gt;Cicadellidae&lt;/a&gt;), are
capable to infecting a range of plants with a number of phytoplasmas, whereas
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Monophagous&#34;&gt;monophagous&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Oligophagous&#34;&gt;oligophagous&lt;/a&gt; vectors, such as &lt;em&gt;Scaphoideus
luteolus&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;DeLong&lt;/code&gt;  (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cicadellidae&#34;&gt;Cicadellidae&lt;/a&gt;),  can transmit phytoplasmas only to a few
plant species, primarily &lt;em&gt;Ulmus&lt;/em&gt; spp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doi, Y.M., Teranaka, M., Yora, K. and Asuyana, H. 1967. Mycoplasma or PLT-
group- like microorganisms found in the phloem elements of plants infected
with mulberry dwarf, potato witches&amp;rsquo; broom, aster yellows, or paulownia
witches&amp;rsquo; broom. &lt;em&gt;Annals of the Phytopathological Society of Japan&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt;:
259-266.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lee, I.-M. Gundersen-Rindal, D.E., Davis, R.E., and Bartoszyk, I. M. 1998.
Revised classification scheme of phytoplasmas based on RFLP annalyses of 16S
RNA and ribosomal protein gene sequences. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Systematic
Bacteriology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;48&lt;/strong&gt;: 1153-1169.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granados, R.R. and Chapman, R.K. 1968. Heat inactivation and interactions of
four aster yellows virus strains in their vector, &lt;em&gt;Macrosteles fascifrons&lt;/em&gt;
(Stal).&lt;em&gt;Virology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt;: 333-342.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gundersen, D.E., Lee, I.M., Rehner, S.A., Davis, R.E. and Kingsbury, D.T.
1994. Phylogeny of mycoplasmalike organisms (phytoplasmas): a basis for their
classification. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Bacteriology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;176&lt;/strong&gt;: 5244-5254.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weintraub, P.G. and Beanland, L. 2006. Insect vectors of phytoplasmas. &lt;em&gt;Annual
Review of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;51&lt;/strong&gt;: 91-111&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phytoplasma-vector.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.phytoplasma-vector.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oardc.ohio-state.edu/phytoplasma/insect.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.oardc.ohio-state.edu/phytoplasma/insect.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Phyllis G. Weintraub&lt;/strong&gt;, e-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:phyllisw@volcani.agri.gov.il&#34;&gt;phyllisw@volcani.agri.gov.il&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gilat Research Center D.N. Negev, 85280, Israel
Telephone: 08 992-6-8678; Fax: 08 992-6485&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytoseiidae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/phytoseiidae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/phytoseiidae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parasitiformes&#34;&gt;Parasitiformes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mesostigmata&#34;&gt;Mesostigmata&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: World-wide, with more than 1,700 described species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: This family contains several important natural enemies of plant pests, especially spider mites (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;), false spider mites (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tenuipalpidaee&#34;&gt;Tenuipalpidae&lt;/a&gt;), rust and gall mites (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;) and thrips (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;). The Phytoseiidae are therefore very important in the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;biological control&lt;/a&gt; (whether natural or humanly-instigated) of such pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: Phytoseiids bear an entire dorsal plate with less than 23 pairs of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Setae&#34;&gt;setae&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmata&#34;&gt;stigmata&lt;/a&gt; open between legs III and IV and the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Metasternal_plates&#34;&gt;metasternal plates&lt;/a&gt; are small. The legs are undifferentiated, usually with two claws and an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/empodium&#34;&gt;empodium&lt;/a&gt;, and the digits of the male &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermadactyl&#34;&gt;spermadactyls&lt;/a&gt; are distally free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Phytoseiids, fast-moving, proactive predators, live on plants and in the upper soil layers. They mostly attack mites, but also small insects, nematodes and fungi, and may feed on plants, including pollen and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Extrafloral_nectary&#34;&gt;extrafloral nectaries&lt;/a&gt;. Most species develop within a week at 27°C and 60-90% relative humidity and usually deposit 30-40 eggs per female. Sex determination in most phytoseiids is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parahaploidy&#34;&gt;parahaploidy&lt;/a&gt; (a few species are &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thelytokous&#34;&gt;thelytokous&lt;/a&gt;) and the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sex_ratio&#34;&gt;sex ratio&lt;/a&gt; in the field is around 0.75. The males locate females by a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt;. Phytoseiids survive winters either by going into a facultative reproductive &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt; (induced by a short daylight and low temperatures) or by being resistant to low temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phytoseiids disperse by running on leaves, walking along spider mite webs,
crawling on the soil and while borne on air streams. Dispersal by winds is due
to prey depletion; the mites (mostly young, mated females) moving onto exposed
surfaces and placing themselves in a position to be lifted by air currents.
Once on plants the predators are attracted to their prey by volatiles emitted
by the pest-damaged foliage as well as to spider mite cues, such as
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Webbing&#34;&gt;webbing&lt;/a&gt; and other residues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biological control-oriented studies on the Phytoseiidae began only at the
close of the Second World War, when outbreaks of spider mites that followed
the introduction of synthetic pesticides on commercial crops indicated the
paramount importance of these predators. The ability of Phytoseiidae to
develop &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance_to_pesticides&#34;&gt;resistance to pesticides&lt;/a&gt;
contributed to their continuing use in biological control and integrated pest
management (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/IPM&#34;&gt;IPM&lt;/a&gt;) projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diversity of feeding habits and life history traits of the Phytoseiidae
indicated placing them in four categories, a grouping that could be used when
selecting these predators for specific biological control purposes. Type I
consists only of &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phytoseiulus_persimilis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phytoseiulus persimilis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Athias-Henriot and its cogeners, all specialized predators of heavily-webbing
spider mites, mostly &lt;em&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/em&gt; spp. Type II phytoseiids feed on spider
mites, but are not restricted to &lt;em&gt;Tetranychus&lt;/em&gt; spp, devouring also spider
mites that produce little webbing [e.g. the European red mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Panonychus_ulmi&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panonychus
ulmi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Koch)&lt;/code&gt;], as well as other small mites and pollen.
Type III species are generalists that often prefer prey other than spider
mites (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tarsonemidae&#34;&gt;tarsonemids&lt;/a&gt; and thrips). Type IV phytoseiids
are generalists that develop and reproduce best on pollen, with whose
availability their population trends seem to be closely associated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phytoseiidae included in this compendium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Amblyseius_swirskii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Typhlodromus_athiasae&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athiasae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Porath and Swirski&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phytoseiulus_persimilis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phytoseiulus persimilis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chant, D.A. and McMurtry, J.A. 1994. A review of the subfamilies Phytoseiinae
and Typhlodrominae (Acari: Phytoseiidae). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Acarology&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;: 223-310.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Croft, B. A. 1990. &lt;em&gt;Arthropod Biological Control Agents and Pesticides&lt;/em&gt;.
Wiley, New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., R.L. Smiley and R. Ochoa. 2003. &lt;em&gt;Mites (Acari) in Biological
Control.&lt;/em&gt; Blackwell Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoy, M.A., 2000. Transgenic arthropods for pest management: risks and
realities. &lt;em&gt;Experimental and Applied Acarology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;: 463-95.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kostiainen, T.S. and Hoy, M.A. 1996. The Phytoseiidae as Biological Control
Agents of Pest Mites and Insects: a Bibliography (1960-1994). University of
Florida Publications, Monog. 17. Gainesville, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McMurtry, J.A. and Croft, B.A. 1997. Life styles of phytoseiid mites and their
roles in biological control. &lt;em&gt;Annual Review of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt;: 291-321.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sabelis, M.W and van Rijn, P.C.J. 1997. Predation by insects and mites. In:
&lt;em&gt;Thrips as Crop Pests&lt;/em&gt; (Ed. by T. Lewis), pp. 259-354. CABI, London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Ragusa de Chiara, S. and Tsolakis, H. 1998. Keys to the
phytoseiid mites (Parasitiformes, Phytoseiidae) of Israel. &lt;em&gt;Phytophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;:
85-154.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eppo.org/QUARANTINE/biocontrol/acarina.html&#34;&gt;http://www.eppo.org/QUARANTINE/biocontrol/acarina.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyphagous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entry/polyphagous</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entry/polyphagous</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polyphagous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An organism that can feed on many different foods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>