<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Cossidae on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/cossidae/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeuzera pyrina</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/zeuzera_pyrina</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cossidae&#34;&gt;Cossidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Leopard moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Europe, North and South Africa, Japan, North America, Mediterranean region. Distribution Maps of Plant Pests, No. 314, Commonwealth Institute of Entomology. 1973.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Polyphagous, preferring soft-wood trees, in the Middle East occurring mostly on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apple&#34;&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Olive&#34;&gt;olive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pear&#34;&gt;pear&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Plum&#34;&gt;plum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pomegranate&#34;&gt;pomegranate&lt;/a&gt; and about 150 other tree species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: A single young &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larva&lt;/a&gt; may cause the death of thin branches, by withering or breaking. Although olives are less susceptible, the tendency of the moth to remain on the same hosts results in several pest generations developing there, causing considerable damage to the trees, which become weakened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult moth is whitish and covered by numerous dark-bluish spots when developing within apple trees, whereas those from olives have pinkish wings with greenish dotes. The body is darkish with white hairs. At rest the wings are folded along the body, which is 25-30 mm long. The males are smaller (20 mm long). The larva is dark-yellow with black dorsal tubercles, About 50-55 mm long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The moths occur in the orchards from May to November, dependent upon temperatures, host plant and plant protection practices. A female lives about one week, depositing 100-300 eggs on the bark, mostly on the tree from which it had emerged, or nearby. The emerging larvae bore into young twigs, often at the leaf bases, bringing about the withering on a leaf growing underneath. The larvae then move into elder, thicker branches wherein it continues to borrow into the wood, pushing out its brownish &lt;a href=&#34;glossary/Frass&#34;&gt;frass&lt;/a&gt; and completing its development there. The pattern of the excavated tunnels differs between trees. In hosts like deciduous fruit trees, the tunnels are straight, whereas in other trees, like olives, the tunnels may be circular or sinuous. Prior to pupation the mature larva bores an emergence hole near the original point of ingress, and seals it by a thin membrane. The young adults break through and emerge. The pest completes a single annual generation in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Light_trap&#34;&gt;Light traps&lt;/a&gt; have been used in the past, but were supplemented by male &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mating_disruption&#34;&gt;mating disruption&lt;/a&gt; traps, placed during   spring on the trees, to serve as an early warning system. Another method is to   observe the occurrence of “flag leaves”, the withering leaves at the bases of      thin branches infested by the young larvae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural contro&lt;/strong&gt;: In the past thin wires   were inserted through the frass into the burrows, or pesticides were thus   introduced. These are time consuming methods and probably suitable only in   instances of low infestations. More recently  by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; threads (650 per hectare) is being used, as it controls the pest on olives during most of the season,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; are used when necessary, but may only be applied against the exposed adults, and cannot be used during harvest. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/insect_growth_regulators&#34;&gt;IGRs&lt;/a&gt; have also been successfully applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The parasitic &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Elachertus nigritulus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Zetterstedt&lt;/code&gt;, (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae)&lt;/a&gt; has been mass reared from leopard moth larvae, but its effect on the pest’s damage is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abed El-Hadi, Birger, R., Hanoch, E., Vardi, Y., Sarid, D. and Zemer, B. 2005.
Control of &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; in olives by using pheromone male confusing. &lt;em&gt;Alon
Ha’notea&lt;/em&gt; 59: 383-385 (in Hebrew)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, Z. and Harpaz, I. 1969. &lt;em&gt;Plant Pests of Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Israel Universities
Press, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ismail, I.I., Abouzeid, N.A. and Abdallah, F.F. 1992. Population dynamics of
the leopard moth, &lt;em&gt;Zeuzera pyrina&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt;, and its control on olive trees in
Egypt. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Pflanzenkrankheiten und Pfanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; 99:
519-524.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ZeuzPyrin.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6zeupyr.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

[ Insert Text For The Web Site](http://www.Insert Acurate URL)

**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: **

** [ Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>