<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Coccoidea on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/coccoidea/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonina graminis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing:&lt;/strong&gt; Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pseudococcidae&#34;&gt;Pseudococcidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Name&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale occurs in tropical and subtropical regions, approximately bounded by the 32nd parallel. The pest was first found in the Middle East in the late 1960s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #216, 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  About 100 species of grasses (Gramineae), including many pasture grasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  Damage [especially to rhodesgrass, &lt;em&gt;Chloris gayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Kunth&lt;/code&gt;, and to bermudagrass, &lt;em&gt;Cynodon dactylon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;] is due to the removal of plant sap. Infested plants turn yellow and shrivel. Injury may be compounded by plant stress factors, such as drought, irrigation by low-grade water, close mowing (of lawns and golf courses) and by overgrazing. Infested pastures, unless treated, decline and dry up within 2-4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is legless, with short, 2-segmented antennae. The body is dark-red and becomes darker as the scale matures. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spiracles&#34;&gt;spiracles&lt;/a&gt; are large, with many surrounding &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pores&#34;&gt;pores&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cerarii&#34;&gt;Cerarii&lt;/a&gt; absent, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Anal_Ring&#34;&gt;anal ring&lt;/a&gt; somewhat retracted from posterior end of the body. The female is totally enclosed within a white waxy sac, and produces a long, anal waxy excretory tube or stalk, used to excrete its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; away from the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt;, each female giving birth to about 150 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Crawler&#34;&gt;crawlers&lt;/a&gt;. They usually settle at the lower nodes or crowns of grasses, between leaf sheaths, where they feed and produce their excretory stalk. A generation requires about 10 weeks, development being continuous throughout the year except during very cold or very hot periods. Dispersal may be by human transport of infested grasses, by the movement of the crawlers or by being borne on winds. Ants may be associated with these pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-feeding females live for at least five weeks and continue to produce young
for much of that period, an attribute that has been used for the mass rearing
of its natural enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;: Population size can be estimated by collecting 10 rhodesgrass runners, each with at least 10 nodes, from different parts of a field and counting the number of scales that had settled thereon. Best (most uniform) results are obtained from nodes that have not yet taken root. In addition, data from these nodes provide a better indication of recent changes in the pest&amp;rsquo;s population, whereas older nodes could have been colonized for longer periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;:  Improvements of plant condition by better irrigation, by fertilization and by moderate grazing and mowing. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;Resistant&lt;/a&gt; rhodesgrass varieties are also available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;Systemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; may provide satisfactory control, but their use (in granulated formulations) is limited to small areas, like golf courses. The cost of applying such pesticides to rangelands is prohibitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Neodusmetia_sangwani&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Rao)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;),
of Indian provenance, was introduced into Israel in 1971, mass-reared on
field-collected &lt;em&gt;A. graminis&lt;/em&gt; and released at several rhodesgrass plots.
Parasitization rates are very high and at present the pest has almost totally
disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chada, H.L. and Wood, E.A., Jr. 1960. Biology and control of the rhodesgrass
scale. &lt;em&gt;United States Department of Agriculture, Technical Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; #
&lt;strong&gt;1221&lt;/strong&gt;, pp. 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., E. Mescheloff and E. Dubitzki. 1975. The introduction of
&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao) (Hymenoptera: Encyrtidae) into Israel for the
control of rhodesgrass scale, &lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt; (Maskell) (Homoptera:
Pseudococcidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Ecology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:  767-779.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. 1967. Response of forage grasses to rhodesgrass scale. &lt;em&gt;Journal
of Range Management&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;:  307-309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. and Bolling, J.C. 1971. Biological control of rhodesgrass scale
in Texas by &lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao). Effectiveness and colonization
studies. &lt;em&gt;Texas Agricultural Experiment Station&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;B1104&lt;/strong&gt;:  1-15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&#34;&gt;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aonidiella aurantii</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_aurantii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_aurantii</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/occoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: California red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;thumbnails/AonidiellaAurantii-sm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Outdoors in most tropical and subtropical regions of the world; within greenhouses in cooler areas. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #2, 1996 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Polyphagous; a pest mainly of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, rarely also of roses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The California red scale, a major pest of citrus throughout the world, attacks all above-ground parts of the trees. On trunks of young trees the scale may form thick incrustations, and also infests the leaves and fruit. At feeding the pest injects toxins into the leaves, which causes them to yellow and drop. Heavy defoliation retards and stunts tree growth, affecting the yield; young trees are mostly at risk. Although scales that settle on young fruit in the early summer often die, but the pit that remains around them detracts from their market value. Large numbers of scales on the face of the fruit (Figure 1), which are difficult to remove even by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/DescalingMachines&#34;&gt;descaling machines&lt;/a&gt;, further reduce the fruits&amp;rsquo; value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig60p&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/AonidiellaAurantii-on-lemon-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;fig60p&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: Aonidiella aurantii on lemon&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On rose bushes that are more than three years old the scale settles on the
wooden or even green branches, leading to their die back, general plant
weakening and even death. Attack is more common on greenhouse roses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The dorsal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Macroducts&#34;&gt;macroducts&lt;/a&gt; are one-barred, slender, 5-6 on each side of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pygidium&#34;&gt;pygidium&lt;/a&gt;, none on the pre-pygidial segments. The body of the female is initially yellow, pear-shaped, later brown-red, round, almost square. After mating the fused &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prosoma&#34;&gt;prosoma&lt;/a&gt; and thorax become heavily sclerotized, strongly reniform, expanding around the pygidium. The entire body adheres to the shield and cannot be separated. The pygidium bears three large &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lobes&#34;&gt;lobes&lt;/a&gt;, all externally notched, the fourth lobe appearing as a mere point. Four club-like processes (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Paraphyses&#34;&gt;paraphyses&lt;/a&gt;) arise from the lobes on either side of the pygidium, and the anus is located halfway between the median lobes and the vagina. There are no &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Perivulvar_Pores&#34;&gt;perivulvar pores.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; is about 2.0 mm in diameter, thin and
almost transparent, brownish, round and slightly convex, the darker juvenile
exuviae at center. The ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Exuvium&#34;&gt;exuvium&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;velum&amp;rdquo;) is
retained as a thin membrane. The winged males are pale-orange, their dark
shields are oval and the exuvium of the 1st instar placed near one end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The California red scale is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Viviparous&#34;&gt;viviparous&lt;/a&gt;, giving birth to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Crawler&#34;&gt;crawlers&lt;/a&gt;. The emergence of the crawlers is affected by temperature and light. They emerge mostly in the morning hours, when temperatures rise above 12°C, but not in the dark at low temperatures. Under warmer conditions they emerge also in the dark, mostly during a few morning hours. The pest annually raises four generations along the coastal plain of Israel, peaks in crawler production occurring in February, June, September and October. In warmer regions it may raise another 1-2 generations. The populations of the pest have two yearly peaks, attaining their numerical maximum in the autumn, dropping during winter and spring, increasing in mid-summer to decline again in late summer to peak in the autumn. The settlement sites of the crawlers seem to be determined by a compromise between being phototactic and being very sensitive to low relative humidity. Along the coastal plain, where humidity may be quite high, the scale prefers to settle on young citrus trees or on the outer rows of mature orchards, being rare within dense plantations. But in the inner, warmer and drier parts of Israel the scale is more abundant within trees, where humidity is somewhat higher. Crawlers prefer to settle on citrus species and varieties that have relatively few oil glands (sour orange, &lt;em&gt;Citrus aurantium&lt;/em&gt;) as compared to those with abundant oil glands (mandarine, &lt;em&gt;Citrus reticulata&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Threshold_Of_Development&#34;&gt;threshold of development&lt;/a&gt; was
calculated to be 11°C and 825 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Days_Degrees&#34;&gt;days-degrees&lt;/a&gt; were
required for one generation. The optimal conditions for development seem to be
24°C and air humidity of above 60%. The fecundity of the scale is affected by
the season and by the host plant. An average of 220 offspring was produced on
lemon fruit in the spring, 108 in the summer and only 38 on the same host in
autumn. On citrus leaves fecundity came to 19 progeny in the spring, 80 in the
summer and 44 in the autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crawlers (and males) may be dispersed by winds to a distance of over 300
m, their numbers decreasing with increasing distance from the source. The
wind-borne crawlers, which appear to be relatively tolerant to desiccation,
then establish new colonies. Mature females may also be dispersed by winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California red scale females produce a sex
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; that attracts the short-lived males. This
pheromone has been synthesized and, impregnated onto yellow cards, was at one
time used for monitoring the periods of mass male flights and hence of
subsequent crawler emergence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California red scale may be mass-reared on green lemons, banana squash fruit
or on potato tubers. Individual scales may be reared on disks of lemon leaves
floating on water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanical control&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest, unless it infests the fruit in very high numbers, can be removed with high-pressure descaling machines that dislodge the scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mating disruption&lt;/strong&gt;:  Isolation of the sex &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; of the California red scale led to efforts to disrupt its mating, efforts that were later abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;:  On citrus the pest can be controlled with white &lt;a href=&#34;entry/White_Oils&#34;&gt;white oils&lt;/a&gt; or with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt;s, applied against the crawlers, which are the most susceptible stage, in the spring. In recent years the pest has developed widespread &lt;a href=&#34;entry/ResistanceToPesticides&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to organophosphates, whose use has been discontinued. A single application of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Insect_Growth_Regulators&#34;&gt;insect growth regulator&lt;/a&gt; Tiger (pyriproxyfen) currently controls the pest for two years in Israel, whereas in Turkey one or two (in the spring and in the fall) oil treatments suffice. If windbreak trees (e.g. cypress) are also infested, they too should be sprayed. On roses organophosphates (such as azinophos-methyl or malathion), applied four times at monthly intervals during winter, provided full pest control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:  The California red scale is controlled (unless disrupted by pesticides) by a suite of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;aphelinid&lt;/a&gt; parasitoids. In mild and humid regions these include the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_chrysomphali&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_lingnanensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis lingnanensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Compere&lt;/code&gt;, whereas in more arid areas &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_melinus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis melinus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;DeBach&lt;/code&gt; (the dominant species in Turkey) and &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/AphytisCoheni&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;DeBach&lt;/code&gt; may be found. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;encyrtid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Comperiella_bifasciata&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Howard&lt;/code&gt; has recently been introduced into and became established in Cyprus. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccinellidae&#34;&gt;coccinellid&lt;/a&gt; beetle &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Chilocorus_bipustulatus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chilocorus bipustulatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt; is a major predator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kehat, M. and Greenberg, S. 1968. Trials in the control of &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella
aurantii&lt;/em&gt; Mask. On greenhouse roses. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt;: 25-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levitin, E. and Cohen, E. 1998. The involvement of acetylcholinesterase in
resistance of the California red scale &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; to
organophosphorus pesticides. &lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt;:
 115-121.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanides, G.M. 1996. Establishment of &lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt; (Hym:
Encyrtidae) on &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom: Diaspididae) in Cyprus.
&lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;:  53-57.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peleg, B.A. and Bar-Zakay, I. 1995. The pest status of citrus scale insects in
Israel (1984-1994). &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;:  261-264.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uygun, N., Karaca, I. and Sekeroglu, E. 1995. Population dynamics of
&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Maskell) (Homoptera: Diaspididae) and its natural
enemies on citrus in the Mediterranean region of Turkey from 1976 to 1993.
&lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;: 239-246.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willard, J.R. 1972. The rhythm of emergence of crawlers of California red
scale, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mask.)&lt;/code&gt;, (Homoptera: Diaspididae). &lt;em&gt;Australian
Journal of Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;: 49-65.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willard, J.R. 1974. Horizontal and vertical distribution of California red
scale, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mask.)&lt;/code&gt;, (Homoptera: Diaspididae) in the field.
&lt;em&gt;Australian Journal of Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;, 531-548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aonaur.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aonaur.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aonidiella orientalis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_orientalis</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_orientalis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Oriental red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;:  South-East Asia, Australia, parts of Africa, Central America, Middle East. In Israel since 1980, now found in most mango-growing regions. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #386, 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A pest of many crops, including &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Avocado&#34;&gt;avocado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, coconut, papaya and tea. In Israel &lt;em&gt;A. orientalis&lt;/em&gt; is a minor pest of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Mango&#34;&gt;mango&lt;/a&gt;, settling on the leaves and twigs. The feeding sites on the fruit remain green even after color break, reducing their market value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Very polyphagous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The dorsal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Macroducts&#34;&gt;macroducts&lt;/a&gt; are one-barred, slender, usually three on each side of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pygidium&#34;&gt;pygidium&lt;/a&gt;. The pre-pygidial abdominal segments carry clusters of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Microducts&#34;&gt;microducts&lt;/a&gt;. The female is rounded, initially yellow, later turning brown-red. After mating the fused &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prosoma&#34;&gt;prosoma&lt;/a&gt; and thorax become sclerotized, except for a central area extending from the pygidium to the mouth parts. The pygidium bears three &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lobes&#34;&gt;lobes&lt;/a&gt;, the two median lobes externally and internally notched, the third only externally; the fourth lobe occurs as a mere point. The anus is located about two-thirds of the distance between the vulva and the median lobes. Three small &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Paraphyse&#34;&gt;paraphyses&lt;/a&gt; arise near the second and third lobes on either side of the pygidium. The ventral vulva lies between two clusters of about 10 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/PerivulvarPores&#34;&gt;perivulvar pores&lt;/a&gt; on either side, with 1-2 additional pores in front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shield is thick, flat, gray-white to brownish, round, the darker juvenile
exuviae almost at center. The winged males are pale-orange, their dark shields
oval, the paler &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Exuvium&#34;&gt;exuvium&lt;/a&gt; of the 1st instar placed
near one end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest settles on mango leaves, twigs and fruit. Its populations peak in the winter, are low in the spring and increasing during late summer. The scale is more abundant on tree sides not exposed to the prevailing winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental red scale may be controlled by a mixture of two pesticides, an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; The oriental red scale is attacked by several &lt;a href=&#34;Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&#34;ComperiellaBifasciata&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Howard and &lt;a href=&#34;HabrolepisAspidioti&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Habrolepis aspidioti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Compere and Annecke, the &lt;a href=&#34;Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;aphelinid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;AphytisMelinus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis melinus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; DeBach and &lt;a href=&#34;AphytisLingnanensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis lingnanensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Compere, and the endoparasitoid &lt;em&gt;Encarsia&lt;/em&gt; sp. It is not clear whether they contribute to the control of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Badawi, A. and Alahmed, A.M. 1990. The population dynamics of the oriental
scale insect, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead) and factors affecting its
seasonal abundance.  &lt;em&gt;Arab Gulf journal of Scientific Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;: 81-89.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wysoki, M., Ben-Dov, Y., Swirski, E. and Izhar, Y. 1993. The arthropod pests
of mango in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Acta Horticulturae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;341:&lt;/strong&gt;452-466.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wysoki, M., Israeli, Y. and Rosen, D. 1995. The oriental red scale,
&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead) (Diaspididae): biology, phenology,
geographic distribution and natural enemies in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;:  267.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpi.qld.gov.au/horticulture/5353.html&#34;&gt;http://www.dpi.qld.gov.au/horticulture/5353.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenicococcus marlatti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/phoenicococcus_marlatti</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/phoenicococcus_marlatti</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phoenicococcus marlatti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cockerell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt; Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phoenicococcidae&#34;&gt;Phoenicococcidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Red date scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: World-wide, wherever date palms are grown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Members of the genus  &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt; (palms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The red date scale is usually regarded as a minor pest, but if it occurs in large numbers on young trees it can retard their growth, causing stunting and even decline. The pest’s feeding on date pinnae causes their wilting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the female is reddish, rounded, slightly pear-shaped, about 1.3 mm in length. It bears a white marginal fringe. The males lack wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The scale apparently raises four annual generations, although its biology has not been studied in the Middle East. It usually infests the bases of the rachis and does not occur on the apices of the pinnae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to hiding deep within palm trees, chemical control (if necessary) is not recommended, but sanitation of seedlings during planting may reduce the pest’s populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carpenter, J.B. and  Elmer, H.S. 1978. Pests and diseases of the date palm. ARS, USDA Agriculture Handbook, No. 527: 1-42.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinacori, A. 1995. &lt;em&gt;Phoenicococcus marlatti&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;code&gt;Cockerell&lt;/code&gt;) (Homoptera:
Phoenicococcidae) (on &lt;em&gt;Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;) in Sicily. &lt;em&gt;Phytophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;: 55-61.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dip-alicante.es/servdipu/areafome/trabajos/cochinilla/indice5.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.dip-alicante.es/servdipu/areafome/trabajos/cochinilla/indice5.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>