<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Pests on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria mangiferae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_mangiferae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_mangiferae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria mangiferae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Sayed&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Mango bud (or gall) mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Egypt and Israel, South Africa, southern Asia, Florida, Mexico and several Central and South American regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Mango&#34;&gt;Mango&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mangifera indica&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mango bud mite is considered to be the major pest of mango in Egypt. It lives (sometimes in large numbers, coming to over 20 per bud) in the buds and inflorescences of the host, causing &amp;ldquo;califlower&amp;rdquo;-like growths. Mite feeding stunts and malforms the buds, causes leaf drop and arrests plant growth, resulting in twiggy, stubby branches. Young trees are more heavily attacked. Yield can be greatly reduced. The mite usually occurs along with the pathogenic fungus &lt;em&gt;Fusarium mangiferae&lt;/em&gt;. The feeding wounds of the mite probably serve as portals for the fungus, which appears to cause most of the damage. In addition, &lt;em&gt;A. mangiferae&lt;/em&gt; transmits the fungus between trees and probably between tree parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult mango bud mite is whitish, about 0.20 mm in length, cylindrical. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; bears a pair of backwards-pointing setae set on tubercles with three strong ridges located between them. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feather_claw&#34;&gt;feather claw&lt;/a&gt; is six-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The mango bud mite lives throughout the year within closed adventive buds on the tree trunk and branches, moving into terminal buds duirng periods of population increase. It reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt; and its entire cycle (egg to egg) requires 2-3 weeks in summer, twice that much in winter. The pest raises 8 annual generations in Egypt, with distinct spring and autumn peaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Pruning of the affected twigs may reduce, but not eliminate, the extent of the damage. Certain varieties, such as Maya, Palmer, Keitt and Kent, seem to be resistant as they sustain only very small mite colonies, whereas Tommy Atkins is more affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: The application of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricides&lt;/a&gt; may reduce, but not eliminate, the extent of the damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;phytoseiid&lt;/a&gt; predator &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Amblyseius_swirskii&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt; is commonly associated with the mango bud mite but its effect on the pest is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abou-Awad, B.A. 1981. Ecological and biological studies on the mango bud mite,
&lt;em&gt;Eriophyes mangiferae&lt;/em&gt; (Sayed), with descriptions of immature stages
(Eriophyoidea: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Acarologia&lt;/em&gt; 22: 145-150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peña, J. and Johnson, F. 1998. Insect Management in Mango. Department of
Entomology and Nematology Document ENY-413. Florida Cooperative Extension
Service, Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, University of Florida.
Available at:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://edis.ifas.ufl.edu/IG073&#34;&gt;http://edis.ifas.ufl.edu/IG073&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Goldenberg, S. 1976. Mango eriophyid mites in relation to
inflorescence. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 4: 45-50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Wysoki, M. and Izhar, Y. 2002. &lt;em&gt;Subtropical Fruits Pests in
Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Fruit Board of Israel (in Hebrew with English Summary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaher, M.A. and Osman, A.A. 1970. Population studies on mites associated with
mango trees in Egypt. _Bull. Societe d’entomologie Egypte_54: 141-148.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf]&#34;&gt;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria oleae</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_oleae</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_oleae</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria oleae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Olive gall mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Of East Mediterranean origin, the pest has also invaded other Mediterranean countries and South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Olive&#34;&gt;Olive&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Olea europea&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: By feeding within the growing points of the olive, the mite causes the emerging leaves to be deformed and twisted. In severe cases this leads to withering and death, and even total lack of blossoming (and thus prevents fruit formation).  Overall tree development (especially of saplings) and yield may be seriously affected. Greenish spots develop on infested mature leaves which become distorted. Infested young fruit turns silvery and may be deformed by protuberances; more than half the fruit may drop or be damaged. Mature fruits are not attacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that on olives several eriophyid species may live side by side
and infest its organs together, the particular injury attributed to &lt;em&gt;A. oleae&lt;/em&gt;
may actually be due to one or more species damaging the host together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult mite is yellow, about 0.13 mm in length, cylindrical, with a similar number (50-60) of dorsal and ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ppisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosomal&lt;/a&gt; rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt; prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; has an obscure pattern with lines that are discernible only towards the rear and bears two long backwards-pointing setae; the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; The olive gall mite prefers young olives growing in warm and humid conditions, thus thriving in nurseries and well-irrigated young plantations, and infesting mainly the peripheral growth. It passes the winter hidden on the lower sides of the leaves, the populations moving to the flower clusters in spring. In Greece the pest raised 12-15 annual generations in the field, and its populations peaked during June-July, with a smaller rise in late September. The mite reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt; arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;, each female depositing up to 40 eggs. When reared in the laboratory on olive leaf disks at 21-24ºC, its life cycle (egg to egg) required about a forthnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Some olive varieties seem to be tolerant to the pest. In addition, horticultural practices, such as pruning or topping, induce new growth and thus the formation of more susceptible buds. The mite may spread to new areas by infested seedlings, which should be suitably treated prior to transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: In the past the mite was often controlled with wettable sulfur, usually applied early in the season. Nowadays either amitraz or &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt; will control the pest when applied before olive blooming, in order to prevent damage to fruit, or given several times during the season if leaf damage is to be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Several predatory mites of the family &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; are associated with the olive gall mite, the most abundant species in Italy being &lt;em&gt;Typhlodromus athenas&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Swirski and Ragusa&lt;/code&gt;. Although the quantitative effect of the various phytoseiids has not been resolved, it is commonly believed that eriophyid olive pests are held below their economic injury threshold by the predators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abd Elhadi, F. and Birger, R. 1999. A new approach to the control of the olive
mite &lt;em&gt;Aceria&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Eriophyes&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;em&gt;oleae&lt;/em&gt; in olive trees. &lt;em&gt;Acta Horticulturae&lt;/em&gt;
474: 555-557.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Castagnoli, M. and Oldfield, G.N. 1996. Other fruit trees and nut trees. In:
&lt;em&gt;Eriophyoid Mites, Their Biology, Natural Enemies and Control&lt;/em&gt; (edited by
Lindquist, E.E., Sabelis, M.W. and Bruin, J.), pp. 543–559. Elsevier,
Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harpaz, I. 1955. Notes on the eriophyid mites of Israel. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the
Research Council of Israel&lt;/em&gt; (Section B) 5: 61-69.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hatzinikolis, E.N. 1973. A contribution to the study of &lt;em&gt;Aceria oleae&lt;/em&gt;
(Nalepa, 1900) (Acarina: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 3rd International
Congress of Entomology&lt;/em&gt;, Junk, The Hague, pp. 221-224.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.ag.vt.edu/ipmcrsp/presentations/Mites%20poster.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aceria sheldoni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_sheldoni</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aceria_sheldoni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aceria sheldoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Ewing)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt; Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Citrus bud mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; is grown. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #127, 1980 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Citrus&lt;/em&gt; spp., especially lemons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The bud mites lives in and feed on the buds, blossoms and flowers of the host. They sometimes occurs in very large numbers. Their feeding kills the cells and causes the blackening of the buds and irregular growth of leaves, branches and fruit. The damaged buds proliferate and produce irregular and twisted growth of leaf clusters. Twigs are foreshortened and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Brooming&#34;&gt;broomed&lt;/a&gt; and the fruit deforms into various distorted shapes, including finger-like forms. Further damage is caused by fruit drop. Although the pest attacks all citrus varieties, it causes the most serious damage to lemons, whose yield may be seriously affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of the adult citrus bud mite is yellow to pink, about 0.17 mm in length, cylindrical, with a similar number (70-80) of dorsal and ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt; opisthosomal&lt;/a&gt; rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsum&lt;/a&gt; bears a pair of backwards-pointing setae and two parallel ridges along its entire length. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt; featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is five-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The citrus rust mite reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt; arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;, each female deposits about 50 eggs, and its entire cycle (egg to egg) requires about 15 days in summer, twice that much in winter. The pest thus raises about 20 annual generations. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sex_Ratio&#34;&gt; sex ratio&lt;/a&gt; is male-biased in spring and female-biased during fall. Although the mite lacks eyes, it is attracted to yellow and red, not to blue or green. The pest develops throughout the year, mostly in milder and more humid regions, with peaks in the spring and autumn. Dispersal takes place during the spring growth of most citrus trees and the several growth flushes of lemons. Young, elongating twigs are rapidly colonized by the mite, its infestations increasing as the twigs age. Temperatures below 8°C or above 35°C, and relative humidity below 40% are lethal to the mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managenment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: When necessary, the mite can be controlled by most acaricides as well as by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/White_Oils&#34;&gt; white oil&lt;/a&gt;, but the cost of such control may exceed the its economic benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Several predatory mites have
been found to be associated with the citrus bud mite, but due to being
protected inside the buds, none appear to effect the populations or the damage
caused by the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. 1969. A study of fluctuations in the citrus bud mite
population. &lt;em&gt;Annales de Zoologie-Écologie animale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;: 127-147.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. 1969. Effect of different wave lengths of light on the
behaviour of an eriophyid bud mite, &lt;em&gt;Aceria sheldoni&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Entomologia
Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;: 377-382.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Goldenberg, S. 1971. Fertilisation, sex ratio and
postembryonic stages of the citrus bud mite _ Aceria sheldoni_ (Ewing)
(Acarina, Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of Entomological Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;: 391-397.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker, G.P., Voulgaropoulos, A.L. and Phillips, P.A. 1992. Effect of citrus
bud mite (Acari: Eriophyidae) on lemon yields. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;: 1318-1329.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker, G.P., Voulgaropoulos, A.L. and Phillips, P.A. 1992. Distribution of
citrus bud mite (Acari: Eriophyidae) within lemon trees. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;: 2389-2398.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viarural.com.ar/viarural.com.ar/agricultura/frutales/plagas/aceria-sheldoni.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.viarural.com.ar/viarural.com.ar/agricultura/frutales/plagas/aceria-sheldoni.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aculops lycopersici</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculops_lycopersici</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculops_lycopersici</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Massee)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt;Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Tomato russet mite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;entry/images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Worldwide; in the Middle East known since the late 1940s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map # 164, 1987.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Many members of the family Solanaceae, especially in the genera &lt;em&gt;Lycopersicum&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Solanum&lt;/em&gt;. Bindweed, &lt;em&gt;Convolvulus arvensis&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt; (Convolvulaceae), also serves as host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Infestations on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Tomato&#34;&gt;tomato&lt;/a&gt; usually begin in the lower parts of host plants, on the stems and leaves, which lose their color, wilt and drop. Attacked tomatoes become bronzed and rough, and severe infestations cause plant withering and death. Yield is much reduced. Tomato is the most heavily affected host plant, but petunia, pepper and potato may also be damaged. Infested eggplants usually show less damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is spindle-shaped, yellowish, about 0.16-0.18 mm in length, with a pair of backwards-pointing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsal&lt;/a&gt; setae. The dorsal shield bears two ridges that are parallel along their posterior half but diverge anteriorly. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosoma&lt;/a&gt; has about 30 dorsal and 60 ventral rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feather_claw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is a warm-weather leaf vagrant that has no dormancy and dies if exposed to sub-freezing temperatures. Development is also retarded under high humidity conditions at high temperatures. In temperate regions the pest survives winters only within greenhouses, but under warmer conditions &lt;em&gt;A. lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; lives out of season on bindweed or on wild Solanaceae. These plants serve as sources for the infestation of crops, reaching them with winds, insects or by clinging to farming implements and personnel. An entire life cycle cn be completed in about one week, each female producing 30-50 progeny. Like other Eriophyidae, reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;; males deposite &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; on the leaves that are taken up by the females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: Tomato varieties whose leaves bear more &lt;a href=&#34;entry/trichome&#34;&gt;trichomes&lt;/a&gt; are less susceptible to the mite. Various mineral fertilization regimes or plant height have no effect on the pest&amp;rsquo;s level of attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Several acarine
predators in the families &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmaeidae&#34;&gt;Stigmaeidae&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tydeaidae&#34;&gt;Tydeidae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the pest in the
laboratory, but little is known about their effect in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;Acaricides&lt;/a&gt; effective against the pest include &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt;, dicofol, cyhexatin and compounds of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Bacillus_thuringiensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson, L.A. 1954. The tomato russet mite in the United States. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 47: 1001-1005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harpaz, I. 1955. Notes on the eriophyid mites of Israel. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the
Research Council of Israel&lt;/em&gt; 5B: 61-69.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hessein, N. A. and Perring, T.M. 1986. Feeding habits of the Tydeidae with
evidence of &lt;em&gt;Homeopronematus anconai&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Tydeidae) predation on &lt;em&gt;Aculops
lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Acarology&lt;/em&gt;
12: 215-221.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leite, G.L.D., PicanÇo, M., Guedes, R.N.C. and Zanuncio, J.C. 1999. Influence
of canopy height and fertilization levels on the resistance of &lt;em&gt;Lycopersicon
hirsutum&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae). &lt;em&gt;Experimental and
Applied Acarology&lt;/em&gt; 23: 633-642.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osman, A.A. and Zaki, A.M. 1986. Studies on the predation efficiency of
&lt;em&gt;Agistemus exsertus&lt;/em&gt; Gonzalez (Acarina, Stigmaeidae) on the eriophyid mite
&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Massee). &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger Schadlingskunde Pflazenschutz,
Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt; 59: 135-136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice, R.E. and Strong, F.E. 1962. Bionomics of the tomato russet mite,
&lt;em&gt;Vasates lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; (Massee). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 55:
431-435.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Royalty, R.N. and Perring, T.M. 1987. Comparative toxicity of acaricides to
&lt;em&gt;Aculops lycopersici&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Homeopronematus anconai&lt;/em&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae:
Tydeidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 80: 348-351.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/a_lycope.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/a_lycope.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.
inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aculyc.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aculyc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)

 --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aculus cornutus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculus_cornutus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aculus_cornutus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aculus cornutus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Banks)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;[= &lt;em&gt;fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt;]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyoidea&#34;&gt;Eriophyoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;Eriophyidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Silver peach mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: almost wherever &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Peach&#34;&gt;peaches&lt;/a&gt; are grown. In the Middle East since the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Stone fruit trees (Rosaceae), including &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Almond&#34;&gt;almonds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Apricot&#34;&gt;apricots&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Peach&#34;&gt;nectarines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Plum&#34;&gt;plums&lt;/a&gt; and prunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms and economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The feeding of the peach silver mite causes silvering of peach foliage late in the season as well as yellow chlorotic spots on young leaves. In heavy infestations the leaves curl and may drop, plant growth is retarded and yield is affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is spindle-shaped, yellowish, about 0.18 mm in length, with a pair of backwards-pointing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prodorsum&#34;&gt;prodorsal&lt;/a&gt; setae. The dorsal shield bears several parallel ridges that are more pronounced in the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Deutogyne&#34;&gt;deutogynes&lt;/a&gt;, which is also somewhat larger. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Opisthosoma&#34;&gt;opisthosoma&lt;/a&gt; has about 30 dorsal and 50 ventral rings. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Featherclaw&#34;&gt;featherclaw&lt;/a&gt; is four-rayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: The mite is a leaf vagrant, overwintering around the host&amp;rsquo;s terminal buds as deutogynes, which appear in the autumn, and molt to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Protogyne&#34;&gt;protogynes&lt;/a&gt; next spring. A life cycle is completed in about a fortnight, and 15-20 annual generations may be raised. Like other Eriophyidae, reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotoky&lt;/a&gt;; the males deposit &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spermatophore&#34;&gt;spermatophores&lt;/a&gt; that are taken up by the females. Fecundity is host-determined, as the mite produced 41 eggs/female on plum, only 31 on sour cherry. The protogynes of the peach silver mite differ in some morphological from the deutogynes, and were formerly described as a different species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;Acaricides&lt;/a&gt; in common usage against the pest include bromopropylate (Neoron), chlorobenzilate and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Avermectins&#34;&gt;abamectin&lt;/a&gt;. The peach silver mite is not affected by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pyrethroid&#34;&gt;pyrethroids&lt;/a&gt; and applications of these compounds abroad have resulted in pest resurgences, probably due to killing its natural enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest appears to have several efficient natural enemies of the family &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; abroad, but nothing is known about them in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boczek, J., Zawadski, W. and Davis, R. 1984. Some morphological and biological
differences in &lt;em&gt;Aculus fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae)
on various host plants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Acarology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;:81-87.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kondo, A. and Hiramatsu, T. 1999. Resurgences of the peach silver mite,
&lt;em&gt;Aculus fockeui&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Nalepa and Trouessart)&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Eriophyidae), induced by a
synthetic pyrethroid fluvalinate. &lt;em&gt;Applied Entomology and Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt;:
531-535.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sternlicht, M. and Rubin, A. 1990. The peach silver mite, a new pest in
Israel. &lt;em&gt;Ha&amp;rsquo;Sadeh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt;: 910-912 (in Hebrew with an English summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r602400211.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ipm.ucdavis.edu/PMG/r602400211.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acyrthosiphon pisum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/acyrthosiphon_pisum</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/acyrthosiphon_pisum</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acyrthosiphon pisum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Harris)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/entry/Aphidoidea&#34;&gt;Aphidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Aphididae&#34;&gt;Aphididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Pea aphid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cosmopolitan, occurring almost wherever members of the family Papilionaceae are grown. Commonwealth Instutute of Entomology Map #23, 1982 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Mostly restricted to cultivated and wild members of the Papilionaceae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The feeding of the pea aphid causes leaf curling, wilting and a general reduction in the yield of commercial legumes, especially alfalfa and clover. No &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sooty_Mold&#34;&gt;sooty mold&lt;/a&gt; damage is associated with this pest, because like other aphids with long antennae, its output of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; is meager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Apterous&#34;&gt;apterous&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Alate&#34;&gt;alate&lt;/a&gt; females is green to yellow, as are the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Siphunculi&#34;&gt;siphunculi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cauda&#34;&gt;cauda&lt;/a&gt;. The antennae are longer than the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The pea aphid reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Viviparous&#34;&gt;viviparous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt; around the year, its populations peaking in spring. Each female produces 60-70 progeny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: Some varieties of alfalfa and clover are resistant to this pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control:&lt;/strong&gt; If necessary, the pest can be controlled with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Neem&#34;&gt;neem&lt;/a&gt; products or with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The main natural enemies of the pea aphid are the &lt;a href=&#34;Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphidiidae&#34;&gt;aphidiid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt; endoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aphidius ervi&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Halliday&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aphidius urticae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Halliday&lt;/code&gt;, and several &lt;a href=&#34;EntomopathogenicFungi&#34;&gt;entomophatogenic&lt;/a&gt; fungi; their individual contribution to the pest’s control is not known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basedow, T., Ossiewatsch, H.R., Vega, J.A.B., Kollmann, S., El Shafie, H.A.F.
and Nicol, C.M.Y. 2002. Control of aphids and whiteflies (Homoptera :
Aphididae and Aleyrodidae) with different Neem preparations in laboratory,
greenhouse and field: effects and limitations. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift fur
Pflanzenkrankheiten und Pflanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;109&lt;/strong&gt;: 612-623.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mescheloff, E. and Rosen, D. 1990. Biosystematic studies on the Aphidiidae of
Israel (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonoidea). 4. The genera &lt;em&gt;Pauesia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Diaeretus&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;Aphidius&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Diaeretiella&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;: 51-91.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E. and Amitai, S. 1999. Annotated list of aphids (Aphidoidea) in
Israel. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt;: 1-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6acypis.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6acypis.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agrotis ipsilon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/agrotis_ipsilon</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/agrotis_ipsilon</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agrotis ipsilon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Hufnagel)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Noctuidae&#34;&gt;Noctuidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Black cutworm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost cosmopolitan, Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #261, 1969.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Seedlings of most crops, including legumes, crucifers, Solanaceae and &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Cotton&#34;&gt;cotton&lt;/a&gt; in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Larvae commonly feed on seedlings, cutting off their stems at ground level, which topples them. Additionally, the larvae may feed on roots, thus occasionally causing great damage in newly planted fields (e.g. cotton) early in the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The specific name of the pest (&lt;em&gt;ipsilon&lt;/em&gt;) derives from the markings on the adult &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Forewing&#34;&gt;forewing&lt;/a&gt;, which resemble the Greek character &amp;ldquo;ipsilon&amp;rdquo;. Its common name (&amp;ldquo;cutworm&amp;rdquo;) is due to the nature of the damage, the cutting off of seedlings at ground level, and the dark background coloration of the larval integument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Female adults, which are reproductively immature on emergence, begin oviposition within a week and survive for about another week. During their gravid period eggs are deposited singly or in small clusters, on the underside of leaves, near ground level. A female may lay up to 1900 eggs during its lifetime. The larvae disperse after the first molt and remain solitary for the rest of their lives, residing in the soil during day, coming up to feed at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasonal history&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest is a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Migration&#34;&gt;migratory&lt;/a&gt; species, with no seasonal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;. The duration of each generation is one-two months, depending on environmental conditions. In Israel the pest has 4-5 generations, of which those with most potential to cause damage are during autumn (November-December) and spring (February-March). Early autumn rains (e.g. high humidity) and mild temperatures are conducive to population increase. The autumn population in Israel is presumably bolstered by migrant adults. Infestations in Syria are higher in years with high rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The occasional appearance of black cutworm populations poses a logistic
problem for preventive measures, especially as the larvae reside in the soil,
making detection difficult until damage had revealed their existence. Control
measures are difficult because of the inaccessible location of the larvae to
some forms of chemical applications. One preventive measure is sanitation, the
removal of weeds and volunteer plants from previously-damaged fields and their
surroundings, and deep ploughing if populations recur. Adults on the wing can
be monitored by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; trapping. First damage may usually
be expected about 2 weeks after peak flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Spray applications may be directed towards first instar &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; while they are still feeding on the underside of foliage, or else granular insecticides can be applied onto the soil. Moistened poison bait may be mixed with the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; trichlofon and parathion, or the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamate&lt;/a&gt; carbaryl, and broadcast in the field at 10 kg/ha, preferably in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural enemies&lt;/strong&gt;: Natural enemies are not reliable for black cutworm control, mostly due to the sporadic appearance of the pest and the inability of seedlings to compensate for any incurred damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hill, D.S. 1983. &lt;em&gt;Agrotis ipsilon&lt;/em&gt; (Hfn.). In: &lt;em&gt;Agricultural Insect Pests of
the Tropics and Their Control&lt;/em&gt;, 2nd Edition, pp. 357-358. Cambridge University
Press, Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rings, R.W., Arnold, F.J. and Johnson, B.A. 1975. Host range of the black
cutworm on vegetables: A bibliography. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Entomological Society
of America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;:229-234.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/agrotis.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.extento.hawaii.edu/kbase/crop/Type/agrotis.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/AgrotIpsil.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/AgrotIpsil.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aleurothrixus floccosus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aleurothrixus_floccosus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aleurothrixus_floccosus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aleurothrixus floccosus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aleyrodidae&#34;&gt;Aleyrodidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Woolly whitefly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The pest, which is of Asian origin, has spread to Central and North America and then to the Mediterranean region. In Israel it has been present since the early 1990’s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Maps #327, 1997 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The woolly whitefly is approximately 1.5 mm in length, with a yellow-white body and wings that are covered with a white waxy powder. The legless &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt; are initially green, later becoming brownish. The pupa is covered by very conspicuous waxy (“woolly”) filaments (&lt;a href=&#34;figures/AleurothrixusFloccosus-Fig1&#34;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/AleurothrixusFlococcus-adult-and-larvae-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: A colony of Aleurothrixus floccosus on a citrus leaf.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Plants in about 20 families; &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; is the main crop affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The damage of the woolly whitefly to citrus is mostly due to the large amounts of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; excreted by the nymphs. This honeydew serves as substrate for &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sooty_mold&#34;&gt;sooty mold&lt;/a&gt; fungi whose dark layers interfere with leaf &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Photosynthesis&#34;&gt;photosynthesis&lt;/a&gt; and thus with tree growth and performance. During heavy infestations the leaves attain a white-black appearance (Figure2),
 due to the intermittent occurrence of adults and sooty mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/AleurothrixusFloccosus-Fig2.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 2: Citrus leaves heavily infested by the woolly whitefly.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Woolly whiteflies deposit their eggs, which are often placed in a circle or a semi-circle, into the underside of young, fully-extended leaves, usually in the inner regions of the trees. In the Mediterranean area the pest completes 5-6 annual generations, its numbers peaking during mid-summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;: An index of occupation (from 0 to 10) was linearly related to the proportion of leaf undersurface occupied by the pest, thus being a reliable and time-saving sampling method. Examining 150 leaves achieves the desired the relative variation level of 0.25 for most population densities found in Spanish commercial citrus groves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The pest is usually controlled by the introduced &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Cales noacki&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Howard&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ephelinidae&#34;&gt;Aphelinidae&lt;/a&gt;). Another important natural enemy is the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccinellidae&#34;&gt;coccinellid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coleoptera&#34;&gt;beetle&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Delphastus pusilus&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Le Conte&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argov, Y. 1994. The woolly whitefly, a new pest in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Alon Ha’notea&lt;/em&gt;
48: 290-292 (in Hebrew with an English abstract).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soto, A., Ohlenschlaeger, F. and Garcia-Mari, F. 2002. Distribution and
sampling of the whiteflies &lt;em&gt;Aleurothrixus floccosus, Dialeurodes citri _and&lt;/em&gt;
Parabemisia myricae &lt;em&gt;(Homoptera : Aleyrodidae) in citrus in Spain.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Economic Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 95: 167-173.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulusoy M.R., Vatansever, G., Erkilic, L. and Uygun, N. 2003. Studies on
&lt;em&gt;Aleurothrixus floccosus _(Maskell) (Homoptera, Aleyrodidae) and its
parasitoid,&lt;/em&gt; Cales noacki &lt;em&gt;Howard (Hymenoptera, Aphelinidae) in the East
Mediterranean region of Turkey.&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger für Schadlingskunde&lt;/em&gt; 76:
163-169.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aleflo.htm&#34;&gt; http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aleflo.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

**Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact:  [Insert Again The Same E-mail Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)**

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amblyseius swirskii</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/amblyseius_swirskii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/amblyseius_swirskii</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias-Henriot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mesostigmata&#34;&gt;Mesostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert%20Small-Image%20File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: Many indigenous and introduced plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: Dorsum about 0.3-0.4 mm in length, almost smooth, with a few &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Reticulations&#34;&gt;reticulations&lt;/a&gt;, and 17 pairs of nude setae plus two pairs of lateral setae. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternal_Plate&#34;&gt;sternal plate&lt;/a&gt; bears three pairs of setae, and there are three pairs of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Preanal_Setae&#34;&gt;preanal setae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; is the dominant summer phytoseiid predator in &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; groves along the coastal plain of Israel, where it is possibly one of the main natural enemies of the citrus rust mite, &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Phyllocoptruta_oleivora&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phyllocoptruta oleivora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Ashmead). More recently _A. swirskii _has been developed by the Dutch company Koppert B.V. as a natural enemy of thrips (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thysanoptera&#34;&gt;Thysanoptera&lt;/a&gt;), and whiteflies (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aleyrodidae&#34;&gt;Aleyrodidae&lt;/a&gt;). By late 2006 more than one billion predators, mostly within slow-release bags, known as Swirski-Mite Plus, have been sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;:The female mite required less than one week to complete a generation at 27°C, produced 44 eggs when feeding on an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eriophyidae&#34;&gt;eriophyid&lt;/a&gt; mite and lived about four weeks. The predator also feeds on other prey, including many pest mites, thrips, whiteflies, the eggs of moths (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;) and the crawlers of scale insects (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;), as well as on pollen. &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; has no winter &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El-Laithy, A.Y.M. 1998. Laboratory studies on growth parameters of three
predatory mites associated with eriophyid mites in olive nurseries. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Planzenkrankheiten und Pflanzenschutz&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt;: 78-83.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porath, A. and Swirski, E. 1965. A survey of phytoseiid mites (Acarina:
Phytoseiidae) on citrus, with a description of one new species. &lt;em&gt;Israel
Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;: 87-100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ragusa, S. and Swirski, E. 1977. Feeding habits, post-embryonic and adult
survival, mating, virility and fecundity of the predacious mite &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius
swirskii&lt;/em&gt; (Acarina: Phytoseiidae) on some coccids and mealybugs. &lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;: 383-92.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E., Amitai, S. and Dorzia, N. 1967. Laboratory studies on the
feeding, development and reproduction of the predaceous mites &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius
rubini&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Swirski &amp;amp; Amitai&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Amblyseius swirskii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Athias&lt;/code&gt; (Acarina:
Phytoseiidae) on various kinds of food substances. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of
Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;: 101-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitefly.org/whiteflyforum/forum_posts.asp?TID=82&#34;&gt;http://www.whitefly.org/whiteflyforum/forum_posts.asp?TID=82&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anacridium aegyptium</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/anacridium_aegyptium</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/anacridium_aegyptium</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anacridium aegyptium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy:   Insecta,  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt; ,  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Orthoptera&#34;&gt;Orthoptera&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acridoidea&#34;&gt;Acridoidea&lt;/a&gt;,  Acrididae Cyrtacanthacridinae&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Common name: Egyptian tree locust.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Click on image to enlarge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; The Egyptian tree locust occurs in all countries that border the Mediterranean and that are included in this compendium, and eastwards into Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants:&lt;/strong&gt; This &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;polyphagous&lt;/a&gt; feeds on grapevines in enclosed facilities as well as on the foliage of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt; and deciduous orchard trees, and on vegetables, but rarely on graminaceous plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Anacridium aegyptium&lt;/em&gt; is generally regarded as a minor pest, but may occasionally be found in sufficient density to cause local damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology:&lt;/strong&gt; The Egyptian tree locust is a large grasshopper. At rest, the adult female body, including the folded &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tegmina&#34;&gt;tegmina&lt;/a&gt;, is up to 90 mm in length, while the male measures up to 65 mm. The mottled tegmina project beyond the end of the abdomen. Adults are grey-brown in color. The hind wings are transparent and have a purplish cast, and a curved band of darker aspect runs diagonally across them. A dull yellow line runs dorsally along the crest of the pronotum. The hind tibial spines are basally pale and apically dark-tipped. The juveniles are greenish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; The pest establishes one generation per year. The adult female undergoes a photoperiod-controlled reproductive &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diapause&#34;&gt;diapause&lt;/a&gt; that lasts from September to January, and deposits eggs in the spring. Juveniles develop during the hot season, from April to August, with new adults appearing near the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management:&lt;/strong&gt; In most cases, control measures are not indicated for the occasional locust adults encountered. Because of their habit of roosting in trees, markedly during the winter diapause, it is not practical to control these pests with poisoned bait. If necessary, baits should be used against the juveniles during their development in the summer. Chemical control measures being developed against &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Locusta_migratoria&#34;&gt;migratory locusts&lt;/a&gt; may be appropriate for control of these large grasshoppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anonymous 1982. &lt;em&gt;The Locust and Grasshopper Agricultural Manual.&lt;/em&gt; Centre for Overseas Pest research, London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fishelson, L. 1985. &lt;em&gt;Orthoptera: Acridoidea&lt;/em&gt;, in: Fauna Palaestina, Insecta III. The Israel Academy of Sciences and Humanities, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geldiay, S. 1967. Hormonal control of adult reproductive diapause in the Egyptian grasshopper, &lt;em&gt;Anacridium aegyptium&lt;/em&gt; L. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Endocrinology&lt;/em&gt; 37:63-71.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geldiay, S. 1970. Photoperiodic control of neurosecretory cells in the brain of the Egyptian grasshopper, &lt;em&gt;Anacridium aegyptium&lt;/em&gt; L. &lt;em&gt;General and Comparative Endocrinology&lt;/em&gt; 14:35-42.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Websites:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&#34;&gt;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://locust.cirad.fr/omm/ana_en.html&#34;&gt;http://locust.cirad.fr/omm/ana_en.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: Insert Again The Same E-mail Address
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonina graminis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing:&lt;/strong&gt; Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pseudococcidae&#34;&gt;Pseudococcidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Name&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale occurs in tropical and subtropical regions, approximately bounded by the 32nd parallel. The pest was first found in the Middle East in the late 1960s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #216, 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  About 100 species of grasses (Gramineae), including many pasture grasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  Damage [especially to rhodesgrass, &lt;em&gt;Chloris gayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Kunth&lt;/code&gt;, and to bermudagrass, &lt;em&gt;Cynodon dactylon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;] is due to the removal of plant sap. Infested plants turn yellow and shrivel. Injury may be compounded by plant stress factors, such as drought, irrigation by low-grade water, close mowing (of lawns and golf courses) and by overgrazing. Infested pastures, unless treated, decline and dry up within 2-4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is legless, with short, 2-segmented antennae. The body is dark-red and becomes darker as the scale matures. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spiracles&#34;&gt;spiracles&lt;/a&gt; are large, with many surrounding &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pores&#34;&gt;pores&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cerarii&#34;&gt;Cerarii&lt;/a&gt; absent, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Anal_Ring&#34;&gt;anal ring&lt;/a&gt; somewhat retracted from posterior end of the body. The female is totally enclosed within a white waxy sac, and produces a long, anal waxy excretory tube or stalk, used to excrete its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; away from the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt;, each female giving birth to about 150 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Crawler&#34;&gt;crawlers&lt;/a&gt;. They usually settle at the lower nodes or crowns of grasses, between leaf sheaths, where they feed and produce their excretory stalk. A generation requires about 10 weeks, development being continuous throughout the year except during very cold or very hot periods. Dispersal may be by human transport of infested grasses, by the movement of the crawlers or by being borne on winds. Ants may be associated with these pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-feeding females live for at least five weeks and continue to produce young
for much of that period, an attribute that has been used for the mass rearing
of its natural enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;: Population size can be estimated by collecting 10 rhodesgrass runners, each with at least 10 nodes, from different parts of a field and counting the number of scales that had settled thereon. Best (most uniform) results are obtained from nodes that have not yet taken root. In addition, data from these nodes provide a better indication of recent changes in the pest&amp;rsquo;s population, whereas older nodes could have been colonized for longer periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;:  Improvements of plant condition by better irrigation, by fertilization and by moderate grazing and mowing. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;Resistant&lt;/a&gt; rhodesgrass varieties are also available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;Systemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; may provide satisfactory control, but their use (in granulated formulations) is limited to small areas, like golf courses. The cost of applying such pesticides to rangelands is prohibitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Neodusmetia_sangwani&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Rao)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;),
of Indian provenance, was introduced into Israel in 1971, mass-reared on
field-collected &lt;em&gt;A. graminis&lt;/em&gt; and released at several rhodesgrass plots.
Parasitization rates are very high and at present the pest has almost totally
disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chada, H.L. and Wood, E.A., Jr. 1960. Biology and control of the rhodesgrass
scale. &lt;em&gt;United States Department of Agriculture, Technical Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; #
&lt;strong&gt;1221&lt;/strong&gt;, pp. 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., E. Mescheloff and E. Dubitzki. 1975. The introduction of
&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao) (Hymenoptera: Encyrtidae) into Israel for the
control of rhodesgrass scale, &lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt; (Maskell) (Homoptera:
Pseudococcidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Ecology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:  767-779.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. 1967. Response of forage grasses to rhodesgrass scale. &lt;em&gt;Journal
of Range Management&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;:  307-309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. and Bolling, J.C. 1971. Biological control of rhodesgrass scale
in Texas by &lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao). Effectiveness and colonization
studies. &lt;em&gt;Texas Agricultural Experiment Station&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;B1104&lt;/strong&gt;:  1-15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&#34;&gt;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aonidiella aurantii</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_aurantii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_aurantii</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/occoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: California red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;thumbnails/AonidiellaAurantii-sm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Outdoors in most tropical and subtropical regions of the world; within greenhouses in cooler areas. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #2, 1996 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Polyphagous; a pest mainly of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, rarely also of roses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The California red scale, a major pest of citrus throughout the world, attacks all above-ground parts of the trees. On trunks of young trees the scale may form thick incrustations, and also infests the leaves and fruit. At feeding the pest injects toxins into the leaves, which causes them to yellow and drop. Heavy defoliation retards and stunts tree growth, affecting the yield; young trees are mostly at risk. Although scales that settle on young fruit in the early summer often die, but the pit that remains around them detracts from their market value. Large numbers of scales on the face of the fruit (Figure 1), which are difficult to remove even by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/DescalingMachines&#34;&gt;descaling machines&lt;/a&gt;, further reduce the fruits&amp;rsquo; value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig60p&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/AonidiellaAurantii-on-lemon-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;fig60p&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: Aonidiella aurantii on lemon&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On rose bushes that are more than three years old the scale settles on the
wooden or even green branches, leading to their die back, general plant
weakening and even death. Attack is more common on greenhouse roses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The dorsal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Macroducts&#34;&gt;macroducts&lt;/a&gt; are one-barred, slender, 5-6 on each side of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pygidium&#34;&gt;pygidium&lt;/a&gt;, none on the pre-pygidial segments. The body of the female is initially yellow, pear-shaped, later brown-red, round, almost square. After mating the fused &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prosoma&#34;&gt;prosoma&lt;/a&gt; and thorax become heavily sclerotized, strongly reniform, expanding around the pygidium. The entire body adheres to the shield and cannot be separated. The pygidium bears three large &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lobes&#34;&gt;lobes&lt;/a&gt;, all externally notched, the fourth lobe appearing as a mere point. Four club-like processes (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Paraphyses&#34;&gt;paraphyses&lt;/a&gt;) arise from the lobes on either side of the pygidium, and the anus is located halfway between the median lobes and the vagina. There are no &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Perivulvar_Pores&#34;&gt;perivulvar pores.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Shield&#34;&gt;shield&lt;/a&gt; is about 2.0 mm in diameter, thin and
almost transparent, brownish, round and slightly convex, the darker juvenile
exuviae at center. The ventral &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Exuvium&#34;&gt;exuvium&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;velum&amp;rdquo;) is
retained as a thin membrane. The winged males are pale-orange, their dark
shields are oval and the exuvium of the 1st instar placed near one end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: The California red scale is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Viviparous&#34;&gt;viviparous&lt;/a&gt;, giving birth to &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Crawler&#34;&gt;crawlers&lt;/a&gt;. The emergence of the crawlers is affected by temperature and light. They emerge mostly in the morning hours, when temperatures rise above 12°C, but not in the dark at low temperatures. Under warmer conditions they emerge also in the dark, mostly during a few morning hours. The pest annually raises four generations along the coastal plain of Israel, peaks in crawler production occurring in February, June, September and October. In warmer regions it may raise another 1-2 generations. The populations of the pest have two yearly peaks, attaining their numerical maximum in the autumn, dropping during winter and spring, increasing in mid-summer to decline again in late summer to peak in the autumn. The settlement sites of the crawlers seem to be determined by a compromise between being phototactic and being very sensitive to low relative humidity. Along the coastal plain, where humidity may be quite high, the scale prefers to settle on young citrus trees or on the outer rows of mature orchards, being rare within dense plantations. But in the inner, warmer and drier parts of Israel the scale is more abundant within trees, where humidity is somewhat higher. Crawlers prefer to settle on citrus species and varieties that have relatively few oil glands (sour orange, &lt;em&gt;Citrus aurantium&lt;/em&gt;) as compared to those with abundant oil glands (mandarine, &lt;em&gt;Citrus reticulata&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Threshold_Of_Development&#34;&gt;threshold of development&lt;/a&gt; was
calculated to be 11°C and 825 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Days_Degrees&#34;&gt;days-degrees&lt;/a&gt; were
required for one generation. The optimal conditions for development seem to be
24°C and air humidity of above 60%. The fecundity of the scale is affected by
the season and by the host plant. An average of 220 offspring was produced on
lemon fruit in the spring, 108 in the summer and only 38 on the same host in
autumn. On citrus leaves fecundity came to 19 progeny in the spring, 80 in the
summer and 44 in the autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crawlers (and males) may be dispersed by winds to a distance of over 300
m, their numbers decreasing with increasing distance from the source. The
wind-borne crawlers, which appear to be relatively tolerant to desiccation,
then establish new colonies. Mature females may also be dispersed by winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California red scale females produce a sex
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; that attracts the short-lived males. This
pheromone has been synthesized and, impregnated onto yellow cards, was at one
time used for monitoring the periods of mass male flights and hence of
subsequent crawler emergence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California red scale may be mass-reared on green lemons, banana squash fruit
or on potato tubers. Individual scales may be reared on disks of lemon leaves
floating on water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanical control&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest, unless it infests the fruit in very high numbers, can be removed with high-pressure descaling machines that dislodge the scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mating disruption&lt;/strong&gt;:  Isolation of the sex &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; of the California red scale led to efforts to disrupt its mating, efforts that were later abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;:  On citrus the pest can be controlled with white &lt;a href=&#34;entry/White_Oils&#34;&gt;white oils&lt;/a&gt; or with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt;s, applied against the crawlers, which are the most susceptible stage, in the spring. In recent years the pest has developed widespread &lt;a href=&#34;entry/ResistanceToPesticides&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to organophosphates, whose use has been discontinued. A single application of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Insect_Growth_Regulators&#34;&gt;insect growth regulator&lt;/a&gt; Tiger (pyriproxyfen) currently controls the pest for two years in Israel, whereas in Turkey one or two (in the spring and in the fall) oil treatments suffice. If windbreak trees (e.g. cypress) are also infested, they too should be sprayed. On roses organophosphates (such as azinophos-methyl or malathion), applied four times at monthly intervals during winter, provided full pest control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:  The California red scale is controlled (unless disrupted by pesticides) by a suite of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;aphelinid&lt;/a&gt; parasitoids. In mild and humid regions these include the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_chrysomphali&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis chrysomphali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_lingnanensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis lingnanensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Compere&lt;/code&gt;, whereas in more arid areas &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Aphytis_melinus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis melinus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;DeBach&lt;/code&gt; (the dominant species in Turkey) and &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/AphytisCoheni&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis coheni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;DeBach&lt;/code&gt; may be found. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;encyrtid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Comperiella_bifasciata&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Howard&lt;/code&gt; has recently been introduced into and became established in Cyprus. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccinellidae&#34;&gt;coccinellid&lt;/a&gt; beetle &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Chilocorus_bipustulatus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chilocorus bipustulatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt; is a major predator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kehat, M. and Greenberg, S. 1968. Trials in the control of &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella
aurantii&lt;/em&gt; Mask. On greenhouse roses. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Agricultural Research&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt;: 25-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levitin, E. and Cohen, E. 1998. The involvement of acetylcholinesterase in
resistance of the California red scale &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; to
organophosphorus pesticides. &lt;em&gt;Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt;:
 115-121.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orphanides, G.M. 1996. Establishment of &lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt; (Hym:
Encyrtidae) on &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Hom: Diaspididae) in Cyprus.
&lt;em&gt;Entomophaga&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;:  53-57.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peleg, B.A. and Bar-Zakay, I. 1995. The pest status of citrus scale insects in
Israel (1984-1994). &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;:  261-264.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uygun, N., Karaca, I. and Sekeroglu, E. 1995. Population dynamics of
&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; (Maskell) (Homoptera: Diaspididae) and its natural
enemies on citrus in the Mediterranean region of Turkey from 1976 to 1993.
&lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;: 239-246.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willard, J.R. 1972. The rhythm of emergence of crawlers of California red
scale, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mask.)&lt;/code&gt;, (Homoptera: Diaspididae). &lt;em&gt;Australian
Journal of Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;: 49-65.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willard, J.R. 1974. Horizontal and vertical distribution of California red
scale, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella aurantii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mask.)&lt;/code&gt;, (Homoptera: Diaspididae) in the field.
&lt;em&gt;Australian Journal of Zoology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;, 531-548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aonaur.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aonaur.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aonidiella orientalis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_orientalis</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aonidiella_orientalis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Diaspididae&#34;&gt;Diaspididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Oriental red scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;:  South-East Asia, Australia, parts of Africa, Central America, Middle East. In Israel since 1980, now found in most mango-growing regions. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #386, 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  A pest of many crops, including &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Avocado&#34;&gt;avocado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, coconut, papaya and tea. In Israel &lt;em&gt;A. orientalis&lt;/em&gt; is a minor pest of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Mango&#34;&gt;mango&lt;/a&gt;, settling on the leaves and twigs. The feeding sites on the fruit remain green even after color break, reducing their market value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Very polyphagous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;:  The dorsal &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Macroducts&#34;&gt;macroducts&lt;/a&gt; are one-barred, slender, usually three on each side of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pygidium&#34;&gt;pygidium&lt;/a&gt;. The pre-pygidial abdominal segments carry clusters of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Microducts&#34;&gt;microducts&lt;/a&gt;. The female is rounded, initially yellow, later turning brown-red. After mating the fused &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prosoma&#34;&gt;prosoma&lt;/a&gt; and thorax become sclerotized, except for a central area extending from the pygidium to the mouth parts. The pygidium bears three &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lobes&#34;&gt;lobes&lt;/a&gt;, the two median lobes externally and internally notched, the third only externally; the fourth lobe occurs as a mere point. The anus is located about two-thirds of the distance between the vulva and the median lobes. Three small &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Paraphyse&#34;&gt;paraphyses&lt;/a&gt; arise near the second and third lobes on either side of the pygidium. The ventral vulva lies between two clusters of about 10 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/PerivulvarPores&#34;&gt;perivulvar pores&lt;/a&gt; on either side, with 1-2 additional pores in front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shield is thick, flat, gray-white to brownish, round, the darker juvenile
exuviae almost at center. The winged males are pale-orange, their dark shields
oval, the paler &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Exuvium&#34;&gt;exuvium&lt;/a&gt; of the 1st instar placed
near one end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest settles on mango leaves, twigs and fruit. Its populations peak in the winter, are low in the spring and increasing during late summer. The scale is more abundant on tree sides not exposed to the prevailing winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental red scale may be controlled by a mixture of two pesticides, an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; The oriental red scale is attacked by several &lt;a href=&#34;Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&#34;ComperiellaBifasciata&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comperiella bifasciata&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Howard and &lt;a href=&#34;HabrolepisAspidioti&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Habrolepis aspidioti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Compere and Annecke, the &lt;a href=&#34;Aphelinidae&#34;&gt;aphelinid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Ectoparasitoid&#34;&gt;ectoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;AphytisMelinus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis melinus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; DeBach and &lt;a href=&#34;AphytisLingnanensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphytis lingnanensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Compere, and the endoparasitoid &lt;em&gt;Encarsia&lt;/em&gt; sp. It is not clear whether they contribute to the control of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Badawi, A. and Alahmed, A.M. 1990. The population dynamics of the oriental
scale insect, &lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead) and factors affecting its
seasonal abundance.  &lt;em&gt;Arab Gulf journal of Scientific Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;: 81-89.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wysoki, M., Ben-Dov, Y., Swirski, E. and Izhar, Y. 1993. The arthropod pests
of mango in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Acta Horticulturae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;341:&lt;/strong&gt;452-466.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wysoki, M., Israeli, Y. and Rosen, D. 1995. The oriental red scale,
&lt;em&gt;Aonidiella orientalis&lt;/em&gt; (Newstead) (Diaspididae): biology, phenology,
geographic distribution and natural enemies in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;:  267.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpi.qld.gov.au/horticulture/5353.html&#34;&gt;http://www.dpi.qld.gov.au/horticulture/5353.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphanostigma piri</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphanostigma_piri</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphanostigma_piri</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphanostigma piri&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Cholodkovsky)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;:  Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;Aphidoidea&#34;&gt;Aphidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phylloxeridae&#34;&gt;Phylloxeridae&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;:  Pear phylloxera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Mediterranean region, Crimea, East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Pyrus communis&lt;/em&gt; (pear), &lt;em&gt;Pyrus syriaca&lt;/em&gt; (Syrian pear).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The pear phylloxera is a major pest of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Pear&#34;&gt;pears&lt;/a&gt;. Its sucking on the bark results in intensive cracking that can cause the death of branches. Infested buds are destroyed and brown, rotted areas develop around the calyx of affected fruit, which may then drop or be culled during packing. The cultivar “Spadona” is most susceptible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The body of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Apterous&#34;&gt;apterous&lt;/a&gt; females is green to yellow, about 0.7-0.9 mm long. No &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Alate&#34;&gt;alate&lt;/a&gt; forms known from the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Groups of the pear phylloxera live throughout the year in the crevices of the bark, infesting buds and even the fruit &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Calyx&#34;&gt;calyx&lt;/a&gt;. It reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Viviparous&#34;&gt;viviparous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt; around the year, the populations peaking in spring and autumn. Each female can produce 70-150 progeny during its lifetime, which may last 3-4 weeks in summer, 10 weeks in winter. A generation is completed in about two weeks at 30ºC and the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Threshold_Of_Development&#34;&gt;threshold of development&lt;/a&gt; is around 3.0ºC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Observations of the cracked bark of mature pear trees should commence in May, whereas fruit monitoring is by marking 20 pears per tree and observing their condition till picking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant resistance&lt;/strong&gt;:  Some pear cultivars, such as Gentil and Coscia, are little infested by the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Pear phylloxera can be controlled with &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;systemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt;, although the pest may be developing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance_To_Pesticides&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to this group of pesticides in Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheng, M.F. and Yeh, C.C. 1999. Effect of temperature on the development and
reproduction of &lt;em&gt;Aphanostigma piri&lt;/em&gt; (Cholodkovsky). &lt;em&gt;Chinese Journal of
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:73-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oppenheim, D. 1994 (Ed.). &lt;em&gt;A Guide to Integrated Pome &lt;/em&gt;_ Pest Management in
Israel._ Israel Ministry of Agriculture, Extension Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E. and Amitai, S. 1999. Annotated list of aphids (Aphidoidea) in
Israel. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt;: 1-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aphpir.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.inra.fr/Internet/Produits/HYPPZ/RAVAGEUR/6aphpir.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphis craccivora</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphis_craccivora</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/aphis_craccivora</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aphis craccivora&lt;/em&gt; Koch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphidoidea&#34;&gt;Aphidoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphididae&#34;&gt;Aphididae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Cowpea aphid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cosmopolitan; Common Institute of Entomology Map # 99, 1983 (revised).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;Polyphagous&lt;/a&gt;, with a preference for legumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The feeding of this aphid on clover and alfalfa causes plant wilting as well as blackening, due to the pests&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; and the ensuing &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sooty_Molds&#34;&gt;sooty mold&lt;/a&gt; fungi. Such damage is quite serious on &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Ornamentals&#34;&gt;ornamentals&lt;/a&gt;, because it detracts from their external appearance. The cowpea aphid transmits several plant viruses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The bodies of female &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Apterous&#34;&gt;apterous&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Alate&#34;&gt;alate&lt;/a&gt; cowpea aphids, including the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Siphunculi&#34;&gt;siphunculi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cauda&#34;&gt;cauda&lt;/a&gt;, are mostly black. The antennae are shorter than the body, which is about 1.5-2.3 long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; In the Middle East the cowpea aphid reproduces by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt; the year around and no sexual forms have so far been found. The populations of &lt;em&gt;A. craccivora&lt;/em&gt; increase in spring and decline during summer. The females are attracted to green plants and seem to distinguish between the odor of their original host-plant and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: High levels of resistance to the cowpea aphid were found in some cowpea cultivars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphates&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamates&lt;/a&gt; control the cowpea aphid, as do various formulations of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Neem&#34;&gt;neem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;: The cowpea aphid is attacked by several &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoids&lt;/a&gt; of the family &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Aphidiidae&#34;&gt;Aphidiidae&lt;/a&gt;, and infected by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Entomopathogenic_Fungi&#34;&gt; entomopathogenic fungi&lt;/a&gt; that kill the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abdel-Baky, N.F. and Abdel-Salam, A.H. 2003. Natural incidence of &lt;em&gt;Cladosporium&lt;/em&gt; spp. as a bio-control agent against whiteflies and aphids in
Egypt. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;127&lt;/strong&gt;: 228-235.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annan, I.B., Tingey, W.M., Schaefers, G.A., Tjallingii, W.F., Backus, E.A. and
Saxena, K.N. 2000. Stylet penetration activities by &lt;em&gt;Aphis craccivora&lt;/em&gt; (Homoptera: Aphididae) on plants and excised plant parts of resistant and
susceptible cultivars of cowpea (Leguminosae). &lt;em&gt;Annals of the Entomological
Society of America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt;: 133-140.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pettersson, J., Karunaratne, S., Ahmed, E. and Kumar, V. 1998. The cowpea aphid, &lt;em&gt;Aphis craccivora, _host plant odours and pheromones.&lt;/em&gt; Entomologia
Experimentalis et Applicata_ &lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt;: 177-184.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swirski, E. and Amitai, S. 1999. Annotated list of aphids (Aphidoidea) in
Israel. &lt;em&gt;Israel Journal of Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt;: 1-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward, A., Morse, S., Denholm, I., Thompson, R. and McNamara, N. 2002. Foliar
insect pest management on cowpea (&lt;em&gt;Vigna unguiculata&lt;/em&gt; Walpers) in simulated varietal mixtures II. Pest resistance management implications. &lt;em&gt;Field Crops
Research&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;79&lt;/strong&gt;: 67-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dimetry, N.Z. and Elhawary, F.M.A. 1995. Neem AZAL-F as an inhibitor of growth
and reproduction in the cowpea aphid &lt;em&gt;Aphis craccivora&lt;/em&gt; Koch. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;119&lt;/strong&gt;: 67-71.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulrichs, C., Mewis, I. and Schnitzler, W.H. 2001. Experiments with synthetic insecticides alone and in combination with &lt;em&gt;Bacill. thur&lt;/em&gt;. and &lt;em&gt;Trichogramma
evan.&lt;/em&gt; to control &lt;em&gt;Vigna&lt;/em&gt; pests under conditions in tropic lowlands. &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger
für Schadlingskunde&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;74&lt;/strong&gt;: 117-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>