<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Tetranychidae on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/tetranychidae/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutetranychus orientalis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_orientalis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_orientalis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Klein)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychoidea&#34;&gt;Tetranychoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fig30pr&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/EutetranychusOrientalis-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Oriental spider mite, citrus brown mite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite occurs in the eastern Mediterranean countries, in Asia from India to China and in most of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite may develop on over two hundred host plants, mostly &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Dicotyledones&#34;&gt;dicotyledons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult female is about 0.4-0.5 mm in length, brownish, with a oval body and its legs are about as long as the body (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;static/figures/EutetranychusOrientalis-fs.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: A colony of Eutetranychus orientalis on a citrus leaf&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male is reddish, smaller, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hysteronotum&#34;&gt;hysteronotum&lt;/a&gt; is pointed and the legs are longer than the body. The dorsal setae are short, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spatulate&#34;&gt;spatulate&lt;/a&gt; and placed on small tubercles. The rounded eggs are pale-brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite is an important pest of &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Citrus&#34;&gt;citrus&lt;/a&gt;, especially in drier areas. It is the most persistent citrus pest in Upper Egypt and an occasional serious pest in the south of Israel. The mites colonize the upper side of leaves where they feed, and their damage develops as yellow-grey stippled spots which cause leaf wilting and drop. Heavy infestations may cause fruit drop and the death of upper branches, and next-years&amp;rsquo; blossoming may be severely affected. Reduced irrigation increases the damage. Lemon trees are more damaged than other citrus species and varieties, whereas oranges are little affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: The mites colonize the upper side of leaves whereon their eggs are deposited along the midrib. The threshold of development is at 10° and development requires about two weeks at around 25°C. Each female produces 30-40 eggs during two-three weeks. The pest raises about 20 annual, largely overlapping generations. Like other Tetranychoidea, the Oriental spider mite is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sex_ratio&#34;&gt;sex ratio&lt;/a&gt; is usually 0.7, female-biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: The oriental spider mite has not yet developed &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to pesticides. Thus it may still be be controlled by such commonly-used &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acaricide&#34;&gt;acaricides&lt;/a&gt; as amitraz and dicofol, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organotin&#34;&gt;organotin&lt;/a&gt; fenbutatin oxide and even petroleum oils. However, the pest seems to be less susceptible to some of these chemicals, and continuous monitoring for resistance is thus necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The pest is attacked by many
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Indigenous&#34;&gt;indigenous&lt;/a&gt; predatory mites of the families
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phytoseiidae&#34;&gt;Phytoseiidae&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Stigmaeidae&#34;&gt;Stigmaeidae&lt;/a&gt;. The phytoseiid &lt;em&gt;Euseius scutalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Athias-Henriot)&lt;/code&gt; appears to regulate the
citrus brown mite in Jordan, but little is known about its specificity and the
ability of other predators to reduce pest outbreak populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avidov, H.Z. 1936. Contributions to the knowledge of the red spiders in
Palestine. 1. The Oriental red spider, &lt;em&gt;Anychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt; Zacher. &lt;em&gt;Hadar&lt;/em&gt;
9: 107-111, 126-132.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drishpoun, Y. 2000. &lt;em&gt;A Guide to the Control of Citrus Pests&lt;/em&gt;. Ministry of
Agriculture and Rural Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Momen, F. and El-Borolossy, M. 1999. Suitability of the citrus brown mite,
&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt; as prey for nine species of phytoseiid mites
(Acari: Tetranychidae, Phytoseiidae). &lt;em&gt;Acarologia&lt;/em&gt; 40: 19-23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osman, M.S. 1997. Petroleum oils as a component of integrated pest management
of phytophagous mites. &lt;em&gt;Arab Journal of Scientific Research&lt;/em&gt; 15: 125-135.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanigoshi, L.K., Bahdousheh, M., Babcock, J.M. and Sawaqed, R. 1990. &lt;em&gt;Euseius
scutalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Athias-Henriot)&lt;/code&gt; a predator of &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus orientalis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Klein)&lt;/code&gt; in
Jordan: toxicity of some acaricides to &lt;em&gt;E. orientalis&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Arab Journal of Plant
Protection&lt;/em&gt; 8: 114-120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaher, M.A., Wafa, A.K., Maher Ali, M. and Rasmy, A.H. 1970. Survey of mites
associated with citrus trees in Egypt and Gaza Strip. &lt;em&gt;Bulletin de la Societe
Entomologique d&amp;rsquo;Egypte&lt;/em&gt; 56: 73-79.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ento.csiro.au/aicn/system/c_204.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.ento.csiro.au/aicn/system/c_204.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

Insert A Name Of A Person To Contact: [Insert Again The Same E-mail
Address](mailto:Insert E-mail Address Of That Person)
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eutetranychus palmatus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_palmatus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/eutetranychus_palmatus</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acari&#34;&gt;Acari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Prostigmata&#34;&gt;Prostigmata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychoidea&#34;&gt;Tetranychoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Tetranychidae&#34;&gt;Tetranychidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: None.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: This mite occurs in Egypt and in the south of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt; has been found on various Palmae, including the &lt;a href=&#34;crop/Date_palms&#34;&gt;date palm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Phoenix dactylifera&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L.&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Washingtonia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hyphaene&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The adult female is about 0.4-0.5 mm in length, red-brown, with an oval body and legs that are about as long as the body. The male is reddish, smaller, its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hysteronotum&#34;&gt;hysteronotum&lt;/a&gt; is pointed and the legs are longer than the body. The dorsal setae are short and serate, not placed on small tubercles. The rounded eggs are pale-brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt; is a minor pest of date palm fruit (apparently more of the cultivar &amp;lsquo;Barhi&amp;rsquo;), whose feeding produces exudates that later become covered by dust as well as by the mites&amp;rsquo; shed skins. Its damage may be masked by that of &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Oligonychus_afrasiaticus&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oligonychus afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt; (with which it often co-occurs), and could become more severe where &lt;em&gt;O. afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt; is not present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history&lt;/strong&gt;: Little is known about the biology of &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;. It develops thorough the year on the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Frond&#34;&gt;fronds&lt;/a&gt;, moving onto the fruit during mid-summer earlier then &lt;em&gt;O. afrasiaticus&lt;/em&gt;, and back to the fronds when the dates turn yellow. Like other Tetranychoidea, this mite is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Arrhenotokous&#34;&gt;arrhenotokous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;: No measures to control this mite have so far been necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attiah, H.H. 1967. The genus &lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus&lt;/em&gt; in U.A.R. with descriptions of
three new species (Acarina: Tetranychidae). &lt;em&gt;Bulletin de la Societe
Entomologique d&amp;rsquo;Egypte&lt;/em&gt; 51: 11-16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., Venezian, A. and Blumberg, D. 1983. Phytophagous mites on date
palms in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Fruits&lt;/em&gt; 38: 133-135.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palevsky, E., Ucko, O., Peles, S. and Gerson, U. The phenology of
&lt;em&gt;Eutetranychus palmatus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Attiah&lt;/code&gt; (Acari: Tetranychidae) on date palms in
Israel. Submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>