<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Acridoidea on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/acridoidea/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locusta migratoria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/locusta_migratoria</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/locusta_migratoria</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy: Insecta, Hemimetabola, Orthoptera, Acridoidea, Acrididae, Oedipodinae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Migratory locust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Click on image to enlarge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution:&lt;/strong&gt;  The distribution of &lt;em&gt;L. migratoria&lt;/em&gt; encompasses practically the whole of the temperate and tropical parts of the Eastern Hemisphere, from the Canaries and the Azores in the West to Japan and New Zealand in the East. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants:&lt;/strong&gt; The migratory locust prefers gramineous plants, but may feed on a large variety of rangeland flora in its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Primary_breeding_sites&#34;&gt;primary breeding sites&lt;/a&gt;, or on economic crops, when present in the environment. Leguminous plants are less compatible nutritionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance:&lt;/strong&gt; At low population densities, the migratory locust is a minor pest. Although permanently solitariform in the eastern Mediterranean, the behavior of occasional crowded populations is reminiscent of its gregariform subspecies, the African migratory locust, &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria migratorioides&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Reiche &amp;amp; Fairmaire)&lt;/code&gt;, with which it can readily hybridize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology:&lt;/strong&gt; The Egyptian tree locust is a large grasshopper. At rest, the adult female body, including the folded, is up to 90 mm in length, while the male measures up to 65 mm. The mottled tegmina project beyond the end of the abdomen. Adults are grey-brown in color. The hind wings are transparent and have a purplish cast, and a curved band of darker aspect runs diagonally across them. A dull yellow line runs dorsally along the crest of the pronotum. The hind tibial spines are basally pale and apically dark-tipped. The juveniles are greenish.
 Within this species in its broad distribution, solitariform adults are characterized by a concave pronotum. Their background coloration is cryptic, being green or brown, dependent on levels of ambient humidity. Gregariform adults are much darker. Isolated males are substantially larger than females whereas crowded males are about the same size as the females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; Within their vast geographic range the populations of the migratory locust exhibit morphological and biological diversity, and the existence of nine subspecies is nowadays accepted; some are economic pests. Populations of L. migratoria that are endemic to temperate climates (some classified as subspecies), undergo embryonic diapause, thus establishing 1-2 annual generations. However, this does not occur in the subtropical Middle East. A non-swarming subspecies, &lt;em&gt;L. m. cinerascens&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Fabricius)&lt;/code&gt;, exists in some of the other countries surrounding the Mediterranean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule, the migration of L. migratoria is more limited than that of the desert locust, Schistocerca gregaria (Forskal). Isolated migratory locusts fly at night, whereas crowded adults fly mainly by day. Isolated locusts have 1-2 more larval instars than individuals in crowded populations, but this does not prolong their development, which is more rapid than when crowded. In consequence locusts in crowded populations establish fewer generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selection favoring non-migratory behavior may occur in localities where emigration is detrimental to survival. Evolution of distinct populations and subspecies with pronounced solitarious phase characteristics would have been favored in such cases. The more isolated and smaller the population and its geographical distribution, the more likely it is to possess unique morphometrics. In Israel, when first recorded in the Jezreel Valley (which is contiguous with the Jordan Valley), L. migratoria was originally described as L. danica, but later determined to be the solitariform of L. migratoria. Its primary breeding sites on the shores of the Sea of Gallilee have since become degraded due to development projects. Some breeding sites may still exist in the Sudano-Deccanian enclave surrounding the Dead Sea. The Jordan Valley, contiguous with the Arava Valley, was originally part of the African Rift Valley and the Israeli population is possibly a relict form of the African migratory locust. The Israeli population of L. migratory does not undergo an overt gregarization, and is permanently solitariform in appearance. This does not mean that crowded populations do not behave like typical gregarious locusts, but only that morphometrically, differences between the two phases is slight. Finally, the Israeli migratory locust population is superficially similar to another population that is established in irrigated localities in central Arabia. Migration along the Arava Valley could connect these two populations but this has not been examined. Solitariform L. migratoria may occur in low numbers on field crops and grasses during summer and autumn in Israel, and disappear in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Other than on the rare occasions when population of the migratory locust increases substantially, the solitariform grasshopper does not require special control measures. In its areas of abundance, environmentally compatible control agents, such as the entomopathogenic fungus Metarhizium anisopliae applied in an oil-based formulation, have been tested. IGRs, inhibitors of chitin synthesis, such as Dimilin, prevent normal molting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heifetz, Y., Applebaum, S.W., and Popov, G.B. 1994. Phase characteristics of the Israeli population of the migratory locust, &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt; (Orthoptera: Acrididae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Orthoptera Research&lt;/em&gt; 2: 15-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El-Minshawy, A.M., El-Hinnawy, N.H. et al. 1975. Population fluctuations of grasshoppers and locusts in Alexandria area (Egypt) &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Entomological Society of Egypt&lt;/em&gt; 59: 83-98.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanyang, S. and van Emden, H.F. 1996. The combined effects of the fungus Metarhizium flavoviride Gams &amp;amp; Rozsypal and the insecticide cypermethrin on &lt;em&gt;Locusta migratoria migratorioides&lt;/em&gt; (Reiche &amp;amp; Fairmaire) in the laboratory. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Pest Management&lt;/em&gt; 42: 183-187.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&#34;&gt;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/species.htm#Near%20East&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schistocerca gregaria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/schistocerca_gregaria</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/schistocerca_gregaria</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schistocerca gregaria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Forskal)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Orthoptera&#34;&gt;Orthoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acridoidea&#34;&gt;Acridoidea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Acrididae&#34;&gt;Acrididae&lt;/a&gt;, Cyrtacanthacridinae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Desert locust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: ranging from West Africa, across the Arabian peninsula and most of the Indian sub-continent. In the Mediterranean region: all of northern Africa, the Middle East north to parts of Turkey, Iran and the Central Asian Republics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;: highly &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Polyphagous&#34;&gt;polyphagous&lt;/a&gt;, feeding mainly on a large variety of rangeland shrubs and grasses that grow in primary breeding sites and on economic crops when encountered during pest outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Damage caused by the desert locust is a consequence of its polyphagous nature, the density of the population, and its habits to aggregate and swarm. Each individual gregarious locust is able to consume roughly its own weight in foliage daily. This partly explains how dense swarms of adults, or marching bands of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt;, can inflict considerable injury in a short time. Damage by gregarious swarming populations occurs in cycles, in most cases afflicting economies in fragile ecosystems, least able to sustain biomass reduction or complete crop loss. In the long term, the cumulative damage does not surpass that inflicted by indigenous grasshoppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: When reared in isolation and consequently &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Solitariform&#34;&gt;solitariform&lt;/a&gt;, locusts exhibit convex &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pronotum&#34;&gt;pronotal&lt;/a&gt; crests, typical &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Morphometrics&#34;&gt;morphometric&lt;/a&gt; ratios of body measurements, and cryptic green to light-brown coloration usually harmonizing with the color of the immediate environment and affected by humidity. Cuticular accumulation of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Melanin&#34;&gt;melanin&lt;/a&gt; is markedly reduced. In contrast &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Gregariform&#34;&gt;gregariform&lt;/a&gt; locusts, crowded during rearing, have concave or straight pronota, and are yellow with contrasted melanized and reddish marking. When adult but immature, the background color of both sexes of the desert locust has a pink caste. The mature adult gregariform male is yellowish, progressing to bright yellow, that of females brownish. Solitariform adults retain their green to brown coloration and convex pronota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;: Eggs of the desert locust develop and hatch in about two weeks. Gregariform &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Nymph&#34;&gt;nymphs&lt;/a&gt; pass through five instars before maturing to the adult stage, while solitariform nymphs pass through six instars. Solitariform individuals tend to disperse and exhibit low activity. Gregariform nymphs tend to aggregate, and they are more active than solitariform nymphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecology&lt;/strong&gt;: Nymphal development requires about one month under optimal conditions, but may extend for 2-3 months under less favorable conditions. Newly-eclosed adults are reproductively immature. During their pre-reproductive period the adults accumulate reserves in preparation for migration and/or reproduction. Reproductive maturation occurs within about three weeks but may be delayed for many months, in synchrony with the environment. There is evidence that delayed maturation within primary breeding sites is synchronized with rainfall and flowering of desert shrubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During periods of &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Recession&#34;&gt;recession&lt;/a&gt;, desert locusts breed
in &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Primary_Breeding_Sites&#34;&gt;primary breeding sites&lt;/a&gt;, mainly
restricted to semi-arid and arid deserts where precipitation is sporadic and
below 200 mm annually. Rainfall in primary breeding sites initiates seed
germination. This sequence of events subsequently leads to an increased
population density. Within 2-3 generations of increasing density,
transformation to the gregariform &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Phase&#34;&gt;phase&lt;/a&gt; is induced. When these conditions cease, and
a dry spell occurs, adults swarm gregariously, migrating actively in the
direction of prevailing winds. In Africa, migration is associated with the
Inter-Tropical Convergence Zone (ITCZ). When opposing winds meet within this
zone, high air pressure develops and vertical flow of air occurs. During its
ascent, air temperature decreases leading to an increase in relative humidity
and finally to rainfall. The arrival of locust swarms to the convergence zone
coincides with the occurrence of precipitation and vegetation, encouraging and
supporting further population growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Females contribute to gregarization by depositing egg pods close to pods that
are being laid concurrently or have been laid previously. This is due to their
attraction to ovipositional sites, whether because of suitability of soil,
moisture and other environmental conditions, or to attraction to an
oviposition &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; with which each female marks the exact
spot wherein she has deposited eggs. Clutches of eggs are bound together with
a proteinaceous foam, which is produced in the female genital &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Accessory_Glands&#34;&gt;accessory
glands&lt;/a&gt;. Solitarious
females produce and deposit more eggs (60-80) in each clutch than do
gregarious females (40-60).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swarming behavior and migration are not necessarily dependent on gregariform
phase characteristics of coloration or morphometrics, but are usually
positively correlated to population density: Gregarious behavior is induced as
a consequence of interactions among individuals upon crowding, irrespective of
whether they are initially solitariform or gregariform in coloration and
morphometrics. Solitarious behavior is conversely expressed when locusts are
isolated, even when initially gregariform. Solitarious larvae do not
aggregate, whereas gregarious locusts are marked with bright color patterns,
tend to aggregate in their nymphal stages and to march together in bands,
while adults fly in dense and highly mobile swarms. Locust flight is directed
by prevailing winds. These directions differ from night to day. Locusts ascend
on thermal currents during the day to considerable heights, where they may
encounter wind directions differing from those found at lower altitudes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The area covered by gregarious locust swarms may range from 1 to 200 square
kilometers, at a density which is commonly in the range of 100 individual per
square meter, but under extreme conditions may be one to two orders of
magnitude greater in density.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another characteristic of sustained flight or migration, is that reproduction
is normally delayed. This may be due to the allocation for flight of limited
resources in the first case, or allocation of the same resource pool for egg
development, in the second. This differential allocation of resources is
termed the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/OocyteFlightSyndrome&#34;&gt;oocyte-flight syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt;: Populations of the Desert Locust are monitored during recession and outbreak by various international agencies. These include the Desert Locust Control Organization (DLCO) of the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) of the United Nations. When gregarization commences, outbreak is prevented primarily by chemical control, preferably with less persistent chemicals, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pyrethroids&#34;&gt;pyrethroids&lt;/a&gt; fenitrothion and deltamethrin, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Insect_Growth_Regulator&#34;&gt;insect growth regulator&lt;/a&gt; (IGR) diflubenzuron, the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Carbamates&#34;&gt;carbamate&lt;/a&gt; bendiocarb and the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/GABA_Blocker&#34;&gt;GABA-blocker&lt;/a&gt; fipronil. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Neem&#34;&gt;Neem&lt;/a&gt; seed extracts, whether prepared locally or commercially, are effective as &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Feeding_Deterrent&#34;&gt;feeding deterrents&lt;/a&gt; of the desert locust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best chance to restrict locust outbreak is by careful monitoring and
control of evolving gregarization. There are several reasons why this is not
always logistically possible, or indeed efficient. Primarily, this is because
breeding sites are sporadic and spread over a very wide area, often in remote
location. Access to many of these sites is difficult, security questionable,
and resources limited. Finally, the cycles of desert locust outbreaks and
recessions are extended, and this leads to loss of attention during extended
recession periods. There is a recurrent debate concerning the long-term
economic justification of global locust control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/BiologicalControl&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Various parasites and
predators have been reported to attack the different stages of Desert Locust
development. None are effective in suppressing populations once they have
gregarized and swarmed. They may contribute to some degree to the collapse of
locust populations, once the outbreak had peaked. Recent studies with
preparations of the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Entomopathogenic_Fungi&#34;&gt;entomopathogenic fungus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Metarhizium anisopliae&lt;/em&gt; are encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COPR, 1982. &lt;em&gt;The Locust and Grasshopper Agricultural Manual&lt;/em&gt;. London: Centre
for Overseas Pest Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fishelson, L. 1985. &lt;em&gt;Orthoptera: Acridoidea. Fauna Palaestina - Insecta III&lt;/em&gt;.
The Israel Academy of Sciences and Humanities, Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uvarov, V.B. 1966. &lt;em&gt;Grasshoppers and Locusts&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 1, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uvarov, V.B. 1977. &lt;em&gt;Grasshoppers and Locusts&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 2, London: Centre for
Overseas Pest Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shower, A.T. 1996. &lt;em&gt;The Desert Locust in Africa and Western Asia: Complexities
of War, Politics, Perilous Terrain, and Development.&lt;/em&gt; University of Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/lit3.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.dpw.wageningen-ur.nl/locust/loclit/lit3.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fao.org/NEWS/GLOBAL/locusts/locuhome.HTM&#34;&gt;http://www.fao.org/NEWS/GLOBAL/locusts/locuhome.HTM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Person to contact&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mahmoud Taher, at:
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Mahmoud.Taher@field.fao.org&#34;&gt;Mahmoud.Taher@field.fao.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>