<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Thaumetopoeidae on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/thaumetopoeidae/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thaumetopoea pityocampa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_pityocampa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_pityocampa</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;(Denis &amp;amp; Schiffermüller)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thaumetopoeidae&#34;&gt;Thaumetopoeidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Winter pine processionary moth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: The western Mediterranean region, reaching south-western Turkey in the Middle East, colonizing over 1,500,000 ha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past the vicariants  &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; and   &lt;a href=&#34;pest/Thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt; were often confused. A
molecular study recently revealed  differences between the two species, which
became separated before the Quaternary ice ages.  Commonwealth Institute of
Entomology Map #366, 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Feeding of the pest is restricted to pines, such as &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;inus&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;nigra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;P. brutia&lt;/em&gt;,  &lt;em&gt;P. sylvestris&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;L&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;em&gt;P. pinea&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;P. halepensis&lt;/em&gt; and to &lt;em&gt;Cedrus&lt;/em&gt; spp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the needles which then drop; saplings may be entirely defoliated, causing tree dieback and even death.  Fourth- and fifth-instar larvae consume all the needles of pine trees, so that they to have been burned. The average decrease in annual diameter increment for Calabrian trees in damaged areas, compared with healthy trees, can reach about 22%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The larvae are armed with stinging setae that break off easily and release a
protein, thaumetopoein, which causes inflammations of eyes and of the
respiratory system in humans and domestic animals, as well as allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moth is a relatively new pest in Turkey, whose emergence has been
attributed to the intense cultivation of conifers for afforestation of
degraded soils and as ornamentals, and the recent expansion of the pest to
upper elevations and latitudes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The greyish adults bear transverse dark stripes and their heads are decorated with dense hairs. The young larvae are brown-yellow, becoming darker with each molt. All larvae bear red-brown tubercles with yellow-white detachable setae with hooked tips. The average weight of mature larvae is almost 0.80 g, and their average length 30 mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Univoltine&#34;&gt;univoltine&lt;/a&gt;. Adults emerge and fly in August, laying eggs in September; the larvae hatch by the end of that month and the next (October). They form processions as they crawl along pine branches to find feeding sites and then rest in nests; an average nest holding about 210 larvae. They pass through five &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Instar&#34;&gt;instars&lt;/a&gt;, pupating in the soil during May, June and July. Pine &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Secondary_plant_constituents&#34;&gt;secondary plant constituents&lt;/a&gt; seem to determine the pest&amp;rsquo;s host selection processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphates&#34;&gt;Organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; were formerly applied
against the pest. Steam-distilled wood sulfate turpentine was the best of
several essential plant oils tried in Turkey to control the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparations of  &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Bacillus_thuringiensis&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Bt) may control the pest but two applications are required for
satisfactory control. This is the result of the prolonged, month-long
emergence of the vulnerable young larval instars, whose late members avoid the
treatment, which does not persist that long on the needles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: In Turkey the pest is attacked by several natural enemies, the more common being the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; egg parasitoids &lt;em&gt;Ooencyrtus pityocampae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Eutetrastichus&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Baryscapus&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;em&gt;servadeii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Dom.)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;). The former parasitized eggs placed near the top of the batches, whereas the latter was found mainly in eggs near the base of the batches. All egg parasitoids together reduced hatching rate to 50.7-65.6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battisti, A., Longo, S., Tiberi, R. and Triggiani, O. 1998. Results and
perspectives in the use of &lt;em&gt;Bacillus thuringiensis&lt;/em&gt; Berl. var. &lt;em&gt;kurstaki&lt;/em&gt; and
other pathogens against &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. et Schiff.)&lt;/code&gt; in Italy
(Lep., Thaumetopoeidae). &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger für Schädlingskunde, Pflanzenschutz,
Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt;, 71, 72-76.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devkota, B. and Schmidt, G. H., 1990: Larval development of &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. &amp;amp; Schiff)&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) from Greece as influenced
by different host plants under laboratory conditions. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied
Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 109: 321-330.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanat, M., Sivrikaya, F. and Serez, M. 2002. A research on the effects of pine
processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Schiff&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;em&gt;Pinus brutia&lt;/em&gt; Ten
trees and tending activities on the diameter increment of calabrian pine in
Kahramanmaras. &lt;em&gt;Symposium on the Pine Processionary Moth&lt;/em&gt;, Kahramanmaras,
Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanat, M. and Alma, M.H. 2004. [ Insecticidal effects of essential oils from
various plants. against larvae of pine processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Schiff&lt;/code&gt;) (Lepidoptera : Thaumetopoeidae)]
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14971685&#34;&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14971685&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;em&gt;Pest Management Science&lt;/em&gt; 60: 173-177.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirchev, P., Schmidt, G. H., Tsankov, G. and Avci M. 2004. Egg parasitoids of
&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Den. &amp;amp; Schiff.)&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) and their
impact in SW Turkey. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 128: 533-542.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvato, P.; Battisti, A.; Concato, S.; Masutti, L.; Partanello, T. and Zane,
L., 2002. Genetic differentiation in the winter pine processionary moth
(&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa-wilkinsoni _complex), inferred by AFLP and
mitochondrial DNA markers&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Molecular Ecology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 2435-2444.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Türkmen, H. and Y. Ali Öner[ Y. ]
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.1398-9995.2003.00369.x&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.1398-9995.2003.00369.x&lt;/a&gt;
2004. A human dermatitis
caused by _ Thaumetopoea pityocampa_ (Denis and Schiffermüller, 1775) (order:
Lepidoptera) caterpillars in Istanbul, Turkey. &lt;em&gt;Allergy&lt;/em&gt; 59: 232-233.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--- 
aj13989995200300369x ---&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Zhang, Q.-H., Schlyter, F., Battisti, A., Birgersson, G. and Anderson, P.
2003. Electrophysiological responses of &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; females to
host volatiles: implications for host selection of active and inactive
terpenes. &lt;em&gt;Anzeiger für Schädlingskunde Pflanzenschutz, Umweltschutz&lt;/em&gt;, 76:
103-107.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ThaumPityoc.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.leps.it/indexjs.htm?SpeciesPages/ThaumPityoc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/thaumetopoea_wilkinsoni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing&lt;/strong&gt;: Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Holometabola&#34;&gt;Holometabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Lepidoptera&#34;&gt;Lepidoptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Thaumetopoeidae&#34;&gt; Thaumetopoeidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common name&lt;/strong&gt;: Cyprus processionary caterpillar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Cyprus, Israel, Jordan and Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vicariants &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea
pityocampa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Denis and Schiffermüller)&lt;/code&gt; were often confused in the past.
However, a recent molecular study showed clear differences between the two
species, which became separated before the Quaternary ice ages. &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; is restricted to the Middle East, whereas &lt;em&gt;T.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;pityocampa&lt;/em&gt;
is a more western species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  Feeding of the pest is restricted to pines (&lt;em&gt;Pinus&lt;/em&gt; spp.). In the Middle East young &lt;em&gt;P. eldarica&lt;/em&gt; trees are preferred to &lt;em&gt;P. brutia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;P. halepensis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Larva&#34;&gt;larvae&lt;/a&gt; feed on the needles, which causes their shedding; saplings may entirely be defoliated, causing die back and even (in dry years) tree death. Larger trees may recover, although totally defoliated branches can still be seen. The external parts of the trees, especially young ones, are usually preferred. The larvae are armed with stinging setae that easily break off and release a protein, thaumetopoein, which causes inflammations of eyes and of the respiratory system in humans and domestic animals, as well as allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large-scale reforestation programs with pines undertaken in Cyprus and Israel
have increased the importance of the pest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The brownish adults, whose length is 17-22 mm, bear transverse dark stripes and their bodies are decorated with dense hairs. The young larvae are brown-yellow, becoming darker with each molt. At maturity they are almost black and attain a size of 40 mm. All larvae bear tubercles with yellow-white detachable setae with hooked tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  The pest is &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Univoltine&#34;&gt;univoltine&lt;/a&gt;. Adults emerge in the autumn and lay their eggs in early winter. Each female lays many eggs, arranging them in rows around pine needles and covering them with reddish scales. The larvae emerge after 6-7 weeks and immediately form processions that march off to seek food. The young larvae feed only on the needles&amp;rsquo; epidermis, but later stages consume entire needles. After a few days of feeding the larvae form a temporary communal nest, moving to another site as they crawl on to look for fresh needles. Larval development lasts 4-6 months, pupation taking place in the soil and takes about 5 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;: Mass &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Mass_trapping&#34;&gt;male trapping&lt;/a&gt; is feasible with the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pheromone&#34;&gt;pheromone&lt;/a&gt; pityolure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: Stem injections with an &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphate&lt;/a&gt; bring about 100% mortality, as do implants of similar pesticides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_control&#34;&gt;Biological control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Various stages of the pest are attacked by several natural enemies, the more common being the &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt; egg parasitoids &lt;em&gt;Ooencyrtus pityocampae&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Mercet)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Eutetrastichus servadeii&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Dom.)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Eulophidae&#34;&gt;Eulophidae&lt;/a&gt;). Their overall effect on the pest appears to be  negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halperin, J. 1985. Detection and control of the pine processionary
caterpillar, &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; , with pityolure.  &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt;
13: 148-149&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halperin, J. 1986. Acephate implants for control of the pine processionary
caterpillar. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 14: 97-100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitt, J. and Schmidt, G. H., 1993: Parasitism of egg-batches of the pine
processionary moth &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) in the
mountains of Lahav (Israel). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 115, 484-498.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mendel, Z. 1988. Host selection by the pine processionary caterpillar,
 &lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Phytoparasitica&lt;/em&gt; 16: 101-108.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mendel, Z. 1990. On the origin of the pine processionary caterpillar,
&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Tams&lt;/code&gt; (Lep., Thaumetopoeidae) in Israel. &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Applied Entomology&lt;/em&gt; 109: 311-314.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvato, P., Battisti, A., Concato, S., Masutti, L., Partanello, T. and Zane, L., 2002: Genetic differentiation in the winter pine processionary moth (&lt;em&gt;Thaumetopoea pityocampa-wilkinsoni&lt;/em&gt; complex), inferred by AFLP and mitochondrial DNA markers. &lt;em&gt;Molecular Ecology&lt;/em&gt; 11: 2435-2444.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>