<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Pseudococcidae on Plant Pests of the Middle East </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/taxonomy/pseudococcidae/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Uri Gerson</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2014, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonina graminis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Uri Gerson</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pest/antonina_graminis</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Maskell)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomic placing:&lt;/strong&gt; Insecta, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemimetabola&#34;&gt;Hemimetabola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hemiptera&#34;&gt;Hemiptera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Sternorrhyncha&#34;&gt;Sternorrhyncha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Coccoidea&#34;&gt;Coccoidea,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pseudococcidae&#34;&gt;Pseudococcidae&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Name&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Insert Small-Image File&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical distribution&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rhodesgrass scale occurs in tropical and subtropical regions, approximately bounded by the 32nd parallel. The pest was first found in the Middle East in the late 1960s. Commonwealth Institute of Entomology Map #216, 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host plants&lt;/strong&gt;:  About 100 species of grasses (Gramineae), including many pasture grasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic importance&lt;/strong&gt;:  Damage [especially to rhodesgrass, &lt;em&gt;Chloris gayana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Kunth&lt;/code&gt;, and to bermudagrass, &lt;em&gt;Cynodon dactylon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;(L.)&lt;/code&gt;] is due to the removal of plant sap. Infested plants turn yellow and shrivel. Injury may be compounded by plant stress factors, such as drought, irrigation by low-grade water, close mowing (of lawns and golf courses) and by overgrazing. Infested pastures, unless treated, decline and dry up within 2-4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphology&lt;/strong&gt;: The female is legless, with short, 2-segmented antennae. The body is dark-red and becomes darker as the scale matures. The &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Spiracles&#34;&gt;spiracles&lt;/a&gt; are large, with many surrounding &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Pores&#34;&gt;pores&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Cerarii&#34;&gt;Cerarii&lt;/a&gt; absent, &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Anal_Ring&#34;&gt;anal ring&lt;/a&gt; somewhat retracted from posterior end of the body. The female is totally enclosed within a white waxy sac, and produces a long, anal waxy excretory tube or stalk, used to excrete its &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Honeydew&#34;&gt;honeydew&lt;/a&gt; away from the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle&lt;/strong&gt;:  Reproduction is by &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Parthenogenesis&#34;&gt;parthenogenesis&lt;/a&gt;, each female giving birth to about 150 &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Crawler&#34;&gt;crawlers&lt;/a&gt;. They usually settle at the lower nodes or crowns of grasses, between leaf sheaths, where they feed and produce their excretory stalk. A generation requires about 10 weeks, development being continuous throughout the year except during very cold or very hot periods. Dispersal may be by human transport of infested grasses, by the movement of the crawlers or by being borne on winds. Ants may be associated with these pests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-feeding females live for at least five weeks and continue to produce young
for much of that period, an attribute that has been used for the mass rearing
of its natural enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;: Population size can be estimated by collecting 10 rhodesgrass runners, each with at least 10 nodes, from different parts of a field and counting the number of scales that had settled thereon. Best (most uniform) results are obtained from nodes that have not yet taken root. In addition, data from these nodes provide a better indication of recent changes in the pest&amp;rsquo;s population, whereas older nodes could have been colonized for longer periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural control&lt;/strong&gt;:  Improvements of plant condition by better irrigation, by fertilization and by moderate grazing and mowing. &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Resistance&#34;&gt;Resistant&lt;/a&gt; rhodesgrass varieties are also available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical control&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Systemic&#34;&gt;Systemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;entry/Organophosphate&#34;&gt;organophosphates&lt;/a&gt; may provide satisfactory control, but their use (in granulated formulations) is limited to small areas, like golf courses. The cost of applying such pesticides to rangelands is prohibitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Biological_Control&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Hymenoptera&#34;&gt;hymenopterous&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Endoparasitoid&#34;&gt;endoparasitoid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;enemy/Neodusmetia_sangwani&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;(Rao)&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;entry/Encyrtidae&#34;&gt;Encyrtidae&lt;/a&gt;),
of Indian provenance, was introduced into Israel in 1971, mass-reared on
field-collected &lt;em&gt;A. graminis&lt;/em&gt; and released at several rhodesgrass plots.
Parasitization rates are very high and at present the pest has almost totally
disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chada, H.L. and Wood, E.A., Jr. 1960. Biology and control of the rhodesgrass
scale. &lt;em&gt;United States Department of Agriculture, Technical Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; #
&lt;strong&gt;1221&lt;/strong&gt;, pp. 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerson, U., E. Mescheloff and E. Dubitzki. 1975. The introduction of
&lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao) (Hymenoptera: Encyrtidae) into Israel for the
control of rhodesgrass scale, &lt;em&gt;Antonina graminis&lt;/em&gt; (Maskell) (Homoptera:
Pseudococcidae). &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Ecology&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;:  767-779.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. 1967. Response of forage grasses to rhodesgrass scale. &lt;em&gt;Journal
of Range Management&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt;:  307-309.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schuster, M.F. and Bolling, J.C. 1971. Biological control of rhodesgrass scale
in Texas by &lt;em&gt;Neodusmetia sangwani&lt;/em&gt; (Rao). Effectiveness and colonization
studies. &lt;em&gt;Texas Agricultural Experiment Station&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;B1104&lt;/strong&gt;:  1-15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&#34;&gt;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=Antonina+graminis&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/depts/ent/notes/O&amp;amp;T/lawn/note127/note127.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>